{
  "sections": [
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "7.1",
          "definitions": {
            "ABASE": {
              "word": "ABASE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩbAs')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to degrade, humiliate, demean, humble \nABASE comes from the same Latin word as the adjective <em>base</em>, meaning <em>low</em>. To ABASE is to lower in rank or es- teem, to degrade. \n\"We do not feel that doing manual work ABASES us.\" \nThe word is usually used reflexively-that is, in such phrases as \"ABASE myself\" and \"ABASE themselves.\" \n\"The mayor refused to ABASE himself by trading insults with his opponent.\" \n\"I think she ABASED herself by agreeing to wear that silly costume in the show.\" \nOther forms of the word: ABASEMENT, n."
            },
            "MALIGN": {
              "word": "MALIGN",
              "phonetic": "(mÔøΩlln')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to slander, defame \nMALIGN, like <em>malice</em> and <em>malevolent</em>, comes from a Latin word meaning <em>bad</em>. To MALIGN people is to speak badly of them, particularly to lie about them maliciously. \n\"The purpose of the anonymous pamphlet was to MALIGN the doctor's reputation.\" \n\"The team's owner said he was constantly being MALIGNED by sportswriters who didn't understand what he was trying to do.\" \nMALIGN is often used in its past participle form, MALIGNED. \n\"The writer claimed that Lucrezia Borgia is one of the most falsely MALIGNED women in history; she wasn't really as bad as people say.\" \n\"The much-MALIGNED dinosaur may actually have been a rather intelligent animal.\""
            },
            "OVERT": {
              "word": "OVERT",
              "phonetic": "(O-vert'",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "unconcealed, open, manifest \nOVERT means \"open to view; not concealed or hidden.\" The word is usually used about actions and attitudes, rather than physical objects. \n\"There was plenty of secret resentment toward the boss, but no OVERT hostility.\" \n\"The country sought an OVERT gesture of support from its allies, to show the enemy it was not alone in the struggle.\" \n\"The governor was angered by the OVERT favoritism the newspaper showed to her opponent.\" \nThe opposite of OVERT is <em>covert</em>, which means <em>covered up</em>, <em>concealed</em>."
            },
            "DEBONAIR": {
              "word": "DEBONAIR",
              "phonetic": "(deb-ÔøΩnair')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "suave; nonchalant, carefree, lighthearted \nDEBONAIR comes from a phrase in Old French, <em>de bon aire</em>, meaning \"of good family or disposition.\" Today DEBONAIR is used about people who are suave or have a carefree, charming manner. \n\"The DEBONAIR young man seemed to glide through life.\" \n\"He longed for the DEBONAIR existence of the rich bachelor.\" \n\"These happy, DEBONAIR people don't know what poverty and disease are like.\""
            },
            "INSOLVENT": {
              "word": "INSOLVENT",
              "phonetic": "(in-sol'-vQnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "bankrupt \nINSOLVENT is the combination of <em>solvent</em>, meaning \"able to meet financial obligations,\" and the prefix in-, meaning <em>not</em>. Thus INSOLVENT means \"unable to meet financial obligations,\" <em>bankrupt</em>. \n\"The INSOLVENT corporation owed its employees thousands of dollars in back pay.\" \n\"Bob told the bank he couldn't start paying off the loan because he was INSOLVENT.\" \nOther forms of the word: INSOLVENCY, n."
            },
            "RESPITE": {
              "word": "RESPITE",
              "phonetic": "(res'pit",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a pause, rest \nA RESPITE is a temporary pause from something unpleasant or distressing, an interval of rest or relief. \n\"The cotton pickers worked for hours in the hot sun without RESPITE.\" \n\"The concert was so terrible that the intermission was a welcome RESPITE.\" \n\"Sarah looked forward to her vacation; she felt that she needed a RESPITE from her fast-paced job.\""
            },
            "ROTUND": {
              "word": "ROTUND",
              "phonetic": "rO-tuhnd')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "plump, rounded \nROTUND comes from a Latin word meaning <em>round</em>, and is related to English words like <em>rotor</em> and <em>rotate</em>. ROTUND is used mainly about the roundness of a person's shape. It suggests a person who is short and fat, but not excessively so. \n\"He used to be skinny, but years of drinking beer have made him rather ROTUND.\" \n\"The ROTUND man looked as though he would bounce if he fell down.\" \nA related word, ROTUNDA, refers to a round building or a large round room. \nOther forms of the word: ROTUNDITY, n."
            },
            "HOVEL": {
              "word": "HOVEL",
              "phonetic": "(huhv'-ÔøΩI",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an open shed; a hut, miserable dwelling \nA HOVEL was originally an open shed used for storing tools or sheltering livestock. Now it is a hut or any small, dismal place in which people live. \n\"The penniless family lived in a miserable HOVEL at the edge of town.\" \n\"I wouldn't let a dog live in that HOVEL, much less a human being.\" \nRUBBISH is the most common wrong answer on the Pretest, chosen by people who know that a HOVEL is something dirty and wretched, but who are unsure of its specific meaning."
            },
            "INORDINATE": {
              "word": "INORDINATE",
              "phonetic": "(in-or'-dÔøΩ-nit)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "excessive, immoderate, exorbitant \nINORDINATE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>order</em> or <em>arrange</em>, and its root meaning is \"not in order.\" See <em>in-2</em> under Prefixes. The word is generally used about things that are \"not in order\" because they go beyond what is reasonable or acceptable. \n\"Two hours is an INORDINATE amount of time to spend taking a bath.\" \n\"Mary had an INORDINATE fondness for orange pineapple creams. She would eat them by the pound.\" \n\"Viewers were repelled by the INORDINATE amount of violence in the movie.\""
            },
            "INTRACTABLE": {
              "word": "INTRACTABLE",
              "phonetic": "(in-trak'-tÔøΩ-bÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "stubborn, obstinate, unmanageable \nThe <em>tract</em> part of INTRACTABLE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>handle</em> or <em>treat</em>. A person who is <em>tractable</em> is able to be handled or controlled. An INTRACTABLE person cannot be controlled, is stubborn or unmanageable. See <em>in-2</em> under Prefixes. \n\"The INTRACTABLE student simply refused to obey the teacher.\" \n\"When it saw the trailer, the INTRACTABLE horse dug its heels into the ground and refused to move.\" \nINTRACTABLE can also be applied to things, and means \"difficult to work with\" or \"not easily relieved.\" \n\"The soil was so INTRACTABLE that Mr. Brown decided to give up farming.\" \n\"He could not mold the INTRACTABLE metal into the appropriate shape.\" \n\"The pain was INTRACTABLE: none of the medicines seemed to help.\""
            },
            "MANIFEST": {
              "word": "MANIFEST",
              "phonetic": "(man'-ÔøΩ-fest)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "evident, obvious, apparent \nSomething that is MANIFEST is apparent either to the eye or the mind. \n\"The young instructor's nervousness was so MANIFEST that everyone in the class noticed it immediately.\" \n\"It is MANIFEST that a dog that isn't housebroken belongs outside.\" \n\"Parking sideways across the street is a MANIFEST violation of both the law and common courtesy.\" \nThe term \"MANIFEST Destiny\" refers to a future event that people regard as \"apparently inevitable.\" \n\"In the 1800s, many Americans regarded territorial expansion as their nation's MANIFEST Destiny.\" \nMANIFEST is also a verb, meaning to show clearly. \n\"The nobleman's every action MANIFESTED his utter contempt for the common people.\" \nOther forms of the word: MANIFESTATION, n."
            },
            "VERTIGO": {
              "word": "VERTIGO",
              "phonetic": "(ver'-tÔøΩgO)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "dizziness \nVERTIGO comes from the Latin verb <em>vertere</em>, to turn, and means <em>dizziness</em>, the feeling that the world is whirling about you. Other English words from <em>vertere</em> include <em>divert</em>, <em>revert</em>, and <em>convert</em>. \n\"Just before she fainted, Jane was aware of a sensation of VERTIGO: the room seemed to start spinning around her at an increasing speed until she blacked out.\""
            },
            "CONDUCIVE": {
              "word": "CONDUCIVE",
              "phonetic": "(k:m-dU'-siv",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "favorable, helpful, promoting \nCONDUCIVE means <em>promoting</em>, <em>favorable</em>. The Latin root <em>duc</em> means <em>lead</em>; it is also found in such words as <em>produce</em> and <em>induce</em>. See <em>con<em>- under Prefixes. The adjective CONDUCIVE is always used with <em>to</em>. \n\"A glass of hot milk at bedtime is often CONDUCIVE to sleep.\" \n\"Ron found that the stress of his new job was not CONDUCIVE to domestic bliss: he yelled at his wife and children almost every evening.\""
            },
            "DISCONCERT": {
              "word": "DISCONCERT",
              "phonetic": "(dis-kÔøΩn-sert')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to confuse, perturb, upset \nThe phrase \"in concert\" means <em>in agreement</em>, <em>all together</em>. Someone who is DISCONCERTED is not \"together,\" is confused or flustered. See <em>dis-</em> under Prefixes. The word is generally applied to people. \n\"She was so DISCONCERTED by his sudden arrival that she just stood in the doorway and stared at him.\" \n\"The noise from the stands momentarily DISCONCERTED the tennis player.\" \n\"The rumor of possible layoffs DISCONCERTED the employees.\" \nThe adjective from DISCONCERT is DISCONCERTING. Something that is DISCONCERTING causes you to be flustered or disturbed. \n\"Nancy has a DISCONCERTING way of smiling knowingly whenever anyone speaks to her.\" \nOther forms of the word: DISCONCERTING, adj."
            },
            "INFUSE": {
              "word": "INFUSE",
              "phonetic": "(in-fyUz')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to fill, instill, imbue \nINFUSE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>pour into</em>. See <em>in-1</em> under Prefixes. The <em>fuse</em> root is also found in such words as <em>confuse</em>, <em>diffuse</em>, and <em>suffuse</em>. INFUSE means to <em>pour in</em> in a figurative sense, to instill or inculcate a belief, an emotion, or the like. \n\"The coach INFUSED his players with a sense of pride.\" \n\"The charges of corruption INFUSED a new spirit of bitterness into the campaign.\" \n\"Dickens's novels are INFUSED with a delight in humanity's variety.\" \nOther forms of the word: INFUSION, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to ABASE",
                  "answers": [
                    "harm",
                    "neglect",
                    "glorify",
                    "degrade",
                    "worry"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABASE",
                  "correct": "degrade"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to MALIGN",
                  "answers": [
                    "disgust",
                    "confuse",
                    "wound",
                    "cheat",
                    "slander"
                  ],
                  "word": "MALIGN",
                  "correct": "slander"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OVERT",
                  "answers": [
                    "unconcealed",
                    "secret",
                    "recent",
                    "upside-down",
                    "simple"
                  ],
                  "word": "OVERT",
                  "correct": "unconcealed"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEBONAIR",
                  "answers": [
                    "passionate",
                    "angry",
                    "carefree",
                    "wealthy",
                    "young"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEBONAIR",
                  "correct": "carefree"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INSOLVENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "angry",
                    "rich",
                    "dirty",
                    "stingy",
                    "bankrupt"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSOLVENT",
                  "correct": "bankrupt"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RESPITE",
                  "answers": [
                    "conclusion",
                    "pause",
                    "trick",
                    "repetition",
                    "response"
                  ],
                  "word": "RESPITE",
                  "correct": "pause"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ROTUND",
                  "answers": [
                    "plump",
                    "short",
                    "jolly",
                    "enormous",
                    "bald"
                  ],
                  "word": "ROTUND",
                  "correct": "plump"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HOVEL",
                  "answers": [
                    "basement",
                    "crate",
                    "mansion",
                    "hut",
                    "rubbish"
                  ],
                  "word": "HOVEL",
                  "correct": "hut"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INORDINATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "forbidden",
                    "jumbled",
                    "excessive",
                    "unexpected",
                    "insignificant"
                  ],
                  "word": "INORDINATE",
                  "correct": "excessive"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTRACTABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "impatient",
                    "rough",
                    "fatal",
                    "hidden",
                    "stubborn"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTRACTABLE",
                  "correct": "stubborn"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MANIFEST",
                  "answers": [
                    "usual",
                    "numerous",
                    "important",
                    "apparent",
                    "strong"
                  ],
                  "word": "MANIFEST",
                  "correct": "apparent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VERTIGO",
                  "answers": [
                    "dizziness",
                    "stiffness",
                    "fever",
                    "dryness",
                    "speed"
                  ],
                  "word": "VERTIGO",
                  "correct": "dizziness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONDUCIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "shocking",
                    "favorable",
                    "necessary",
                    "dangerous",
                    "appropriate"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONDUCIVE",
                  "correct": "favorable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DISCONCERT",
                  "answers": [
                    "explain",
                    "destroy",
                    "frighten",
                    "confuse",
                    "oppose"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCONCERT",
                  "correct": "confuse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to INFUSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "fill",
                    "bother",
                    "trick",
                    "cover",
                    "expand"
                  ],
                  "word": "INFUSE",
                  "correct": "fill"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it pleasant to ABASE yourself?",
                  "word": "ABASE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would people be MALIGNED if their actions were called commendable?",
                  "word": "MALIGN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is booing an OVERT expression of disapproval?",
                  "word": "OVERT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are DEBONAIR people apt to be glum?",
                  "word": "DEBONAIR",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do corporations seek to become INSOLVENT?",
                  "word": "INSOLVENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are RESPITES usually enjoyable?",
                  "word": "RESPITE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are basketball players usually ROTUND?",
                  "word": "ROTUND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would it be an ordeal to live in a HOVEL?",
                  "word": "HOVEL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a dollar an INORDINATE amount of money to spend on a book?",
                  "word": "INORDINATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a person be INTRACTABLE?",
                  "word": "INTRACTABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would someone be likely to notice a MANIFEST error?",
                  "word": "MANIFEST",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a merry-go-round cause VERTIGO?",
                  "word": "VERTIGO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is bankruptcy usually CONDUCIVE to happiness?",
                  "word": "CONDUCIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a nervous person easily DISCONCERTED?",
                  "word": "DISCONCERT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a person be INFUSED with courage?",
                  "word": "INFUSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The elevator quickly ABASED us to the lobby.",
                  "word": "ABASE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher MALIGNED him never to do that again.",
                  "word": "MALIGN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The spy carried out an OVERT investigation by sneaking into the embassy at night.",
                  "word": "OVERT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "George's DEBONAIR ways made him the life of every party.",
                  "word": "DEBONAIR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The company was declared INSOLVENT when it could no longer pay its creditors.",
                  "word": "INSOLVENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The town received no RESPITE from the enemy bombing.",
                  "word": "RESPITE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Ann started exercising after someone told her she was becoming ROTUND.",
                  "word": "ROTUND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The city tore down those old HOVELS and built modern houses on the same spot.",
                  "word": "HOVEL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The miser had an INORDINATE love of gold.",
                  "word": "INORDINATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The INTRACTABLE workers agreed to do whatever their boss wanted.",
                  "word": "INTRACTABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The doctor's MANIFEST concern for her patients made them trust her.",
                  "word": "MANIFEST",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Standing on the roof of the building gave him such a feeling of VERTIGO that he was afraid he would fall off.",
                  "word": "VERTIGO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Loud music in the background is not CONDUCIVE to effective studying.",
                  "word": "CONDUCIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Charles had a DISCONCERTING habit of staring intently at complete strangers.",
                  "word": "DISCONCERT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The preacher's words INFUSED us with a desire to reform.",
                  "word": "INFUSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ABASE",
                  "answers": [
                    "degrade",
                    "grovel",
                    "flinch"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABASE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MALIGN",
                  "answers": [
                    "delete",
                    "slander",
                    "detract"
                  ],
                  "word": "MALIGN",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OVERT",
                  "answers": [
                    "blatant",
                    "insistent",
                    "open"
                  ],
                  "word": "OVERT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEBONAIR",
                  "answers": [
                    "carefree",
                    "clever",
                    "affable"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEBONAIR",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INSOLVENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "bankrupt",
                    "impoverished",
                    "affluent"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSOLVENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RESPITE",
                  "answers": [
                    "conclusion",
                    "recess",
                    "interval"
                  ],
                  "word": "RESPITE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ROTUND",
                  "answers": [
                    "ruddy",
                    "portly",
                    "obese"
                  ],
                  "word": "ROTUND",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HOVEL",
                  "answers": [
                    "ranch",
                    "slum",
                    "shed"
                  ],
                  "word": "HOVEL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INORDINATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "extraordinary",
                    "extravagant",
                    "extraneous"
                  ],
                  "word": "INORDINATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTRACTABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "unruly",
                    "wanton",
                    "obstinate"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTRACTABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MANIFEST",
                  "answers": [
                    "apparent",
                    "necessary",
                    "distinct"
                  ],
                  "word": "MANIFEST",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VERTIGO",
                  "answers": [
                    "hoarseness",
                    "giddiness",
                    "dizziness"
                  ],
                  "word": "VERTIGO",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONDUCIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "contributing",
                    "helpful",
                    "simple"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONDUCIVE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISCONCERT",
                  "answers": [
                    "confound",
                    "defile",
                    "nonplus"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCONCERT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INFUSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "imbue",
                    "inspire",
                    "perplex"
                  ],
                  "word": "INFUSE",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "7.2",
          "definitions": {
            "PREDISPOSED": {
              "word": "PREDISPOSED",
              "phonetic": "(prE-dis-pOzd')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "inclined, tending, susceptible \nOne meaning of the verb to <em>dispose</em> is to <em>make willing</em>. To PREDISPOSE is to make willing in advance. See <em>pre-</em> under Prefixes. The word suggests putting someone in the right frame of mind ahead of time. It is usually used with <em>to</em>. \n\"His open, honest face PREDISPOSED me to believe him.\" \nPREDISPOSE is also used about one's physical condition. In this sense it means to <em>make susceptible</em>. \n\"Her frail constitution PREDISPOSED her to a variety of ailments.\" \nPREDISPOSE is more often seen in its adjectival form, PREDISPOSED. As an adjective, it generally comes after the noun it modifies. \n\"Because he was broke, he was PREDISPOSED to accept whatever money they offered him.\" \nOther forms of the word: PREDISPOSE, v. PREDISPOSITION, n."
            },
            "REPROVE": {
              "word": "REPROVE",
              "phonetic": "(ri-prUv')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to rebuke, scold, admonish, reprimand \nTo REPROVE is to scold or criticize. The word usually suggests that the scolding is done without anger or harshness, in order to help the person. \n\"Sally's mother gently REPROVED her for going out without her mittens.\" \n\"The principal felt compelled to REPROVE the students for their rowdy behavior.\" \nThe noun related to REPROVE is REPROOF, which is an expression of blame or censure. \n\"Her mother's REPROOF made Sally decide to mend her ways.\" \nOther forms of the word: REPROOF, n."
            },
            "SUBTERFUGE": {
              "word": "SUBTERFUGE",
              "phonetic": "(suhb'-tÔøΩr-fyUj)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a deception, artifice, stratagem \nSUBTERFUGE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>flee secretly</em>. A SUBTERFUGE is a trick or tactic used to avoid or conceal something. \n\"Through various SUBTERFUGES he managed to avoid paying any income tax.\" \n\"We saw through all his SUBTERFUGES, and wouldn't let him get away with anything.\" \n\"The police used SUBTERFUGE to help the singer escape: they put a look-alike in the limousine, while the singer drove away unnoticed in a police car.\""
            },
            "ACQUIESCE": {
              "word": "ACQUIESCE",
              "phonetic": "(ak-wE-es')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to agree, assent, go along \nTo ACQUIESCE is to comply passively or tacitly. The word suggests going along with something because one is unwilling to protest or oppose it. ACQUIESCE is often followed by <em>in</em> or <em>to</em>. \n\"When the workers threatened to strike, management was forced to ACQUIESCE to their demand.\" \n\"I'm afraid we cannot ACQUIESCE in this matter. Our opposition is unalterable.\" \n\"He was opposed to using credit cards, but because he had no cash, he finally ACQUIESCED.\" \nOther forms of the word: ACQUIESCENCE, n. ACQUIESCENT, adj."
            },
            "ACRIMONIOUS": {
              "word": "ACRIMONIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ak-rÔøΩ-mO'-nE-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "bitter, stinging, sharp, biting \nThe Latin adjective <em>acer</em> means <em>sharp</em> or <em>sour</em>, and is found in English words like <em>acrid</em>, <em>acute</em>, <em>acid</em>, and <em>acerbic</em>. ACRIMONIOUS means <em>sharp</em> in a figurative sense, and suggests bitterness of speech, feeling, behavior, or disposition. \n\"Janice wrote an ACRIMONIOUS letter to her parents after they refused to come to her wedding.\" \n\"Bill could tell by her ACRIMONIOUS reply that she had a hot temper.\" \n\"She wondered whether his ACRIMONIOUS remarks about marriage stemmed from his recent divorce.\" \nACRIMONY is a biting sharpness or bitterness; like ACRIMONIOUS it has to do with speech, feeling, or behavior. \n\"The jurors never forgot the ACRIMONY with which the defendant's mother protested their verdict,\" \nOther forms of the word: ACRIMONY, n."
            },
            "COPIOUS": {
              "word": "COPIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(kO'-pE-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "plentiful, abundant, ample \nCOPIOUS means <em>plentiful</em>, \"existing in abundance.\" \n\"We have a COPIOUS supply of meat in the freezer.\" \n\"The composer's works are not COPIOUS, but they make up in quality what they lack in quantity.\" \nCOPIOUS is also sometimes used about language that is full of thought or wordy. \n\"The students were hard put to take notes on everything the professor said during his COPIOUS lecture.\""
            },
            "FURTIVE": {
              "word": "FURTIVE",
              "phonetic": "(fer'-tiv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "secret, stealthy, sneaky \nFURTIVE comes from a Latin word meaning <em>thief</em>. See <em>-ive</em> under Suffixes. FURTIVE means \"characterized by the stealth and watchfulness of a thief.\" It is applied to people, their actions, and their expressions. \n\"The FURTIVE soldier crept quietly through the enemy lines.\" \n\"With a FURTIVE glance around him the thief reached toward the open cash register.\" \n\"Gail signaled FURTIVELY to her brother to keep quiet about going to the movies.\""
            },
            "HARBINGER": {
              "word": "HARBINGER",
              "phonetic": "(hahr'-bÔøΩn-jÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a forerunner, herald, precursor \nA HARBINGER was originally a person sent ahead to prepare lodgings for English royalty when they traveled. From this, the word came to be used about anyone or anything that is a forerunner of something else. \n\"The sound of the trumpets was a HARBINGER of the king's arrival.\" \n\"The cold north wind is a sure HARBINGER of winter.\" \n\"The secretaries knew that the boss's early-morning frown was a HARBINGER of a bad day to come.\" \nHARBINGER is also occasionally used as a verb. \n\"The poor harvest HARBINGERS a long and difficult winter for everyone.\""
            },
            "INCLEMENT": {
              "word": "INCLEMENT",
              "phonetic": "(in-klem'-ÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "stormy, severe, harsh \nThe word <em>clement</em> means <em>mild</em> or <em>merciful</em>. INCLEMENT is the opposite of clement; see <em>in-2</em> under Prefixes. INCLEMENT means <em>stormy</em> or <em>severe</em>, and is usually used about the weather. \n\"The baseball game was postponed because of INCLEMENT weather.\" \nOther forms of the word: INCLEMENCY, n."
            },
            "PORTENT": {
              "word": "PORTENT",
              "phonetic": "(por'tent)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an omen, sign, augury \nA PORTENT is an omen or sign of something calamitous or very important that is about to happen. \n\"The natives took the eclipse to be a PORTENT of evil times to come.\" \n\"The boss's friendly smile was a PORTENT that this job would be better than Jack's previous one.\" \nThe verb related to PORTENT is PORTEND, which means \"to be an omen of,\" to <em>presage</em>. \n\"These early snowstorms PORTEND a long, cold winter.\" \nThe adjective from PORTENT is PORTENTOUS, which means <em>ominous</em>, <em>fateful</em>. Sometimes it is used in a less threatening sense to mean <em>prodigious</em>, <em>marvelous</em>. \n\"We will always remember having lived through these PORTENTOUS times.\" \nOther forms of the word: PORTEND, v. PORTENTOUS, adj."
            },
            "ADVERSITY": {
              "word": "ADVERSITY",
              "phonetic": "(ad-ver'-sÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "misfortune, disaster, trouble, distress \nADVERSITY is a state of misfortune or suffering. \n\"He kept a great deal of money in the bank as a protection against ADVERSITY.\" \n\"Susan did not let physical ADVERSITY keep her from improving her mind.\" \n\"Some artists seem to thrive on ADVERSITY; the more they suffer, the more they create.\" \nWhen used in the plural, ADVERSITIES, the word means <em>unfortunate experiences</em>, <em>disasters</em>. \n\"There seemed to be no end to these ADVERSITIES; it was just one stroke of bad luck after another.\" \nOther forms of the word: ADVERSE, adj."
            },
            "COGITATE": {
              "word": "COGITATE",
              "phonetic": "(koj'-ÔøΩtAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to ponder, meditate, think carefully \nTo COGITATE is to think deeply, to consider carefully. The word does not necessarily suggest that there will be any result from the thinking. \n\"He smoked his pipe and COGITATED for a long time about the best place to do his fishing.\" \n\"John appeared to COGITATE for ten minutes before he answered the question.\" \nThe noun from COGITATE is COGITATION, meaning <em>deep thought</em>. \n\"After long COGITATION, Alan thought he had the answer.\" \nOther forms of the word: COGITATION, n."
            },
            "CORPULENT": {
              "word": "CORPULENT",
              "phonetic": "(kor'-pyÔøΩlÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "fat, stout, obese \nCORPULENT comes from the Latin word for <em>body</em>, also the source of the English words <em>corpse</em> and <em>corporation</em>. People who are CORPULENT have too much flesh; they have large, overweight bodies. CORPULENT has a somewhat more negative sense than <em>fat</em> or <em>stout</em>; it is not quite as negative as <em>obese</em>, however, which suggests gross fatness. \n\"The CORPULENT passenger could barely fit into the seat on the airplane.\" \n\"Before her diet Janet was CORPULENT and unhealthy; now she is slim and feels wonderful.\n\" Other forms of the word: CORPULENCE, n."
            },
            "DERISIVE": {
              "word": "DERISIVE",
              "phonetic": "(di-rl'-siv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "mocking, ridiculing, scoffing \nTo DERIDE is to make fun of in a bitter or contemptuous way. It comes from the Latin word for laugh, also the source of the word <em>ridiculous</em>. \n\"Jones said he had found a way to make himself invisible, but scientists DERIDED his claim.\" \nDERISIVE is the adjective from DERIDE. See <em>-ive</em> under Suffixes. \n\"The audience responded to the stupid movie with DERISIVE laughter.\" \n\"The DERISIVE senior said that only a freshman would be dumb enough to believe that he had to go to school on Saturday.\" \nOther forms of the word: DERIDE, v. DERISION, n."
            },
            "DISCONSOLATE": {
              "word": "DISCONSOLATE",
              "phonetic": "(dis-kon'-sÔøΩlit)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "heartbroken, dejected, depressed \nTo console means to <em>cheer up</em>, to <em>give comfort to</em>. DISCONSOLATE means \"not consoled, deeply dejected, hopelessly sad.\" See <em>dis-</em> under Prefixes and <em>-ate2</em> under Suffixes. \n\"We were DISCONSOLATE when we found out our team had been disqualified.\" \n\"Don't be DISCONSOLATE. Things are bound to get better.\" \n\"The sad expression on his face mirrored his DISCONSOLATE state of mind.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "PREDISPOSED",
                  "answers": [
                    "inclined",
                    "unwilling",
                    "expected",
                    "too sick",
                    "discarded"
                  ],
                  "word": "PREDISPOSED",
                  "correct": "inclined"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to REPROVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "recommend",
                    "teach",
                    "rebuke",
                    "require",
                    "shun"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPROVE",
                  "correct": "rebuke"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUBTERFUGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "escape",
                    "deception",
                    "theft",
                    "attack",
                    "hideout"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUBTERFUGE",
                  "correct": "deception"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ACQUIESCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "confess",
                    "obtain",
                    "insist",
                    "oppose",
                    "agree"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACQUIESCE",
                  "correct": "agree"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ACRIMONIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "formal",
                    "discouraging",
                    "bitter",
                    "friendly",
                    "noisy"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACRIMONIOUS",
                  "correct": "bitter"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COPIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "difficult",
                    "scarce",
                    "repetitive",
                    "plentiful",
                    "grand"
                  ],
                  "word": "COPIOUS",
                  "correct": "plentiful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FURTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "secret",
                    "dangerous",
                    "positive",
                    "unimportant",
                    "clever"
                  ],
                  "word": "FURTIVE",
                  "correct": "secret"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HARBINGER",
                  "answers": [
                    "actor",
                    "bird",
                    "forerunner",
                    "danger",
                    "historian"
                  ],
                  "word": "HARBINGER",
                  "correct": "forerunner"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCLEMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "dark",
                    "fair",
                    "changing",
                    "stormy",
                    "unusual"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCLEMENT",
                  "correct": "stormy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PORTENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "copy",
                    "omen",
                    "ship",
                    "key",
                    "desire"
                  ],
                  "word": "PORTENT",
                  "correct": "omen"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADVERSITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "difference",
                    "luck",
                    "hardship",
                    "danger",
                    "conflict"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADVERSITY",
                  "correct": "hardship"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to COGITATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "disturb",
                    "lecture",
                    "remember",
                    "ponder",
                    "strain"
                  ],
                  "word": "COGITATE",
                  "correct": "ponder"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CORPULENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "wretched",
                    "merry",
                    "proud",
                    "rich",
                    "fat"
                  ],
                  "word": "CORPULENT",
                  "correct": "fat"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DERISIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "helpful",
                    "final",
                    "mocking",
                    "unoriginal",
                    "angry"
                  ],
                  "word": "DERISIVE",
                  "correct": "mocking"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISCONSOLATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "heartbroken",
                    "excited",
                    "defeated",
                    "lonely",
                    "enraged"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCONSOLATE",
                  "correct": "heartbroken"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Should a jury be PREDISPOSED to find a defendant guilty?",
                  "word": "PREDISPOSED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a heroic act deserve a REPROOF?",
                  "word": "REPROVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a disguise be a form of SUBTERFUGE?",
                  "word": "SUBTERFUGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could people ACQUIESCE in something they don't favor?",
                  "word": "ACQUIESCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do ACRIMONIOUS discussions promote friendship?",
                  "word": "ACRIMONIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is there a COPIOUS supply of water in the desert?",
                  "word": "COPIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a spy be FURTIVE?",
                  "word": "FURTIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can animals be HARBINGERS?",
                  "word": "HARBINGER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people enjoy having a picnic in INCLEMENT weather?",
                  "word": "INCLEMENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a PORTENT be favorable?",
                  "word": "PORTENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a depression a time of economic ADVERSITY?",
                  "word": "ADVERSITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a sleeping person COGITATE?",
                  "word": "COGITATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a CORPULENT person have a large girth?",
                  "word": "CORPULENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Might people DERIDE a buffoon?",
                  "word": "DERISIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a DISCONSOLATE person need to be comforted?",
                  "word": "DISCONSOLATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "She PREDISPOSED of her Christmas presents early in December.",
                  "word": "PREDISPOSED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Victor seemed indifferent when he was REPROVED.",
                  "word": "REPROVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The embezzler used some very sophisticated SUBTERFUGES to escape detection.",
                  "word": "SUBTERFUGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The company ACQUIESCED to the workers' demand for another paid holiday.",
                  "word": "ACQUIESCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "There was considerable ACRIMONY over the unfair tactics the other team had used in the game.",
                  "word": "ACRIMONIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jerry's grandmother gave him a COPIOUS serving of ice cream for dessert.",
                  "word": "COPIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Chuck gave a FURTIVE wink to his fellow conspirator.",
                  "word": "FURTIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The crocus peeping up through the ground was the first HARBINGER of spring.",
                  "word": "HARBINGER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The plane had difficulty landing because of the INCLEMENT weather.",
                  "word": "INCLEMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone chose to ignore the PORTENTS of the coming war.",
                  "word": "PORTENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Someday these ADVERSITIES will seem less important to us, but right now they are quite oppressive.",
                  "word": "ADVERSITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Nancy COGITATED the right answer immediately.",
                  "word": "COGITATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The CORPULENT fellow didn't need to stuff a pillow under his coat in order to play Santa Claus.",
                  "word": "CORPULENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The DERISIVE audience hooted the singer off the stage.",
                  "word": "DERISIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Sally's parents tried to be DISCONSOLATE toward her when she lost the contest.",
                  "word": "DISCONSOLATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "PREDISPOSED",
                  "answers": [
                    "reminded",
                    "susceptible",
                    "biased"
                  ],
                  "word": "PREDISPOSED",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REPROVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "reproach",
                    "reprimand",
                    "repent"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPROVE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUBTERFUGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "wile",
                    "resistance",
                    "trickery"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUBTERFUGE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ACQUIESCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "advise",
                    "assent",
                    "accede"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACQUIESCE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ACRIMONIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "angry",
                    "sinister",
                    "sour"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACRIMONIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COPIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "lavish",
                    "profuse",
                    "prominent"
                  ],
                  "word": "COPIOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FURTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "sinful",
                    "secret",
                    "cunning"
                  ],
                  "word": "FURTIVE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HARBINGER",
                  "answers": [
                    "reporter",
                    "precursor",
                    "herald"
                  ],
                  "word": "HARBINGER",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCLEMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "harsh",
                    "rainy",
                    "warm"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCLEMENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PORTENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "omen",
                    "precursor",
                    "monument"
                  ],
                  "word": "PORTENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADVERSITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "trouble",
                    "misfortune",
                    "confusion"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADVERSITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COGITATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "reflect",
                    "surprise",
                    "meditate"
                  ],
                  "word": "COGITATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CORPULENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "strong",
                    "heavy",
                    "big"
                  ],
                  "word": "CORPULENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DERISIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "bitter",
                    "cunning",
                    "mocking"
                  ],
                  "word": "DERISIVE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISCONSOLATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "woeful",
                    "dejected",
                    "confused"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCONSOLATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "7.3",
          "definitions": {
            "EXACERBATE": {
              "word": "EXACERBATE",
              "phonetic": "(ig-zas'-ÔøΩr-bAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to aggravate, embitter, irritate \nThe <em>acerb</em> part of EXACERBATE comes from a Latin word meaning <em>bitter</em> or <em>sour</em>. <em>Acerb</em>, or <em>acerbic</em>, also has the same meaning in English. To EXACERBATE something is to make it more bitter, to increase its severity or violence. See <em>-ate1</em> under Suffixes. The word is usually used about pain, emotions, or the like. \n\"You must eat something. Going without food will only EXACERBATE your illness.\" \n\"The mayor's thoughtless remark only served to EXACERBATE racial tensions in the city.\" \n\"Instead of solving the problem, Jack's foolish scheme EXACERBATED it.\""
            },
            "FELICITY": {
              "word": "FELICITY",
              "phonetic": "(fa-lis'-ÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "happiness, bliss; a pleasing manner \nFELICITY is a rather formal term for <em>happiness</em>. \n\"On their 50th anniversary, the couple were a model of wedded FELICITY.\" \n\"At the reunion, there was such FELICITY that smiles and laughter flowed like wine.\" \nIn a less common sense, FELICITY is a pleasing manner or quality, especially in language. \n\"Some say it was not the politician's platform that got him elected, but his good looks and FELICITY of speech.\" \nOther forms of the word: FELICITOUS, adj."
            },
            "OBLIVIOUS": {
              "word": "OBLIVIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩbliv'-E-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "forgetful, unaware, unmindful \nOBLIVIOUS and its related noun OBLIVION come from a Latin word meaning to <em>forget</em>. The basic meaning of OBLIVIOUS is <em>forgetful</em>, either because one chooses to forget, or because the matter is too trivial to remember. The word is usually followed by <em>of</em> or <em>to</em>. \n\"The sudden new crisis made Sheila OBLIVIOUS of her previous concerns.\" \n\"The union said it would strike if management remained OBLIVIOUS to its grievance.\" \nVery often OBLIVIOUS is used to mean <em>unaware</em>. \n\"The busy teacher was OBLIVIOUS of the talking and laughter going on all around her.\" \nThis usage is sometimes criticized as being too general and imprecise. \nOther forms of the word: OBLIVION, n."
            },
            "SQUALOR": {
              "word": "SQUALOR",
              "phonetic": "(skwol'-ÔøΩ)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "filthiness, corruption, baseness \nThe adjective SQUALID means filthy. \n\"They lived in a SQUALID apartment, with garbage heaped everywhere.\" \nSQUALID can also be applied to moral filth, and means <em>sordid</em>. \n\"The newspaper was filled with SQUALID stories about divorce trials and ax murders.\" \nSQUALOR is the noun from SQUALID. It too is used about both physical and moral filth. \n\"Janet longs to move away from the SQUALOR of the slums.\" \n\"The preacher denounced the moral SQUALOR in which so many people lived.\" \nOther forms of the word: SQUALID, adj."
            },
            "AFFRAY": {
              "word": "AFFRAY",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩfrA')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a brawl, noisy quarrel \nIn legal use, an AFFRAY is a public quarrel or fight loud enough to disturb people nearby. Generally, AFFRAY refers to any noisy or unseemly dispute. \n\"What had started as a political discussion turned into such an AFFRAY that people at nearby tables got up to leave.\" \n\"The two groups began to shout and throw garbage at each other, but the police broke up the AFFRAY.\" \n\"The argumentative economist was always getting into bitter AFFRAYS with his equally opinionated colleagues.\""
            },
            "ANTIPATHY": {
              "word": "ANTIPATHY",
              "phonetic": "(an-tip'-ÔøΩthE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "aversion, repugnance, distaste, enmity \nThe <em>path</em> part of ANTIPATHY comes from a Greek word meaning <em>feeling</em>; this root is also found in <em>pathos</em>, <em>pathetic</em>, and <em>sympathy</em>. See <em>anti-</em> under Prefixes and <em>-y</em> under Suffixes. ANTIPATHY is a \"feeling against someone or something, a sense of aversion or strong distaste. It is often followed by <em>to</em>, <em>toward</em>, or <em>against</em>. \n\"Sam's ANTIPATHY toward his boss was so great that he finally had to quit.\" \n\"His experience during the war left him with a strong ANTIPATHY to violence.\" \n\"John overcame his ANTIPATHY toward cats and now owns three of them.\" \nOther forms of the word: ANTIPATHETIC, adj."
            },
            "ASPECT": {
              "word": "ASPECT",
              "phonetic": "(as'-pekt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a part or feature; trait; appearance \nAn ASPECT of something or someone is a part you can see with either your eyes or your mind. Its Latin root, <em>spectare</em>, meaning to look or behold, is found in words like <em>inspect</em>, <em>spectator</em>, <em>prospect</em>, and <em>spectacle</em>. An ASPECT is something that is looked at, regarded, or considered. It can mean the actual appearance of something. \n\"Their painted bodies and unsmiling faces gave the natives a fierce ASPECT.\" \n\"The combination of dusk and fog gave the forest a terrifying ASPECT.\" \nASPECT can also be less visual and more figurative or abstract. \n\"The unfamiliar ASPECTS of Bob's new job confused him.\" \n\"The judge instructed the jurors to consider each ASPECT of the case with the greatest care.\" \nASPECT also means \"the manner in which something or someone is looked at or presented.\" \n\"A salesperson tries to present his product in a favorable ASPECT.\" \n\"I suddenly understood the poem when I regarded it in a different ASPECT.\""
            },
            "CONTRITION": {
              "word": "CONTRITION",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-trish'-ÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "repentance, remorse, penitence \nCONTRITION and its adjective CONTRITE come from a Latin word meaning to <em>bruise</em> or <em>grind</em>, also the source of the words <em>attrition</em> and <em>detritus</em>. People who are CONTRITE are bruised or broken in spirit because of sorrow for their sins. CONTRITION is sincere regret and sorrow for having done wrong. \n\"The child showed no CONTRITION for having stolen the money. In fact, he appeared to be happy that he had done it.\" \n\"We could tell Jane's CONTRITION for her crime was real: she couldn't stop crying as she tried to say how sorry she was.\" \n\"The criminal's words of CONTRITION did not sway the judge.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONTRITE, adj."
            },
            "IMPUDENT": {
              "word": "IMPUDENT",
              "phonetic": "(im'-pyU-dÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "shameless, disrespectful, impertinent, brazen \nIMPUDENT is made up of the prefix <em>im-</em>, meaning not, and the root <em>pud</em>, from a Latin word meaning to <em>feel shame</em>. An IMPUDENT person is shameless, especially in his or her attitude toward others. The word often stresses boldness and lack of respect. \n\"The IMPUDENT student simply ignored the principal when she spoke to him.\" \n\"The boss fired the worker because of his IMPUDENT behavior.\" \nThe noun from IMPUDENT is IMPUDENCE. \n\"Jane's mother made her apologize for her IMPUDENCE toward the guests.\" \n\"Because of his constant IMPUDENCE, Paul was told that he was no longer welcome as a member of the business association.\" \nOther forms of the word: IMPUDENCE, n."
            },
            "INDOLENT": {
              "word": "INDOLENT",
              "phonetic": "(in'-da-lÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "lazy, slothful \nINDOLENT means \"habitually lazy.\" An INDOLENT person is not inclined to work or to perform any other kind of exertion. \n\"She is so INDOLENT that she spends the entire summer lying on the beach.\" \n\"The INDOLENT fellows hung around the park all day, playing cards and watching the cars go by.\" \nThe noun form of INDOLENT is INDOLENCE. \n\"The boss accused his workers of INDOLENCE, saying that all they wanted to do was take long lunch hours.\" \nOther forms of the word: INDOLENCE, n."
            },
            "INTERLOPER": {
              "word": "INTERLOPER",
              "phonetic": "(in'-tÔøΩr-lOp-ÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an intruder, trespasser \nAn INTERLOPER is an intruder, someone who interferes in other people's affairs, often in order to gain a privilege or a right that belongs to someone else. \n\"A group of INTERLOPERS appeared and tried to take over our mining claims.\" \n\"She said no one had invited Dave to the party; he was nothing but an INTERLOPER.\" \nThe verb form is INTERLOPE, to <em>intrude</em>, <em>meddle</em>, <em>butt in</em>. \n\"The company official accused the government of constantly INTERLOPING in the affairs of business.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTERLOPE, v."
            },
            "MILIEU": {
              "word": "MILIEU",
              "phonetic": "(mEl-yÔøΩr')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "surroundings, environment, setting \nNote the pronunciation. MILIEU is a French word, and has retained its French pronunciation. The MILIEU of people is their surroundings, the social and physical setting in which they live. \n\"The book examines the cultural MILIEU in Vienna at the turn of the century.\" \n\"She came out of the slums of New York City and anyone who has lived in that MILIEU knows the obstacles she had to overcome.\" \n\"The painter did his best work in a strange MILIEU of poets, out-of-work actors, and assorted eccentrics.\""
            },
            "NEBULOUS": {
              "word": "NEBULOUS",
              "phonetic": "(neb'-ya-lÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "hazy, cloudy, indistinct, vague \nNEBULOUS comes from the Latin word for <em>cloud</em>. See <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. Something that is NEBULOUS is hazy and indistinct, like a cloud. The word is often used in an extended sense about anything that is dimly realized or not clearly established. \n\"The boundary between the countries is quite NEBULOUS; no one is sure where one country ends and the other begins.\" \n\"Their plans for the party are still NEBULOUS, but I'm sure everything will be settled by next week.\" \n\"NEBULOUS memories and ideas floated through her mind as she lay on the hammock.\" \nOther forms of the word: NEBULOSITY, n."
            },
            "ODIOUS": {
              "word": "ODIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(O'-dE-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "hateful, abhorrent, offensive, detestable \nODIOUS and the noun ODIUM come from a Latin word meaning to <em>hate</em>. Something that is ODIOUS arouses one's hatred or disgust. \n\"I cannot tell you how shocked I am by your ODIOUS conduct.\" \n\"Finally they abolished their ODIOUS policy of excluding women from their club.\" \n\"The ODIOUS band of criminals would stop at nothing in carrying out their fiendish plans.\" \nOther forms of the word: ODIUM, n."
            },
            "REPAST": {
              "word": "REPAST",
              "phonetic": "(ri-past'",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a meal, food \nA REPAST is a meal, or the food provided at a meal. \n\"This salad will make a pleasant summer REPAST.\" \n\"For our evening REPAST we will have chicken wings and asparagus.\" \nThe <em>past</em> part of REPAST leads many people to pick <em>legend</em> on the Pretest as the word's meaning. The derivation of REPAST has nothing to do with time, however."
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to EXACERBATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "comfort",
                    "aggravate",
                    "falsify",
                    "calculate",
                    "elevate"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXACERBATE",
                  "correct": "aggravate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FELICITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "loyalty",
                    "ease",
                    "satisfaction",
                    "happiness",
                    "fame"
                  ],
                  "word": "FELICITY",
                  "correct": "happiness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBLIVIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "rash",
                    "helpless",
                    "high-spirited",
                    "aware",
                    "forgetful"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBLIVIOUS",
                  "correct": "forgetful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SQUALOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "cleanliness",
                    "wealth",
                    "filthiness",
                    "bitterness",
                    "storminess"
                  ],
                  "word": "SQUALOR",
                  "correct": "filthiness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AFFRAY",
                  "answers": [
                    "brawl",
                    "game",
                    "party",
                    "comedy",
                    "war"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFRAY",
                  "correct": "brawl"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANTIPATHY",
                  "answers": [
                    "depression",
                    "confusion",
                    "understanding",
                    "fear",
                    "aversion"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANTIPATHY",
                  "correct": "aversion"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASPECT",
                  "answers": [
                    "appearance",
                    "decision",
                    "behavior",
                    "opportunity",
                    "feeling"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASPECT",
                  "correct": "appearance"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTRITION",
                  "answers": [
                    "pressure",
                    "anxiety",
                    "repentance",
                    "pride",
                    "holiness"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTRITION",
                  "correct": "repentance"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPUDENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "helpless",
                    "cautious",
                    "shameless",
                    "courageous",
                    "playful"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPUDENT",
                  "correct": "shameless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INDOLENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "lazy",
                    "hardworking",
                    "poor",
                    "weak",
                    "mean"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDOLENT",
                  "correct": "lazy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTERLOPER",
                  "answers": [
                    "thief",
                    "intruder",
                    "messenger",
                    "beginner",
                    "opponent"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTERLOPER",
                  "correct": "intruder"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MILIEU",
                  "answers": [
                    "surroundings",
                    "target",
                    "substitute",
                    "food",
                    "inhabitants"
                  ],
                  "word": "MILIEU",
                  "correct": "surroundings"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NEBULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "false",
                    "incredible",
                    "distant",
                    "hazy",
                    "bright"
                  ],
                  "word": "NEBULOUS",
                  "correct": "hazy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ODIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "foreign",
                    "hateful",
                    "sweet",
                    "clear",
                    "unusual"
                  ],
                  "word": "ODIOUS",
                  "correct": "hateful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REPAST",
                  "answers": [
                    "play",
                    "party",
                    "legend",
                    "beverage",
                    "meal"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPAST",
                  "correct": "meal"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Could cigarette smoking EXACERBATE a respiratory infection?",
                  "word": "EXACERBATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does living in a hovel cause FELICITY?",
                  "word": "FELICITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it possible to be OBLIVIOUS of noisy surroundings?",
                  "word": "OBLIVIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a palace likely to be SQUALID?",
                  "word": "SQUALOR",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could an AFFRAY involve bitter words?",
                  "word": "AFFRAY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do mothers usually show ANTIPATHY toward their children?",
                  "word": "ANTIPATHY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are there furtive ASPECTS to being an undercover agent?",
                  "word": "ASPECT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a CONTRITE person be likely to apologize?",
                  "word": "CONTRITION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a teacher want to rebuke a pupil for IMPUDENCE?",
                  "word": "IMPUDENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an INDOLENT person make a good employee?",
                  "word": "INDOLENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are INTERLOPERS welcome?",
                  "word": "INTERLOPER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can people be part of a MILIEU?",
                  "word": "MILIEU",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a thought be NEBULOUS?",
                  "word": "NEBULOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it ODIOUS to be a murderer?",
                  "word": "ODIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a banquet be a REPAST?",
                  "word": "REPAST",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher EXACERBATED them for smoking on the school grounds.",
                  "word": "EXACERBATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mr. Jones claimed that nothing was more important to him than his wife's FELICITY.",
                  "word": "FELICITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "When hard at work, John became OBLIVIOUS of his surroundings.",
                  "word": "OBLIVIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The SQUALOR of the teenagers' bedrooms contrasted vividly with the cleanliness of the rest of the house.",
                  "word": "SQUALOR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was a quiet AFFRAY, attended only by his close friends.",
                  "word": "AFFRAY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I have considerable ANTIPATHY for your predicament; unfortunately, there is nothing I can do to help you.",
                  "word": "ANTIPATHY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Looking at it from a different ASPECT, I can understand why she was upset.",
                  "word": "ASPECT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The murderer expressed great CONTRITION when she said the victim got what he deserved.",
                  "word": "CONTRITION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The IMPUDENT children stuck their tongues out at the woman.",
                  "word": "IMPUDENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His INDOLENCE is astonishing; he wouldn't get out of bed if he didn't have to eat.",
                  "word": "INDOLENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Betty called the new salesman an INTERLOPER for trying to take over some of her accounts.",
                  "word": "INTERLOPER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The refined lady seemed out of place in the rough-and-tumble MILIEU of the waterfront.",
                  "word": "MILIEU",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They painted their house a bright, NEBULOUS color.",
                  "word": "NEBULOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She exclaimed with delight at the ODIOUS smell of the roses.",
                  "word": "ODIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The man entertained us with REPASTS of things that had happened long ago.",
                  "word": "REPAST",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "EXACERBATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "worsen",
                    "destroy",
                    "embitter"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXACERBATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FELICITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "pleasure",
                    "contentment",
                    "nostalgia"
                  ],
                  "word": "FELICITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBLIVIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "unaware",
                    "careful",
                    "forgetful"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBLIVIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SQUALOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "filth",
                    "sordidness",
                    "danger"
                  ],
                  "word": "SQUALOR",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AFFRAY",
                  "answers": [
                    "meeting",
                    "quarrel",
                    "wrangle"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFRAY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANTIPATHY",
                  "answers": [
                    "ferocity",
                    "repugnance",
                    "aversion"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANTIPATHY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASPECT",
                  "answers": [
                    "belief",
                    "view",
                    "trait"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASPECT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTRITION",
                  "answers": [
                    "regret",
                    "remorse",
                    "resentment"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTRITION",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPUDENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "angry",
                    "brash",
                    "insolent"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPUDENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INDOLENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "lonely",
                    "lethargic",
                    "languid"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDOLENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTERLOPER",
                  "answers": [
                    "conqueror",
                    "meddler",
                    "intruder"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTERLOPER",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MILIEU",
                  "answers": [
                    "discipline",
                    "atmosphere",
                    "background"
                  ],
                  "word": "MILIEU",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NEBULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "unclear",
                    "unknown",
                    "imprecise"
                  ],
                  "word": "NEBULOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ODIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "hateful",
                    "disgusting",
                    "fearful"
                  ],
                  "word": "ODIOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REPAST",
                  "answers": [
                    "dessert",
                    "breakfast",
                    "water"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPAST",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ACQUIESCE",
            "answer": "acquiesce"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONDUCIVE",
            "answer": "conducive"
          },
          {
            "word": "FELICITY",
            "answer": "felicity"
          },
          {
            "word": "INDOLENT",
            "answer": "indolent"
          },
          {
            "word": "OVERT",
            "answer": "overt"
          },
          {
            "word": "ACRIMONIOUS",
            "answer": "acrimonious"
          },
          {
            "word": "COPIOUS",
            "answer": "copious or inordinate"
          },
          {
            "word": "FURTIVE",
            "answer": "furtive"
          },
          {
            "word": "INFUSE",
            "answer": "infused"
          },
          {
            "word": "REPAST",
            "answer": "repast"
          },
          {
            "word": "ADVERSITY",
            "answer": "adversities"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEBONAIR",
            "answer": "debonair"
          },
          {
            "word": "HARBINGER",
            "answer": "harbinger"
          },
          {
            "word": "INORDINATE",
            "answer": "inordinate"
          },
          {
            "word": "ROTUND",
            "answer": "rotund"
          },
          {
            "word": "AFFRAY",
            "answer": "affray"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXACERBATE",
            "answer": "exacerbate"
          },
          {
            "word": "HOVEL",
            "answer": "hovel"
          },
          {
            "word": "MALIGN",
            "answer": "maligned"
          },
          {
            "word": "SUBTERFUGE",
            "answer": "subterfuges"
          },
          {
            "word": "ANTIPATHY",
            "answer": "antipathy"
          },
          {
            "word": "ABASE",
            "answer": "abase"
          },
          {
            "word": "DERISIVE",
            "answer": "derisive"
          },
          {
            "word": "INSOLVENT",
            "answer": "insolvent"
          },
          {
            "word": "NEBULOUS",
            "answer": "nebulous"
          },
          {
            "word": "REPROVE",
            "answer": "reproved"
          },
          {
            "word": "ASPECT",
            "answer": "aspect"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISCONCERT",
            "answer": "disconsulate"
          },
          {
            "word": "INTERLOPER",
            "answer": "interloper"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBLIVIOUS",
            "answer": "oblivious"
          },
          {
            "word": "RESPITE",
            "answer": "respite"
          },
          {
            "word": "COGITATE",
            "answer": "cogitate"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISCONSOLATE",
            "answer": "disconsulate"
          },
          {
            "word": "INTRACTABLE",
            "answer": "intractable"
          },
          {
            "word": "ODIOUS",
            "answer": "odious"
          },
          {
            "word": "SQUALOR",
            "answer": "squalor"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONTRITION",
            "answer": "contrition"
          },
          {
            "word": "IMPUDENT",
            "answer": "impudent"
          },
          {
            "word": "MANIFEST",
            "answer": "manifest"
          },
          {
            "word": "PORTENT",
            "answer": "portent"
          },
          {
            "word": "VERTIGO",
            "answer": "vertigo"
          },
          {
            "word": "CORPULENT",
            "answer": "corpulent"
          },
          {
            "word": "INCLEMENT",
            "answer": "inclement"
          },
          {
            "word": "MILIEU",
            "answer": "milieu"
          },
          {
            "word": "PREDISPOSED",
            "answer": "predisposed"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "The noisy",
            "part2": "between the two gangs awoke everyone in the neighborhood.",
            "correct": "affray",
            "word": "AFFRAY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "To avoid publicity, the movie star adopted such",
            "part2": "as registering in hotels under an assumed name.",
            "correct": "subterfuges",
            "word": "SUBTERFUGE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The arrival of flocks of birds from the south was a(n)",
            "part2": "of spring.",
            "correct": "harbinger",
            "word": "HARBINGER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was a totally honest man, and felt a strong",
            "part2": "toward those who didn't tell the truth.",
            "correct": "antipathy",
            "word": "ANTIPATHY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "thief moved stealthily through the darkened warehouse.",
            "correct": "furtive",
            "word": "FURTIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Many studies have shown that physical exercise is",
            "part2": "to good health.",
            "correct": "conducive",
            "word": "CONDUCIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We had a delightful",
            "part2": "at the fine French restaurant.",
            "correct": "repast",
            "word": "REPAST"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Despite these temporary",
            "part2": ", he was ultimately able to triumph.",
            "correct": "adversities",
            "word": "ADVERSITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "dispute over who would pay the bill threatened to turn into a full-scale fight.",
            "correct": "acrimonious",
            "word": "ACRIMONIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Everyone admired the",
            "part2": "youth's lighthearted ways.",
            "correct": "debonair",
            "word": "DEBONAIR"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The children grew up in a wretched",
            "part2": "without running water or electricity.",
            "correct": "hovel",
            "word": "HOVEL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "woman spent all her time watching television instead of working.",
            "correct": "indolent",
            "word": "INDOLENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Far from easing the pain, this new drug seems to",
            "part2": "it.",
            "correct": "exacerbate",
            "word": "EXACERBATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The teacher frowned and shook her head and made other",
            "part2": "signs of her displeasure.",
            "correct": "overt",
            "word": "OVERT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We felt that a week was a(n)",
            "part2": "amount of time to wait for our telephone to be fixed.",
            "correct": "inordinate",
            "word": "INORDINATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Harry could always get a job playing Santa Claus because of his",
            "part2": "shape.",
            "correct": "rotund",
            "word": "ROTUND"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mary puts",
            "part2": "amounts of catsup on everything she eats.",
            "correct": "copious or inordinate",
            "word": "COPIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The mayor's enemies",
            "part2": "him by spreading the false rumor that he had taken a bribe.",
            "correct": "maligned",
            "word": "MALIGN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The sight of our old home",
            "part2": "us with a profound sense of nostalgia.",
            "correct": "infused",
            "word": "INFUSE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "With a loving husband and an exciting job she thought nothing could disturb her",
            "part2": ", then tragedy struck.",
            "correct": "felicity",
            "word": "FELICITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We insisted that he go along with us on this, but he refused to",
            "part2": "to our demand.",
            "correct": "acquiesce",
            "word": "ACQUIESCE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The writer lived in the exotic",
            "part2": "of the jungles of Sri Lanka.",
            "correct": "milieu",
            "word": "MILIEU"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I'm afraid the weather is going to be",
            "part2": "; a severe storm is headed our way.",
            "correct": "inclement",
            "word": "INCLEMENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The high priest said the appearance of the comet was a(n)",
            "part2": "of some great calamity.",
            "correct": "portent",
            "word": "PORTENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Al was momentarily",
            "part2": "by the unexpected sound of laughter, but then he realized it was only the television.",
            "correct": "disconcerted",
            "word": "DISCONSOLATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The business recession caused many companies to become",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "insolvent",
            "word": "INSOLVENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The audience's displeasure with the performance was so",
            "part2": "that even the stagehands noticed it.",
            "correct": "manifest",
            "word": "MANIFEST"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "child told the teacher she was stupid.",
            "correct": "impudent",
            "word": "IMPUDENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "owners refused to meet any of the players' demands.",
            "correct": "intractable",
            "word": "INTRACTABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "If you continue to gain weight, you won't be just heavy, you'll be",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "corpulent",
            "word": "CORPULENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Andrea was absolutely",
            "part2": "when she lost the competition; nothing we said could cheer her up.",
            "correct": "disconsulate",
            "word": "DISCONSOLATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Their plans were rather",
            "part2": "at first, but they became clearer as time went by.",
            "correct": "nebulous",
            "word": "NEBULOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When he was angry, his expression took on a fierce",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "aspect",
            "word": "ASPECT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The criminal expressed no",
            "part2": "for his evil deed; in fact, he said he'd do it again.",
            "correct": "contrition",
            "word": "CONTRITION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Since Alan's brothers had been smart, the teacher was",
            "part2": "to believe that he was smart too.",
            "correct": "predisposed",
            "word": "PREDISPOSED"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The incredible",
            "part2": "of the abandoned house defeated our efforts to clean it up.",
            "correct": "squalor",
            "word": "SQUALOR"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Sarah was completely",
            "part2": "to all of the petty little problems of everyday life.",
            "correct": "oblivious",
            "word": "OBLIVIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Being alone in an open space gave her a feeling of",
            "part2": "; the world would seem to spin around her, and she'd almost lose her balance.",
            "correct": "vertigo",
            "word": "VERTIGO"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Simpson had to",
            "part2": "a long time about the difficult problem he needed to solve.",
            "correct": "cogitate",
            "word": "COGITATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I'm no",
            "part2": ",I have as much right to be here as you do.",
            "correct": "interloper",
            "word": "INTERLOPER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "girls laughed scornfully at his feeble attempt to jump rope.",
            "correct": "derisive",
            "word": "DERISIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The judge gave the man the maximum sentence, calling his crime",
            "part2": "and an offense to all decent citizens.",
            "correct": "odious",
            "word": "ODIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After two hours of earsplitting noise we received a welcome",
            "part2": "when the man operating the jackhammer went to lunch.",
            "correct": "respite",
            "word": "RESPITE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The professor",
            "part2": "Tom for not getting his paper in on time, but said it wouldn't affect his grade.",
            "correct": "reproved",
            "word": "REPROVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim was willing to",
            "part2": "himself by begging for money from his relatives.",
            "correct": "abase",
            "word": "ABASE"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "7.4",
          "definitions": {
            "ASCRIBE": {
              "word": "ASCRIBE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩskrlb')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to attribute \nTo ASCRIBE something is to attribute or assign it as a cause or source. The word comes from the Latin <em>scribere</em>, to <em>write</em>, and originally meant \"to add to a writing or enter in a list.\" This Latin source is found in words like <em>prescribe</em> and <em>scribe</em>. Sometimes ASCRIBE still carries with it the sense of writing, in that it suggests the knowledge or authority of an expert. But ASCRIBE is often used interchangeably with the verb <em>attribute</em>. It is usually used with <em>to</em>. \n\"After careful examination, the scholar ASCRIBED the newly discovered diary to the second mate of the famous admiral.\" \n\"He ASCRIBES his financial misfortunes to careless bookkeeping.\" \nOther forms of the word: ASCRIPTION, n."
            },
            "AUSPICIOUS": {
              "word": "AUSPICIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(o-spish'-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "favorable, propitious, fortunate \nAUSPICIOUS comes from Latin words meaning \"to look at birds,\" and refers to the ancient Roman practice of telling the future by observing the flight of birds. Something that is AUSPICIOUS is a good omen; it augurs well for the future, usually because it is successful or fortunate itself. \n\"The singer's debut was AUSPICIOUS; the critics said she had a great career ahead of her.\" \n\"The first day of school was AUSPICIOUS; everything seemed to go well for Dale.\" \n\"The day began AUSPICIOUSLY when Bill found a five-dollar bill on the sidewalk.\""
            },
            "GLOWER": {
              "word": "GLOWER",
              "phonetic": "(glow'-ÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to scowl, frown \nTo GLOWER is to stare blackly, to look with sullen anger. It is usually followed by <em>at</em>. \n\"The professor GLOWERED at the student who dared to criticize his lecture.\" \n\"The customer GLOWERED at the clerk and demanded his money back.\" \n<em>Beam</em> is the most common wrong answer on the Pretest, probably because of the <em>glow</em> part of GLOWER. GLOWER is not related to the word <em>glow</em>, however. Notice that its pronunciation is different: GLOWER rhymes with <em>shower</em>."
            },
            "GUILE": {
              "word": "GUILE",
              "phonetic": "(gll)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "trickery, treachery, craftiness, duplicity \nGUILE is treacherous cunning, the use of one's cleverness in order to deceive. \n\"He used GUILE and deceit to worm his way into the king's circle of advisors.\" \n\"James is entirely without GUILE. He has never tried to trick or cheat anyone in his life.\" \n<em>Evil</em> is frequently chosen as the synonym for GUILE by people who know that GUILE is a bad quality, but aren't sure of its exact meaning. \nOther forms of the word: GUILEFUL, adj. GUILELESS, adj."
            },
            "OBDURATE": {
              "word": "OBDURATE",
              "phonetic": "(ob'-dyU-rÔøΩt",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "stubborn, inflexible, unyielding, intractable \nOBDURATE comes from the Latin word for <em>hard</em>, also the source for the word <em>durable</em>. Someone who is OBDURATE is hardened against any influence, especially appeals to reform or to be merciful. \n\"We begged the teacher to let us out of class early, but she was OBDURATE.\" \n\"The OBDURATE criminal said he would never give up his life of crime.\" \nOther forms of the word: OBDURACY, n."
            },
            "PARITY": {
              "word": "PARITY",
              "phonetic": "(par'-ÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "equality, equivalence, correspondence \nPARITY comes from a Latin word meaning <em>equal</em>, also the source of the English words <em>par</em> and <em>compare</em>. PARITY means <em>equality</em>. It is usually used in a technical sense about exact equivalence of value or amount, while the word <em>equality</em> often stresses the sense of equal rights. For example, PARITY is the equivalent in value of a sum of money as expressed in a different currency. \n\"The new soccer league's aim was to achieve PARITY with the older league.\" \n\"There was a lack of PARITY in the pay scales at the company: some people were paid a lot less than others for doing exactly the same kind of work.\""
            },
            "PAUCITY": {
              "word": "PAUCITY",
              "phonetic": "(po'-sÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "scarcity, dearth, fewness \nPAUCITY is smallness of number or amount, <em>scarcity</em>, <em>scantiness</em>. \n\"There was a PAUCITY of good actors at the tryout for the school play.\" \n\"The PAUCITY of available funds will make it very difficult for us to complete the project on time.\" \n\"There was no PAUCITY of advice for Joe about how to solve the problem, but finally he had to decide for himself.\""
            },
            "TRANSGRESS": {
              "word": "TRANSGRESS",
              "phonetic": "(trans-gres')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to go beyond a limit; to violate, break \nTRANSGRESS comes from a Latin word meaning <em>go beyond</em> or <em>step across</em>. See <em>trans-</em> under Prefixes. The <em>gress</em> root is also foundin words like <em>progress</em>, <em>regress</em>, and <em>egress</em>. TRANSGRESS is usually used in a figurative sense, of going beyond some legal or moral limit. \n\"He admitted he had TRANSGRESSED the law, and was willing to take his punishment.\" \nThe word is often used without a direct object, in which case it means to <em>sin</em> or <em>trespass</em>. \n\"According to her religion, she TRANSGRESSED whenever she drank coffee or liquor.\" \nThe noun is TRANSGRESSION, which means a <em>violation</em> or <em>breach</em>. \n\"He knew that we would never forgive his countless TRANSGRESSIONS.\n\" TRANSGRESS is occasionally used about physically going beyond a limit or boundary, and this might suggest <em>advance</em> as a synonym on the Pretest. \nOther forms of the word: TRANSGRESSION, n."
            },
            "TRAVAIL": {
              "word": "TRAVAIL",
              "phonetic": "(trÔøΩvAI'",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "toil, labor; suffering, anguish \nTRAVAIL is hard work, especially when accompanied by pain or suffering. It comes from a Latin word for a torture device. \n\"It must have taken years of TRAVAIL to build the pyramids.\" \nSometimes the emphasis is so strongly on the suffering that this becomes more important to the word's meaning than the labor. \n\"He recounted his family's TRAVAILS during the long and dangerous trip across the plains.\" \nThe most popular wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>triumph</em>, possibly because of a confusion of TRAVAIL with <em>prevail</em>."
            },
            "WAN": {
              "word": "WAN",
              "phonetic": "(won)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "sickly, pale, pallid \nWAN means \"lacking color or vitality.\" The word often suggests that this paleness is the result of sickness; these two ideas are of about equal importance to the word's meaning. \n\"After her long illness Sheila looked WAN and haggard.\" \n\"The child gave a WAN smile and said he was feeling a little better.\""
            },
            "COMMISERATE": {
              "word": "COMMISERATE",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩmiz'-ÔøΩrAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to sympathize, condole \nSee <em>com-</em> under Prefixes and <em>-ate1</em> under Suffixes. The <em>miser</em> part of COMMISERATE comes from the same Latin root as <em>misery</em> and <em>miserable</em>. To COMMISERATE with people is literally to feel miserable along with them. The word is applied to a feeling of sympathy or pity, especially when it is spoken or expressed publicly. It is usually followed by <em>with</em>. \n\"The police officer COMMISERATED with us over the loss of our valuables, but said there was nothing he could do.\" \n\"I can't really COMMISERATE with him because I don't know why he's so unhappy.\" \n\"He COMMISERATED with me about my problems, but he could do nothing to help me solve them.\" \nOther forms of the word: COMMISERATION, n."
            },
            "DISCERN": {
              "word": "DISCERN",
              "phonetic": "(di-sÔøΩrn'",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to notice, perceive, detect, distinguish \nDISCERN comes from a Latin word meaning \"to sift apart.\" See <em>dis-</em> under Prefixes. DISCERN can be used about sight, and means to <em>make out</em> or <em>notice</em>, especially something that is far away or hard to see. \n\"We could barely DISCERN the ship's sails in the distance.\" \nDISCERN is also used about the other senses. \n\"I could not DISCERN a great deal of difference between the two recordings of the piece.\" \nAnd it is used about recognizing or distinguishing something mentally. \n\"She DISCERNED that it would be difficult to get ahead in the company without more education.\" \n\"I couldn't DISCERN any sympathy in her attitude.\" \nOther forms of the word: DISCERNIBLE, adj. DISCERNING, adj. DISCERNMENT, n."
            },
            "PONDEROUS": {
              "word": "PONDEROUS",
              "phonetic": "(pon'-dÔøΩrÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "heavy, massive, cumbersome; oppressive, dull \nPONDEROUS comes from a Latin word meaning <em>weight</em>; it is related to the English word <em>pound</em>. The basic meaning of PONDEROUS is \"having great weight,\" <em>heavy</em>. The word especially emphasizes the clumsiness that results from this weight. \n\"The PONDEROUS old dictionary was so heavy the child could barely lift it from the shelf.\" \nIn an extended sense, PONDEROUS is used about anything that is heavy for the mind or spirit; in this sense the word means <em>labored</em>, <em>dull</em>. \n\"The after-dinner speaker gave a long and PONDEROUS talk on the history of the Soviet Union's fiscal policy.\" \nOn the Pretest, many people chose <em>gloomy</em> as the meaning of PONDEROUS, probably through a vague understanding of this extended sense of PONDEROUS."
            },
            "SHIFTLESS": {
              "word": "SHIFTLESS",
              "phonetic": "(shift'-lÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "lazy, idle, lacking ambition \nAn old meaning of the word <em>shift</em> is <em>resourcefulness</em>. This sense can still be seen in the adjective <em>shifty</em>, which means <em>resourceful</em> in a bad sense, <em>tricky</em>, <em>cunning</em>. Someone who is SHIFTLESS lacks resourcefulness. See <em>-less</em> under Suffixes. The word nowadays also emphasizes lack of ambition or energy. \n\"Dave is a SHIFTLESS fellow who will never amount to anything.\" \n\"The bar was filled with SHIFTLESS men who had nothing better to do than drink all day.\" \nThe most common wrong answer is <em>evil</em>, probably chosen by people who know that it is bad to be SHIFTLESS, but aren't quite sure why."
            },
            "AMITY": {
              "word": "AMITY",
              "phonetic": "(am'-ÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "friendship, peaceful relations \nAMITY comes from a Latin word meaning <em>friend</em>, also the source of <em>amiable</em> and <em>amicable</em>. See <em>-y</em> under Suffixes. AMITY is <em>friendship</em>, especially between nations. The word often suggests that two people or groups get along despite at least potential sources of discord. \n\"The settlers and the natives lived together in comparative AMITY for several years.\" \n\"The lack of AMITY among the South American countries provided a constant threat of war in the hemisphere.\" \n\"They appeared to live in AMITY, but deep down they really disliked each other.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to ASCRIBE",
                  "answers": [
                    "propose",
                    "attribute",
                    "consider",
                    "command",
                    "write"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASCRIBE",
                  "correct": "attribute"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AUSPICIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "strange",
                    "unfortunate",
                    "curious",
                    "favorable",
                    "cautious"
                  ],
                  "word": "AUSPICIOUS",
                  "correct": "favorable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to GLOWER",
                  "answers": [
                    "scowl",
                    "groan",
                    "beam",
                    "shrink",
                    "cry"
                  ],
                  "word": "GLOWER",
                  "correct": "scowl"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GUILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "evil",
                    "trickiness",
                    "innocence",
                    "energy",
                    "sorrow"
                  ],
                  "word": "GUILE",
                  "correct": "trickiness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBDURATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "stubborn",
                    "inferior",
                    "powerful",
                    "mistaken",
                    "angry"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBDURATE",
                  "correct": "stubborn"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "precision",
                    "normality",
                    "completeness",
                    "equality",
                    "humor"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARITY",
                  "correct": "equality"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PAUCITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "variety",
                    "truthfulness",
                    "capacity",
                    "abundance",
                    "scarcity"
                  ],
                  "word": "PAUCITY",
                  "correct": "scarcity"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to TRANSGRESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "obey",
                    "violate",
                    "carry",
                    "advance",
                    "disagree"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRANSGRESS",
                  "correct": "violate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRAVAIL",
                  "answers": [
                    "toil",
                    "triumph",
                    "secrecy",
                    "danger",
                    "hostility"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRAVAIL",
                  "correct": "toil"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WAN",
                  "answers": [
                    "secret",
                    "tiny",
                    "sickly",
                    "old",
                    "nice"
                  ],
                  "word": "WAN",
                  "correct": "sickly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to COMMISERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "agree",
                    "discuss",
                    "assist",
                    "suffer",
                    "sympathize"
                  ],
                  "word": "COMMISERATE",
                  "correct": "sympathize"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DISCERN",
                  "answers": [
                    "learn",
                    "notice",
                    "forget",
                    "remove",
                    "expect"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCERN",
                  "correct": "notice"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PONDEROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "stupid",
                    "broad",
                    "dangerous",
                    "heavy",
                    "gloomy"
                  ],
                  "word": "PONDEROUS",
                  "correct": "heavy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SHIFTLESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "lazy",
                    "busy",
                    "silent",
                    "evil",
                    "hungry"
                  ],
                  "word": "SHIFTLESS",
                  "correct": "lazy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "friendship",
                    "hostility",
                    "dullness",
                    "fairness",
                    "cheerfulness"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMITY",
                  "correct": "friendship"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Can filthiness sometimes be ASCRIBED to laziness?",
                  "word": "ASCRIBE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a fumble on the first play be an AUSPICIOUS start for a football team?",
                  "word": "AUSPICIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a friendly person frequently GLOWER?",
                  "word": "GLOWER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people consider GUILE to be offensive?",
                  "word": "GUILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do OBDURATE people change their minds easily?",
                  "word": "OBDURATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an underpaid worker want to achieve PARITY with other workers?",
                  "word": "PARITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a PAUCITY of money make it difficult to pay bills?",
                  "word": "PAUCITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people usually feel guilty about committing a TRANSGRESSION?",
                  "word": "TRANSGRESS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does TRAVAIL cause happiness?",
                  "word": "TRAVAIL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is Santa Claus usually pictured as being WAN?",
                  "word": "WAN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a self-centered person likely to COMMISERATE with others?",
                  "word": "COMMISERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can colors and shapes be DISCERNED?",
                  "word": "DISCERN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a comedy supposed to be PONDEROUS?",
                  "word": "PONDEROUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are business executives generally SHIFTLESS?",
                  "word": "SHIFTLESS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does hatred contribute to AMITY?",
                  "word": "AMITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Bill ASCRIBED them that all was well and that he'd be home soon.",
                  "word": "ASCRIBE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Don't be AUSPICIOUS; the work will get done on time.",
                  "word": "AUSPICIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher GLOWERED at the student who came to class late.",
                  "word": "GLOWER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The Greeks couldn't conquer Troy by force, so they decided to use GUILE.",
                  "word": "GUILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mary Ann OBDURATELY refused to listen to our arguments.",
                  "word": "OBDURATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Johnson claimed there was a lack of PARITY in the agreement: he was giving up much more than he was getting.",
                  "word": "PARITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "There is no PAUCITY that we can go with you on Saturday. We're just too busy.",
                  "word": "PAUCITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The explorers TRANSGRESSED rapidly through the woods.",
                  "word": "TRANSGRESS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The victorious general sent word of his TRAVAIL over the enemy.",
                  "word": "TRAVAIL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The WAN face of the spurned lover showed how much he was suffering.",
                  "word": "WAN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher COMMISERATED her students by giving them so much homework.",
                  "word": "COMMISERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Bill's parents DISCERNED a subtle change in him when he came back from summer camp.",
                  "word": "DISCERN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The book's theme seemed interesting, but the author's treatment of it was rather PONDEROUS.",
                  "word": "PONDEROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "These SHIFTLESS teenagers dropped out of school and just hang around the park all day.",
                  "word": "SHIFTLESS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The AMITY between the two nations was shattered by the dispute over who owned the tiny island.",
                  "word": "AMITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ASCRIBE",
                  "answers": [
                    "assign",
                    "impute",
                    "transfer"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASCRIBE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AUSPICIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "encouraging",
                    "fearful",
                    "favorable"
                  ],
                  "word": "AUSPICIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GLOWER",
                  "answers": [
                    "stare",
                    "blare",
                    "glare"
                  ],
                  "word": "GLOWER",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GUILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "sincerity",
                    "cleverness",
                    "deception"
                  ],
                  "word": "GUILE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBDURATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "unyielding",
                    "unmerciful",
                    "unpopular"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBDURATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "mercy",
                    "fairness",
                    "equivalence"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARITY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PAUCITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "scarcity",
                    "glut",
                    "want"
                  ],
                  "word": "PAUCITY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRANSGRESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "misbehave",
                    "sin",
                    "travel"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRANSGRESS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRAVAIL",
                  "answers": [
                    "ordeal",
                    "suffering",
                    "exercise"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRAVAIL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WAN",
                  "answers": [
                    "pallid",
                    "unhealthy",
                    "feverish"
                  ],
                  "word": "WAN",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COMMISERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "understand",
                    "empathize",
                    "wish"
                  ],
                  "word": "COMMISERATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISCERN",
                  "answers": [
                    "observe",
                    "expect",
                    "detect"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCERN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PONDEROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "massive",
                    "tumultuous",
                    "laborious"
                  ],
                  "word": "PONDEROUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SHIFTLESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "recreational",
                    "lazy",
                    "slothful"
                  ],
                  "word": "SHIFTLESS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "neighborliness",
                    "peace",
                    "distance"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "7.5",
          "definitions": {
            "GERMANE": {
              "word": "GERMANE",
              "phonetic": "(jgr-mAn')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "relevant, pertinent, related \nGERMANE comes from an obsolete English word meaning \n\"having the same parents.\" \nGERMANE means \"closely related\" in a figurative sense, to a subject or an occasion, for example. It is usually followed by <em>to</em>. \"The chairman felt that Jennifer's point was not GERMANE to the discussion.\" \n\"His stories were amusing, but also quite GERMANE to the serious issue about which he was speaking.\" \n\"These speculations are interesting but not GERMANE; they should be deleted from the book.\""
            },
            "GIBE": {
              "word": "GIBE",
              "phonetic": "(jib)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to jeer, taunt, mock, ridicule \nGIBE is also sometimes spelled JIBE. \nTo GIBE is to taunt, to make mocking remarks. The remarks can be good-natured, but more often they are sarcastic, intending to hurt. GIBE is often followed by <em>at</em>. \n\"The other boys GIBED at Peter for walking Cindy home, but secretly they were jealous.\" \n\"The newspapers GIBED the owner of the baseball team for his ridiculous antics.\" \nGIBE is also a noun, meaning \"a taunting remark.\" \n\"Helen paid no attention to the GIBES and insults of her classmates when she started taking lessons on the tuba.\""
            },
            "INIMITABLE": {
              "word": "INIMITABLE",
              "phonetic": "(in-im'-g-tg-bgl)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "matchless, unique \nINIMITABLE is made up of the prefix <em>in-</em>, meaning <em>not</em>, the suffix <em>-able</em>, and the root <em>imit</em>, also found in the word <em>imitate</em>. Something that is INIMITABLE is not able to be imitated, usually because it is so good. \n\"We begged Danny to do his INIMITABLE impression of Frank Sinatra.\" \n\"Bill told the story of his first day at college in his own INIMITABLE style.\" \n\"The INIMITABLE Vincent van Gogh created some of the greatest paintings of the nineteenth century.\""
            },
            "ITINERANT": {
              "word": "ITINERANT",
              "phonetic": "(I-tin'-ÔøΩrnnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "journeying, traveling, nomadic, peripatetic \nITINERANT comes from a Latin word meaning <em>journey</em>, also the source of the word ITINERARY, which is a record or route of a journey. ITINERANT means \"moving from place to place.\" It is especially applied to people whose work entails a great deal of traveling. \n\"The ITINERANT actors would put on a play in any town where they could rent a hall.\" \n\"The ITINERANT preacher gave a sermon in a different church every Sunday.\" \n\"He loved the ITINERANT life; nothing could persuade him to settle down.\""
            },
            "MELLIFLUOUS": {
              "word": "MELLIFLUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(mÔøΩlif'-IU-gs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "sweet-sounding, honeyed, smoothly flowing \nThe <em>melli-</em> part of MELLIFLUOUS comes from the Latin word for <em>honey</em>. The <em>flu</em> part is the Latin root meaning flow, also found in <em>fluent</em>. See <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. MELLIFLUOUS literally means \"flowing with honey.\" Although the word is occasionally used with this literal meaning, it usually has the figurative meaning of \"flowing sweetly or smoothly,\" and is applied to sounds, voices, or the like. \n\"The singer's MELLIFLUOUS voice enchanted the audience.\" \n\"The baby fell asleep to the MELLIFLUOUS sounds of the lullaby.\""
            },
            "PUGNACIOUS": {
              "word": "PUGNACIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(pgg-nA'-shgs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "quarrelsome, belligerent, aggressive, truculent, combative \nPUGNACIOUS comes from a Latin word meaning <em>fight</em>, which in turn comes from a word meaning <em>fist</em>. This word is also the source of <em>pugilism</em>, which is a formal term for boxing. PUGNACIOUS means \"eager to fight,\" and is usually used about a person who is naturally or characteristically given to fighting. \n\"The PUGNACIOUS sailors liked nothing better than to get into a brawl when they went ashore.\" \n\"He was quite PUGNACIOUS when it came to defending the reputation of his school.\" \n\"Sandra's PUGNACIOUS manner made it very difficult for us to work with her.\" \nOther forms of the word: PUGNACITY, n."
            },
            "AFICIONADO": {
              "word": "AFICIONADO",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩfE-sE-ÔøΩna'-dO)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an ardent devotee, enthusiast, zealot \nAFICIONADO comes directly from Spanish and literally means \"one who is affectionate.\" But in English its sense is much stronger than \"affectionate.\" It means \"one who is ardently devoted to or enthusiastic about something.\" \n\"The bullfighting AFICIONADOS cheered the toreador with great fervor.\" \n\"The rare first edition of her poems was prized by collectors and cherished by her AFICIONADOS.\" \n\"My professor insisted that I could never consider myself a true AFICIONADO of Shakespeare until I had made a pilgrimage to Stratford.\" ."
            },
            "CEDE": {
              "word": "CEDE",
              "phonetic": "(sEd)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to give up, grant, relinquish \nTo CEDE something is to relinquish the possession of it, especially in a formal manner, through a treaty or other official act. It is usually used about rights or territory. \n\"Under the terms of the treaty, the United States CEDED the land to Canada.\" \n\"The judge ruled that the company had to CEDE all rights in the invention to its competitor.\""
            },
            "DEBASE": {
              "word": "DEBASE",
              "phonetic": "(di-bAs')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to corrupt, degrade, adulterate, vitiate \nDEBASE is related to the adjective <em>base</em>, meaning <em>low</em> or <em>inferior</em>. To DEBASE something is to lower its value or quality. \n\"The so-called 'modern adaptation' DEBASES Shakespeare's play by omitting all the great poetry.\" \n\"I said I would not DEBASE myself by appearing on the same program with my opponent.\" \nVirtually everyone who takes the Pretest knows that DEBASE means something bad, but many think it means <em>destroy</em> rather than <em>corrupt</em>. DEBASE is not quite that strong. To DEBASE is to lower the quality of, not to destroy. Other forms of the word: DEBASEMENT, n."
            },
            "FOMENT": {
              "word": "FOMENT",
              "phonetic": "(fO-ment')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to stir up, instigate, incite, rouse \nFOMENT is usually used about rebellions and other violent actions. It means to <em>stir up</em>, \"to promote the growth of.\" The word suggests a persistent goading or incitement for a bad purpose. \n\"The mayor said that outside agitators were responsible for FOMENTING the riots in his city.\" \n\"She FOMENTED trouble in the organization by spreading rumors and telling lies.\" \n\"The president accused the Communists of FOMENTING revolution in the South American country.\""
            },
            "FORBEARANCE": {
              "word": "FORBEARANCE",
              "phonetic": "(for-bair'-:ms)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "patience, restraint \nTo FORBEAR from doing something is to refrain from doing it, especially when it is your right. FORBEARANCE is the noun from FORBEAR. People who show FORBEARANCE are patient and restrained; they hold back from exacting punishment, criticizing someone, or demanding their rights. \n\"I thought she showed remarkable FORBEARANCE in putting up with her husband's drinking all these years.\" \n\"The bank's FORBEARANCE finally ended when he fell six months behind in his loan payments.\" \nOther forms of the word: FORBEAR, v."
            },
            "JOCOSE": {
              "word": "JOCOSE",
              "phonetic": "(jO-kOs')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "humorous, playful, merry \nJOCOSE is related to the words <em>joke</em> and <em>jocular</em>; all come from a Latin word meaning <em>jest</em> or <em>joke</em>. JOCOSE means \"characterized by joking,\" <em>humorous</em>, <em>waggish</em>. \n\"Bill is the life of every party; with his JOCOSE disposition, he keeps everybody in stitches.\" \n\"Brenda resented Dan's JOCOSE remarks about her weight, even though he thought he was very funny.\" \n\"When Sue complained that she didn't want to go to school, her father JOCOSELY suggested that she quit and become a trapeze artist.\" \nOther forms of the word: JOCOSITY, n."
            },
            "VEX": {
              "word": "VEX",
              "phonetic": "(veks)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to irritate, annoy, bother; to puzzle, perplex, baffle \nTo VEX is to annoy or irritate, often with small matters, but usually to the point of real frustration or anger. \n\"Joe's wife was so VEXED by his behavior that she refused to speak to him for a week.\" \n\"The employees' constant lateness VEXED the boss.\" \nIn a slightly different sense VEX means <em>baffle</em> or <em>perplex</em>. The word suggests irritation and annoyance in this sense as well. \n\"George was VEXED by the problem of how to make ends meet on his salary.\" \nThe adjective from VEX is VEXATIOUS; it means \"causing someone to be VEXED,\" <em>annoying</em>. \n\"False alarms are not just VEXATIOUS to fire departments, they are hazardous.\" \nOther forms of the word: VEXATION, n. VEXATIOUS, adj."
            },
            "BURGEON": {
              "word": "BURGEON",
              "phonetic": "(ber'-jÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to develop, flourish, sprout \nTo BURGEON is to sprout or grow like a budding flower. BURGEON usually emphasizes new and rapid growth, like that of a flower in springtime. \n\"With the new piano teacher, Alan's talent suddenly started to BURGEON.\" \n\"Over the summer vacation their mild affection for each other BURGEONED into love.\" \n\"The two principals tried to end the BURGEONING rivalry between their schools.\""
            },
            "DISTEND": {
              "word": "DISTEND",
              "phonetic": "(dis-tend')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to swell, expand, bloat \nDISTEND is a combination of the prefix <em>dis-</em>, in this case meaning <em>apart</em>, and <em>tend</em>, from a Latin word meaning to <em>stretch</em>. The <em>tend</em> root is also found in such words as <em>extend</em>, <em>contend</em>, and <em>intend</em>. To DISTEND is to stretch out or swell, especially because of internal pressure. \n\"The balloon gradually DISTENDED as we filled it with water.\" \n\"His stomach was DISTENDED with gas.\" \nThe most common wrong answer is postpone, possibly because the <em>dis</em> and <em>end</em> parts of the word suggest \"not ending,\" and thus putting something off'. \nOther forms of the word: DISTENSION or DISTENTION, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "GERMANE",
                  "answers": [
                    "foreign",
                    "sickening",
                    "relevant",
                    "logical",
                    "crucial"
                  ],
                  "word": "GERMANE",
                  "correct": "relevant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GIBE",
                  "answers": [
                    "compliment",
                    "jeer",
                    "punch",
                    "riddle",
                    "lie"
                  ],
                  "word": "GIBE",
                  "correct": "jeer"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INIMITABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "matchless",
                    "unchanging",
                    "frequent",
                    "threatening",
                    "unbeaten"
                  ],
                  "word": "INIMITABLE",
                  "correct": "matchless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ITINERANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "unpredictable",
                    "occasional",
                    "begging",
                    "selling",
                    "journeying"
                  ],
                  "word": "ITINERANT",
                  "correct": "journeying"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MELLIFLUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "bitter tasting",
                    "soft",
                    "convincing",
                    "grating",
                    "sweet-sounding"
                  ],
                  "word": "MELLIFLUOUS",
                  "correct": "sweet-sounding"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PUGNACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "greedy",
                    "ugly",
                    "quarrelsome",
                    "unhappy",
                    "strong"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUGNACIOUS",
                  "correct": "quarrelsome"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AFICIONADO",
                  "answers": [
                    "enthusiast",
                    "ruler",
                    "criminal",
                    "rancher",
                    "champion"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFICIONADO",
                  "correct": "enthusiast"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to CEDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "examine",
                    "start",
                    "accept",
                    "give up",
                    "turn down"
                  ],
                  "word": "CEDE",
                  "correct": "give up"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DEBASE",
                  "answers": [
                    "destroy",
                    "corrupt",
                    "improve",
                    "move",
                    "forget"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEBASE",
                  "correct": "corrupt"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to FOMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "complete",
                    "stir up",
                    "uncover",
                    "talk about",
                    "advise"
                  ],
                  "word": "FOMENT",
                  "correct": "stir up"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FORBEARANCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "confidence",
                    "faith",
                    "respect",
                    "patience",
                    "excitement"
                  ],
                  "word": "FORBEARANCE",
                  "correct": "patience"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "JOCOSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "sullen",
                    "plump",
                    "humorous",
                    "drunken",
                    "insulting"
                  ],
                  "word": "JOCOSE",
                  "correct": "humorous"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to VEX",
                  "answers": [
                    "trick",
                    "scorn",
                    "confuse",
                    "comfort",
                    "annoy"
                  ],
                  "word": "VEX",
                  "correct": "annoy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to BURGEON",
                  "answers": [
                    "rot",
                    "develop",
                    "shine",
                    "fl.oat",
                    "breathe"
                  ],
                  "word": "BURGEON",
                  "correct": "develop"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DISTEND",
                  "answers": [
                    "swell",
                    "shrink",
                    "warp",
                    "deface",
                    "postpone"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISTEND",
                  "correct": "swell"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would comments about sports be GERMANE during a discussion of the solar system",
                  "word": "GERMANE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can GIBES be annoying?",
                  "word": "GIBE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an actor try to give an INIMITABLE performance?",
                  "word": "INIMITABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are librarians usually ITINERANT?",
                  "word": "ITINERANT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do television announcers usually have MELLIFLUOUS voices?",
                  "word": "MELLIFLUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a PUGNACIOUS person be likely to get into a fight?",
                  "word": "PUGNACIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would opera AFICIONADOS have little interest in music?",
                  "word": "AFICIONADO",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do you lose something when you CEDE it?",
                  "word": "CEDE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people find it unpleasant to be DEBASED?",
                  "word": "DEBASE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": " Did Thomas Paine want to FOMENT a rebellion in the British Colonies in America?",
                  "word": "FOMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a stubborn person be likely to show FORBEARANCE?",
                  "word": "FORBEARANCE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a JOCOSE person be likely to scowl?",
                  "word": "JOCOSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a detective find an unsolved murder case VEXING?",
                  "word": "VEX",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a friendship BURGEON?",
                  "word": "BURGEON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can cheeks DISTEND?",
                  "word": "DISTEND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {}
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Your comments are not GERMANE to the topic at hand.",
                  "word": "GERMANE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Bill thought it was immature to GIBE at someone just for being different.",
                  "word": "GIBE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "When Charlie started showing up for work late, the result was INIMITABLE: he was fired.",
                  "word": "INIMITABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ITINERANT life of the traveling salesman became too much for him as he grew older.",
                  "word": "ITINERANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I could listen to her MELLIFLUOUS voice forever.",
                  "word": "MELLIFLUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Harry was PUGNACIOUS to get as much money as he could before it was too late.",
                  "word": "PUGNACIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He is a true AFICIONADO of wine; there is nothing he doesn't know about the subject.",
                  "word": "AFICIONADO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The judge CEDED the money from them and awarded it to us.",
                  "word": "CEDE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The atomic bomb totally DEBASED the city.",
                  "word": "DEBASE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The warden said a few ringleaders had FOMENTED the riot in the prison.",
                  "word": "FOMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The coach is showing amazing FORBEARANCE; I would have thrown Paul off the team weeks ago.",
                  "word": "FORBEARANCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His JOCOSE comments were out of place at the solemn gathering.",
                  "word": "JOCOSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher was VEXED by the lack of obedience in the classroom.",
                  "word": "VEX",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They BURGEONED in to tell us the exciting news.",
                  "word": "BURGEON",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The more he ate, the more his stomach would DISTEND.",
                  "word": "DISTEND",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "GERMANE",
                  "answers": [
                    "expected",
                    "apropos",
                    "pertinent"
                  ],
                  "word": "GERMANE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GIBE",
                  "answers": [
                    "scoff",
                    "sneer",
                    "smile"
                  ],
                  "word": "GIBE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INIMITABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "illustrious",
                    "banal",
                    "unique"
                  ],
                  "word": "INIMITABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ITINERANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "vagabond",
                    "thief",
                    "nomad"
                  ],
                  "word": "ITINERANT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MELLIFLUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "smooth",
                    "light",
                    "sweet"
                  ],
                  "word": "MELLIFLUOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PUGNACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "opposing",
                    "aggressive",
                    "hostile"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUGNACIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AFICIONADO",
                  "answers": [
                    "agitator",
                    "zealot",
                    "fan"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFICIONADO",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CEDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "lend",
                    "grant",
                    "surrender"
                  ],
                  "word": "CEDE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEBASE",
                  "answers": [
                    "corrupt",
                    "lower",
                    "harm"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEBASE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FOMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "agitate",
                    "incite",
                    "debate"
                  ],
                  "word": "FOMENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FORBEARANCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "long suffering",
                    "unhappiness",
                    "understanding"
                  ],
                  "word": "FORBEARANCE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "JOCOSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "facetious",
                    "amiable",
                    "mellifluous"
                  ],
                  "word": "JOCOSE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VEX",
                  "answers": [
                    "pester",
                    "dismiss",
                    "confuse"
                  ],
                  "word": "VEX",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BURGEON",
                  "answers": [
                    "live",
                    "flower",
                    "grow"
                  ],
                  "word": "BURGEON",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISTEND",
                  "answers": [
                    "extend",
                    "inflate",
                    "disappear"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISTEND",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "7.6",
          "definitions": {
            "INTIMATION": {
              "word": "INTIMATION",
              "phonetic": "(in-ta-mA'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a suggestion, hint \nTo INTIMATE (in'-tQ-mAt) something is to communicate it subtly and indirectly, usually in order to be discreet rather than to be misleading. \n\"Janice INTIMATED that she might be busy that night and that Bill should find another date for the party.\" \nINTIMATION is the noun form of INTIMATE. \n\"There was no INTIMATION of wrongdoing in the report; it merely stated that standard procedures had not been followed.\" \n\"We were all worried by the INTIMATION that John's inquiry was more serious than we had thought.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTIMATE, v."
            },
            "INVIOLATE": {
              "word": "INVIOLATE",
              "phonetic": "(in-vl'-a-lit)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "intact, undisturbed, unprofaned \nOne meaning of <em>violate</em> is to <em>harm</em> or <em>disturb</em>, as in the sentence, \"The presence of the unbeliever <em>violated</em> the sacredness of the temple.\" \nSomething that is INVIOLATE has <em>not</em> been violated in this sense. See <em>in-2</em> under Prefixes. The word is used about people, objects, institutions, and the like that are free from being attacked or profaned. \n\"The enemy bombers destroyed most of the city, but hospitals and churches were left INVIOLATE.\" \n\"The president said he would cut the budget, but that Social Security would be INVIOLATE.\" \n\"This promise must be kept INVIOLATE; if you break it, you will be punished.\" \nThe most common wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>injured</em>, probably chosen because of <em>violate</em>."
            },
            "LUMINARY": {
              "word": "LUMINARY",
              "phonetic": "(IU'-mÔøΩner-E)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a celebrity, notable, leading light \nLUMINARY is derived from a Latin word for <em>light</em>, also the source of <em>luminous</em> and <em>illuminate</em>. A LUMINARY is a celestial body, such as the sun, that gives light. But the word is usually used in a figurative sense of a person who is eminent in his or her field, a \"leading light.\" \n\"All the greatest LUMINARIES of the literary world were at the dinner.\" \n\"The medical society was astonished by the bitter disagreement between the two LUMINARIES of the profession.\" \n\"She was at best a minor LUMINARY in the galaxy of Hollywood stars.\""
            },
            "PANACHE": {
              "word": "PANACHE",
              "phonetic": "(pa-nash'",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "flair, verve, dash, swagger \nThe basic meaning of PANACHE is \"a plume of feathers worn as an ornament on a helmet or cap.\" \nFrom this it has come to be used for style or flair, such as would be demonstrated by wearing a PANACHE. \n\"She did everything with a little bit of PANACHE. She arrived at her college reunion in a hot air balloon.\" \n\"You should dress with more PANACHE. The gray business suits and dark ties you wear are just too dull.\" \n\"The singer is quite talented, but lacks the PANACHE that would make audiences really excited.\""
            },
            "PARRY": {
              "word": "PARRY",
              "phonetic": "(par'-E)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to ward off, deflect, evade \nTo PARRY something-a blow or a thrust with a sword, for example-is to ward it off. \n\"The boxer was unable to PARRY his opponent's barrage of jabs.\" \n\"The fencer easily PARRIED his opponent's feeble thrusts.\" \nPARRY is often used about nonphysical kinds of warding off. \n\"The politician skillfully PARRIED the reporter's probing questions.\" \n\"It is useless to try to PARRY his demands; let's just give in to them.\" \nPARRY is also a noun. \n\"The president was an expert in the thrust and PARRY of these press conferences.\""
            },
            "SURREPTITIOUS": {
              "word": "SURREPTITIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ser-ÔøΩp-tish'-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "secret, clandestine, stealthy, covert \nSURREPTITIOUS means \"done in a secret or underhanded manner,\" usually because the action is felt to be improper. \n\"Because of their SURREPTITIOUS manner, we knew they were up to no good.\" \n\"The shoplifter SURREPTITIOUSLY placed the bracelet into her bag.\" \n\"The conservative professor occasionally indulged his SURREPTITIOUS fondness for disco dancing.\""
            },
            "UPBRAID": {
              "word": "UPBRAID",
              "phonetic": "(uhp-brAd')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to scold, censure, reprove \nUPBRAID comes from an Old English word meaning \"to throw up against,\" and means \"to scold severely, to reprove vehemently.\" The word suggests a formal criticism, usually by a superior or an official. \n\"The teacher UPBRAIDED the students for smoking in the corridor.\" \n\"The policeman UPBRAIDED the motorist for disregarding the safety of others.\" \n\"The boys were UPBRAIDED by the lady when they tossed the empty cans on her lawn.\""
            },
            "DISPARATE": {
              "word": "DISPARATE",
              "phonetic": "(dis'-pÔøΩr-it",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "unlike, dissimilar, distinct, different, diverse \nDISPARATE comes from the Latin verb <em>parare</em>, meaning to <em>prepare</em>, and the prefix <em>dis-</em>, which in this case means <em>apart</em>. DISPARATE now emphasizes the <em>apart</em> rather than the <em>prepare</em> of its derivation, and means \"completely different, markedly dissimilar.\" \n\"The students come from many DISPARATE backgrounds: some rich, some poor, some raised strictly, others given a great deal of freedom.\" \n\"The artist created strange sculptures from such DISPARATE elements as old tires and parts of machines.\" \nThe noun DISPARITY means difference, and is applied particularly to inequality of age or wealth. \n\"If they are truly in love, the DISPARITY between their ages will not matter.\" \nOther forms of the word: DISPARITY, n."
            },
            "PECUNIARY": {
              "word": "PECUNIARY",
              "phonetic": "(pi-kyU'-nE-er-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "monetary, financial \nPECUNIARY comes from the Latin word for <em>money</em>, also the source of the word <em>impecunious</em>, which means \"lacking money.\" PECUNIARY means \"relating to or consisting of money.\" \nIt is usually used with reference to small- scale or practical matters dealing with money. \n\"Alice didn't help us out of friendship but from a PECUNIARY motive-she knew we would pay her.\" \n\"There is psychological satisfaction to be gained from this job, but the PECUNIARY rewards are slight.\" \n\"Mr. Micawber was always optimistic despite his PECUNIARY difficulties.\""
            },
            "PROVISO": {
              "word": "PROVISO",
              "phonetic": "(prÔøΩvl'-zO)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a stipulation, condition, reservation, provision \nA PROVISO is a clause in a contract or other agreement that introduces some sort of qualification or limitation. The word PROVISO comes from the Latin phrase <em>proviso quod</em>, \"provided that,\" with which such clauses began in documents of the Middle Ages. PROVISO can also be used in a general sense to refer to any stipulation or condition. \n\"The contract contained a PROVISO stating that if payments were not made by the end of each month either party could withdraw from the agreement.\" \n\"Mrs. Collins let her son go to the party with the PROVISO that he be back by eleven.\" \n<em>Agreement</em> is a common choice on the Pretest. People who choose it are aware that a PROVISO has something to do with an agreement, but aren't quite sure what."
            },
            "REMISS": {
              "word": "REMISS",
              "phonetic": "(ri-mis')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "careless, inattentive, negligent \nREMISS means \"careless or negligent in attending to one's duty.\" It is often used after the noun it modifies. \n\"Sharon is REMISS about doing her homework.\" \n\"The lawyer was REMISS in not informing his client of her rights.\" \nOccasionally the word is applied to the duty itself and means \"showing negligence.\" \n\"Her reports have been REMISS; she should have shown how she reached her conclusions, instead of just stating them as facts.\""
            },
            "STIGMA": {
              "word": "STIGMA",
              "phonetic": "(stig'-mÔøΩ)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a stain, brand, mark of disgrace \nSTIGMA comes from the Greek word for <em>tattoo</em>. Originally in English a STIGMA was a mark made by a branding iron on the skin of a slave or criminal. From this it came to be used figuratively about any mark of shame or disgrace. \n\"The ex-convict tried to overcome the STIGMA of his criminal record.\" \n\"She felt there was a STIGMA attached to being on welfare, so she refused to apply for it.\" \n\"He thought his rural accent was a STIGMA that marked him as a yokel.\" \nThe verb from STIGMA is STIGMATIZE, which means \"to mark with a STIGMA, to brand as disgraceful.\" \n\"The speaker said he didn't mean to STIGMATIZE all college students as lazy and stupid.\" \nOther forms of the word: STIGMATIZE, v."
            },
            "TRUNCATE": {
              "word": "TRUNCATE",
              "phonetic": "(truhng'-kAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to cut short, lop \nTRUNCATE is related to the word <em>trunk</em>. The <em>trunk</em> is the main part of anything. The <em>trunk</em> of a human body, for example, is the central part of it, excluding the head and the limbs. To TRUNCATE something is to cut it short by lopping off part of it. \n\"The mountain's peak appears to have been TRUNCATED by an ancient volcanic eruption.\" \n\"They had to TRUNCATE their presentation when they ran out of time.\" \n\"The cross-country trip had to be TRUNCATED in Denver because of a lack of funds.\" \n\"Craig's session at the computer terminal was TRUNCATED when the system went down.\""
            },
            "VAPID": {
              "word": "VAPID",
              "phonetic": "(vap'-id)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "lifeless, flat, uninteresting, insipid \nVAPID means \"lacking taste, life, or spirit.\" The word is sometimes used about wine, beer, or other drinks that have become flat and tasteless. It is more often used about people and their intellectual activities. \n\"This movie is utterly VAPID. It doesn't have the slightest bit of intellectual or human interest.\" \n\"The VAPID young man spent all of his time watching game shows on television.\" \n\"She had the same VAPID smile for everything and everyone; clearly she didn't understand a bit of what was going on.\" \n<em>Bubbly</em> is the most popular wrong answer. In one sense this is almost an opposite of VAPID. A person with a bubbly manner may also be VAPID, and this may cause the confusion. \nOther forms of the word: VAPIDITY, n."
            },
            "ABSTEMIOUS": {
              "word": "ABSTEMIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ab-stE'-mE-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "sparing, abstinent \nTo be ABSTEMIOUS is to be moderate and self-restrained, especially in eating and drinking. \n\"The ABSTEMIOUS gentleman never had more than an occasional glass of wine.\" \n\"Far from being ABSTEMIOUS, he indulged to the fullest in every pleasure.\" \nIn a slightly different sense ABSTEMIOUS can mean \"characterized by moderation,\" <em>sparing</em>. \n\"Her ABSTEMIOUS diet consisted of little more than bread and water.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "INTIMATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "friendship",
                    "suggestion",
                    "thought",
                    "threat",
                    "solution"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTIMATION",
                  "correct": "suggestion"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INVIOLATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "intact.",
                    "injured",
                    "kindly",
                    "beautiful",
                    "new"
                  ],
                  "word": "INVIOLATE",
                  "correct": "intact"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LUMINARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "optimist",
                    "student",
                    "priest",
                    "substitute",
                    "celebrity"
                  ],
                  "word": "LUMINARY",
                  "correct": "celebrity"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PANACHE",
                  "answers": [
                    "delight",
                    "jollity",
                    "flair",
                    "care",
                    "despair"
                  ],
                  "word": "PANACHE",
                  "correct": "flair"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to PARRY",
                  "answers": [
                    "give back",
                    "annoy",
                    "imitate",
                    "ward off",
                    "seek out"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARRY",
                  "correct": "ward off"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SURREPTITIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "apparent",
                    "secret",
                    "destructive",
                    "celebrated",
                    "evil"
                  ],
                  "word": "SURREPTITIOUS",
                  "correct": "secret"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to UPBRAID",
                  "answers": [
                    "praise",
                    "teach",
                    "hang",
                    "scold",
                    "correct"
                  ],
                  "word": "UPBRAID",
                  "correct": "scold"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISPARATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "unlike",
                    "identical",
                    "unprepared",
                    "frightening",
                    "far off"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISPARATE",
                  "correct": "unlike"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PECUNIARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "involuntary",
                    "psychological",
                    "monetary",
                    "official",
                    "joyous"
                  ],
                  "word": "PECUNIARY",
                  "correct": "monetary"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROVISO",
                  "answers": [
                    "request",
                    "stipulation",
                    "assistance",
                    "preparation",
                    "agreement"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROVISO",
                  "correct": "stipulation"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REMISS",
                  "answers": [
                    "careless",
                    "crazy",
                    "irritating",
                    "confused",
                    "cowardly"
                  ],
                  "word": "REMISS",
                  "correct": "careless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STIGMA",
                  "answers": [
                    "fame",
                    "rumor",
                    "pain",
                    "stain",
                    "disease"
                  ],
                  "word": "STIGMA",
                  "correct": "stain"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to TRUNCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "extend",
                    "cut short",
                    "twirl",
                    "gather up",
                    "hide"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRUNCATE",
                  "correct": "cut short"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VAPID",
                  "answers": [
                    "lifeless",
                    "bubbly",
                    "muddy",
                    "entertaining",
                    "pretty"
                  ],
                  "word": "VAPID",
                  "correct": "lifeless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABSTEMIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "extravagant",
                    "stern",
                    "sparing",
                    "secret",
                    "healthy"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABSTEMIOUS",
                  "correct": "sparing"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an INTIMATION be blunt?",
                  "word": "INTIMATION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a custom be INVIOLATE?",
                  "word": "INVIOLATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Was Albert Einstein a scientific LUMINARY?",
                  "word": "LUMINARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do some great entertainers have PANACHE?",
                  "word": "PANACHE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Will a PARRY generally wound an opponent?",
                  "word": "PARRY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a spying mission usually be carried out SURREPTITIOUSLY?",
                  "word": "SURREPTITIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are mischievous children likely to be UPBRAIDED?",
                  "word": "UPBRAID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are love and hate DISPARATE emotions?",
                  "word": "DISPARATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a bankrupt business be suffering from PECUNIARY difficulties?",
                  "word": "PECUNIARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do some contracts contain PROVISOS?",
                  "word": "PROVISO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a shiftless teacher be REMISS in his duties?",
                  "word": "REMISS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a person's continual lying become a STIGMA?",
                  "word": "STIGMA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a trip be TRUNCATED?",
                  "word": "TRUNCATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a book be VAPID?",
                  "word": "VAPID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a drunkard ABSTEMIOUS?",
                  "word": "ABSTEMIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The boss INTIMATED that there might be a promotion for Ted if he did a good job.",
                  "word": "INTIMATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The play's director left nothing-not even Hamlet's soliloquies-INVIOLATE.",
                  "word": "INVIOLATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Simpson wasn't a LUMINARY in the business world, but he was respected by those who knew him.",
                  "word": "LUMINARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The students rented a Rolls-Royce so that they would arrive at the prom with PANACHE.",
                  "word": "PANACHE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The boss PARRIED Bill's request for a raise by telling him to work harder.",
                  "word": "PARRY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The police became SURREPTITIOUS of the men driving the truck down the alley.",
                  "word": "SURREPTITIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The boss UPBRAIDED her workers for constantly arriving late.",
                  "word": "UPBRAID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We were DISPARATE to go to the beach that hot day.",
                  "word": "DISPARATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PECUNIARY problems are making it difficult for me to pay my bills.",
                  "word": "PECUNIARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The college admitted Bill with the PROVISO that he take a remedial writing course.",
                  "word": "PROVISO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Bill's mother told him he was REMISS in not giving her the telephone message.",
                  "word": "REMISS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Once the principal had STIGMATIZED them as troublemakers, they had a hard time living down their reputation.",
                  "word": "STIGMA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The director TRUNCATED the play by leaving out the last two scenes.",
                  "word": "TRUNCATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The VAPID girl did nothing but read movie magazines and go to parties.",
                  "word": "VAPID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "John has an ABSTEMIOUS lifestyle: he spends very little on entertainment.",
                  "word": "ABSTEMIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "INTIMATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "whisper",
                    "lie",
                    "suggestion"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTIMATION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INVIOLATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "refined",
                    "venerated",
                    "protected"
                  ],
                  "word": "INVIOLATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LUMINARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "eminent",
                    "notable",
                    "notorious"
                  ],
                  "word": "LUMINARY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PANACHE",
                  "answers": [
                    "expense",
                    "flamboyance",
                    "style"
                  ],
                  "word": "PANACHE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARRY",
                  "answers": [
                    "dodge",
                    "deflect",
                    "stab"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARRY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SURREPTITIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "stubborn",
                    "secretive",
                    "clandestine"
                  ],
                  "word": "SURREPTITIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UPBRAID",
                  "answers": [
                    "admonish",
                    "berate",
                    "convince"
                  ],
                  "word": "UPBRAID",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISPARATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "unnecessary",
                    "divergent",
                    "unequal"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISPARATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PECUNIARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "federal",
                    "fiscal",
                    "financial"
                  ],
                  "word": "PECUNIARY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROVISO",
                  "answers": [
                    "bargain",
                    "condition",
                    "requirement"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROVISO",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REMISS",
                  "answers": [
                    "lax",
                    "wan",
                    "slipshod"
                  ],
                  "word": "REMISS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STIGMA",
                  "answers": [
                    "shame",
                    "disgrace",
                    "ruin"
                  ],
                  "word": "STIGMA",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRUNCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "hide",
                    "abbreviate",
                    "lop"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRUNCATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VAPID",
                  "answers": [
                    "insipid",
                    "vivacious",
                    "banal"
                  ],
                  "word": "VAPID",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABSTEMIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "starving",
                    "abstinent",
                    "sober"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABSTEMIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "AMITY",
            "answer": "amity"
          },
          {
            "word": "INIMITABLE",
            "answer": "inimitable"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBDURATE",
            "answer": "obdurate"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROVISO",
            "answer": "proviso"
          },
          {
            "word": "TRAVAIL",
            "answer": "travail"
          },
          {
            "word": "AUSPICIOUS",
            "answer": "auspicious"
          },
          {
            "word": "INVIOLATE",
            "answer": "inviolate"
          },
          {
            "word": "PARITY",
            "answer": "parity"
          },
          {
            "word": "SHIFTLESS",
            "answer": "shiftless"
          },
          {
            "word": "TRUNCATE",
            "answer": "truncate"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISCERN",
            "answer": "discern"
          },
          {
            "word": "JOCOSE",
            "answer": "jocose"
          },
          {
            "word": "PARRY",
            "answer": "parry"
          },
          {
            "word": "SURREPTITIOUS",
            "answer": "surreptitious"
          },
          {
            "word": "UPBRAID",
            "answer": "upbraided"
          },
          {
            "word": "GIBE"
          },
          {
            "word": "MELLIFLUOUS",
            "answer": "mellifluous"
          },
          {
            "word": "PAUCITY",
            "answer": "paucity"
          },
          {
            "word": "TRANSGRESS",
            "answer": "transgressed"
          },
          {
            "word": "VEX"
          },
          {
            "word": "GUILE",
            "answer": "guile"
          },
          {
            "word": "ABSTEMIOUS",
            "answer": "abstemious"
          },
          {
            "word": "COMMISERATE",
            "answer": "commiserated"
          },
          {
            "word": "FORBEARANCE",
            "answer": "forbearance"
          },
          {
            "word": "LUMINARY",
            "answer": "luminaries"
          },
          {
            "word": "REMISS",
            "answer": "remiss"
          },
          {
            "word": "AFICIONADO",
            "answer": "aficianado"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEBASE",
            "answer": "debase"
          },
          {
            "word": "GERMANE",
            "answer": "germane"
          },
          {
            "word": "PANACHE",
            "answer": "panache"
          },
          {
            "word": "STIGMA",
            "answer": "stigma"
          },
          {
            "word": "ASCRIBE",
            "answer": "ascribe"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISPARATE",
            "answer": "disparate"
          },
          {
            "word": "GLOWER",
            "answer": "glowered"
          },
          {
            "word": "PECUNIARY",
            "answer": "pecuniary"
          },
          {
            "word": "VAPID",
            "answer": "vapid"
          },
          {
            "word": "BURGEON",
            "answer": "burgeon"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISTEND",
            "answer": "distended"
          },
          {
            "word": "INTIMATION",
            "answer": "intimation"
          },
          {
            "word": "PONDEROUS",
            "answer": "ponderous"
          },
          {
            "word": "WAN",
            "answer": "wan"
          },
          {
            "word": "CEDE",
            "answer": "cede"
          },
          {
            "word": "FOMENT",
            "answer": "foment"
          },
          {
            "word": "ITINERANT",
            "answer": "itinerant"
          },
          {
            "word": "PUGNACIOUS",
            "answer": "pugnacious"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "These",
            "part2": "fellows just can't be serious; everything is a joke to them.",
            "correct": "jocose",
            "word": "JOCOSE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "With only two minutes left in the class, the professor was forced to",
            "part2": "his lecture.",
            "correct": "truncate",
            "word": "TRUNCATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mrs. Sims was so",
            "part2": "by her children's constant questioning that she finally shouted at them to be quiet.",
            "correct": "vexed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Despite a few problems, the two nations shared the same border in relative",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "amity",
            "word": "AMITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The custom of having Thanksgiving dinner at our house is",
            "part2": ";nothing has ever made us change it.",
            "correct": "inviolate",
            "word": "INVIOLATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Samuel Johnson's literary style was",
            "part2": ";no one could hope to match its vigor and precision.",
            "correct": "inimitable",
            "word": "INIMITABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The color-blind boy was unable to",
            "part2": "the difference between red and green.",
            "correct": "discern",
            "word": "DISCERN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The company's lawyer inserted a(n)",
            "part2": "in the contract.",
            "correct": "proviso",
            "word": "PROVISO"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The judge",
            "part2": "the lawyers for wasting his time with their trivial objections.",
            "correct": "upbraided",
            "word": "UPBRAID"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mr. Phillips remained",
            "part2": "and said he would never rehire the worker he had fired.",
            "correct": "obdurate",
            "word": "OBDURATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The sweetness of the singer's",
            "part2": "voice charmed us all.",
            "correct": "mellifluous",
            "word": "MELLIFLUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Few of the laborers could endure for very long the",
            "part2": "of dragging the boulders across the hot desert.",
            "correct": "travail",
            "word": "TRAVAIL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There is such a(n)",
            "part2": "of good books in the local library that no one bothers to go there.",
            "correct": "paucity",
            "word": "PAUCITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Sam",
            "part2": "at his friends for having voted for a politician who turned out to be a crook.",
            "correct": "gibed"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Just because I'm unemployed, that doesn't mean I'm (a)n",
            "part2": "good-for-nothing. I'd work hard, if only I could find a job.",
            "correct": "shiftless",
            "word": "SHIFTLESS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It only took us two seasons to achieve",
            "part2": "with the other teams in the league; now we're as good as any of them.",
            "correct": "parity",
            "word": "PARITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The king decreed that all who",
            "part2": "this law should be put to death.",
            "correct": "transgressed",
            "word": "TRANSGRESS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The actor forgot his lines in the first scene of the play; it was hardly a(n)",
            "part2": "beginning.",
            "correct": "auspicious",
            "word": "AUSPICIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Through cunning and",
            "part2": ", he was able to convince everyone that his opponent was unfit for office.",
            "correct": "guile",
            "word": "GUILE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The boxer managed to",
            "part2": "his opponent's blows, but he was unable to land a punch himself.",
            "correct": "parry",
            "word": "PARRY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "No one noticed the prisoner’s",
            "part2": "movements toward the open door.",
            "correct": "surreptitious",
            "word": "SURREPTITIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The newspaper claimed that the police were",
            "part2": "in not investigating the charges more thoroughly.",
            "correct": "remiss",
            "word": "REMISS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The professor's",
            "part2": "lecture was so dull it put most of his students to sleep.",
            "correct": "ponderous",
            "word": "PONDEROUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The radicals planned to",
            "part2": "a rebellion by making fiery speeches and calling for a general strike.",
            "correct": "foment",
            "word": "FOMENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His comments, though interesting, were not",
            "part2": "to the subject under discussion.",
            "correct": "germane",
            "word": "GERMANE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Almost overnight the shy young girl seemed to",
            "part2": "into a self-confident woman.",
            "correct": "burgeon",
            "word": "BURGEON"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Dave's friends",
            "part2": "with him when he failed to get the job.",
            "correct": "commiserated",
            "word": "COMMISERATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "farmhands traveled all across the state, picking up jobs here and there.",
            "correct": "itinerant",
            "word": "ITINERANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The animal's body was so",
            "part2": "that it looked round.",
            "correct": "distended",
            "word": "DISTEND"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "truck driver was ready to fight anyone who got in his way on the road.",
            "correct": "pugnacious",
            "word": "PUGNACIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Pamela's long hours of studying have left her looking quite",
            "part2": ".She needs rest and relaxation.",
            "correct": "wan",
            "word": "WAN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The army took these",
            "part2": "types of men and molded them into an effective fighting force.",
            "correct": "disparate",
            "word": "DISPARATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The judges decided to",
            "part2": "his behavior to ignorance of the rules, not cheating.",
            "correct": "ascribe",
            "word": "ASCRIBE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Cindy refused to",
            "part2": "herself by appearing in the ridiculous costume. She said she had too much dignity.",
            "correct": "debase",
            "word": "DEBASE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We were surprised by John's",
            "part2": "that he might not be working for us much longer.",
            "correct": "intimation",
            "word": "INTIMATION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The salesman refused to discuss the",
            "part2": "aspects of the deal; he said the money would take care of itself.",
            "correct": "pecuniary",
            "word": "PECUNIARY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The judge",
            "part2": "at the noisy spectators and threatened to throw them out of the courtroom.",
            "correct": "glowered",
            "word": "GLOWER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I'm sorry I'm so late in repaying you; your",
            "part2": "is greatly appreciated.",
            "correct": "forbearance",
            "word": "FORBEARANCE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His comments on current affairs were utterly",
            "part2": ";he had nothing new or interesting to say.",
            "correct": "vapid",
            "word": "VAPID"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The country refused to",
            "part2": "any of the territory it had captured in the war.",
            "correct": "cede",
            "word": "CEDE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The comic-book",
            "part2": "has a complete collection of Superman.",
            "correct": "aficianado",
            "word": "AFICIONADO"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Many Hall-of-Famers and other athletic",
            "part2": "were on the physical-fitness panel.",
            "correct": "luminaries",
            "word": "LUMINARY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He tried hard to remove the",
            "part2": "attached to the family name because of his father's crimes.",
            "correct": "stigma",
            "word": "STIGMA"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "man ate and drank only when absolutely necessary.",
            "correct": "abstemious",
            "word": "ABSTEMIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The actor had a certain",
            "part2": "that made even his smallest roles interesting and exciting.",
            "correct": "panache",
            "word": "PANACHE"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "7.7",
          "definitions": {
            "FLACCID": {
              "word": "FLACCID",
              "phonetic": "(flak'-sÔøΩd",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "flabby, limp \nFLACCID means \"soft and limp; not firm.\" It is usually used about physical things such as flesh. \n\"Bill's muscles became FLACCID from lack of exercise.\" \nFLACCID is also used in an extended sense about anything that lacks firmness or vigor. \n\"Under Smith's FLACCID leadership the company lacked drive and direction.\" \nOther forms of the word: FLACCIDITY, n."
            },
            "DAUNT": {
              "word": "DAUNT",
              "phonetic": "(dont)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to discourage, dismay, intimidate \nDAUNT is related to the word <em>dominate</em>. Both come from a Latin word meaning to <em>master</em> or <em>tame</em>. To DAUNT is to dishearten or intimidate by removing the courage a person needs to achieve something. \n\"He was completely DAUNTED by the years of study it would take to become a doctor.\" \n\"Nothing DAUNTED the climbers in their attempt to scale Mount Everest.\" \nThe related words DAUNTLESS and UNDAUNTED are perhaps more common. Both mean \"not discouraged,\" <em>resolute</em>, <em>bold</em>. \"The DAUNTLESS explorers went where no man had ever been before.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer for DAUNT on the Pretest is <em>challenge</em>. DAUNTING involves a challenge, but the emphasis is on the discouragement and dismay that the challenge causes. \nOther forms of the word: DAUNTLESS, adj. UNDAUNTED, adj."
            },
            "MESMERIZE": {
              "word": "MESMERIZE",
              "phonetic": "(mez'-mÔøΩIz",
              "pos": " v.",
              "deftext": "to hypnotize, spellbind, enthrall \nMESMERIZE comes from the name Franz Anton Mesmer, an eighteenth-century Austrian physician who was one of the early practicers of hypnotism. The first meaning of MESMERIZE is literally to <em>hypnotize</em>, but it is more often used in the extended sense of <em>fascinate</em>, to \"have a hypnotic effect upon.\" A person who is MESMERIZED behaves as if hypnotized. \n\"When the actors finished the scene, there was a moment of silence; the audience had been so MESMERIZED that it forgot to clap.\" \n\"When she started to sing, I was MESMERIZED: I couldn't move or speak.\" \nOther forms of the word: MESMERISM, n."
            },
            "PEEVISH": {
              "word": "PEEVISH",
              "phonetic": "(pE'-vish)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "irritable, cross, fretful, querulous \nA person who is PEEVISH is irritable in a childish, petty way, and reacts to minor problems like a spoiled child. \n\"Joe noticed that his father was becoming more PEEVISH: if his dinner was late, he would call the nurse names.\" \n\"When her mother asked her to do the dishes, Betty sighed and PEEVISHLY stomped into the kitchen.\" \n\"The PEEVISH doctor grew angry whenever anything was out of its proper place.\" \nOther forms of the word: PEEVE, v., n."
            },
            "PRODIGY": {
              "word": "PRODIGY",
              "phonetic": "(prod'-ÔøΩjE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a marvel, wonder; a person with exceptional talent \nPRODIGY comes from a Latin word meaning an <em>omen</em> or a <em>portent</em>. In English PRODIGY originally had the same meaning and referred to an extraordinary event or occurrence that might be a prophetic sign. It then came to be used about anything that might cause one to marvel or wonder. \n\"The lecturer spoke about comets, supernovae, and other astronomical PRODIGIES.\" \nThe word is most commonly used today about a person, especially a child, who has extraordinary talent or ability. \n\"Mozart was a musical PRODIGY. He composed his first pieces when he was only four.\" \n\"Billy's parents thought he was a child PRODIGY, but no one else thought he was very talented.\""
            },
            "TENET": {
              "word": "TENET",
              "phonetic": "(ten'-ÔøΩt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a belief, dogma, doctrine \nTENET comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>hold</em>, also the source of the word <em>tenacious</em>. A TENET is a firmly held belief. The word is used especially about principles or doctrines believed by a group of people or an organization. \n\"One of the religion's fundamental TENETS is that the world will end in the year 2075.\" \n\"He approved of the organization's TENETS but not of its actions.\" \n\" 'Equal pay for equal work' was one of the TENETS of the women's group.\""
            },
            "DOLOROUS": {
              "word": "DOLOROUS",
              "phonetic": "(dO'-lÔøΩÔøΩs",
              "pos": "or",
              "deftext": "dol-ÔøΩrÔøΩs) adj.: mournful, sorrowful, melancholy, lugubrious \nDOLOR is a Latin word meaning <em>sorrow</em>, <em>grief</em>. It is also used in English as a poetic or literary synonym for <em>sorrow</em>. The adjective DOLOROUS, meaning <em>sorrowful</em>, <em>melancholy</em>, is more common. See <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. It too has a somewhat literary flavor, and is occasionally used rather humorously for grief that is exaggerated or excessive. \n\"After a few days Hal began to find the DOLOROUS sound of the fog horn to be quite depressing.\" \n\"Her DOLOROUS sobs put everyone in a sad mood.\" \n\"I had to interrupt her DOLOROUS tale of woe to tell her I was late for an appointment.\" \nOther forms of the word: DOLOR, n."
            },
            "FRETFUL": {
              "word": "FRETFUL",
              "phonetic": "(fret'-fÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "irritable, peevish, petulant, querulous \nFRETFUL is difficult apparently because it looks like <em>fearful</em>, leading many people to select <em>frightened</em> as its synonym. The verb to FRET comes from an Old English word meaning to <em>devour</em>. In modern English it can mean to <em>eat into</em> or <em>corrode</em>, but usually it is used in a figurative sense to mean to <em>worry</em>, <em>be troubled</em>. The word usually suggests complaining and irritation, rather than serious worry. \n\"She FRETTED for days until she heard that the package had arrived.\" \nFRETFUL is the adjective from this meaning of FRET. See <em>-ful</em> under Suffixes. \n\"The FRETFUL children complained constantly during the long bus ride.\" \n\"Everyone in the office became FRETFUL and short-tempered when the air-conditioning broke down.\" \nOther forms of the word: FRET, v."
            },
            "PROGENY": {
              "word": "PROGENY",
              "phonetic": "(proj'-ÔøΩnE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "descendants, offspring \nPROGENY may be either singular or plural, but it is usually used as plural. PROGENY are descendants of a mother or father. They may be either immediate offspring or more remote descendants. The word is usually used about humans, but may be applied to plants or animals as well. \n\"Many of Johann Sebastian Bach's PROGENY also became distinguished musicians.\" \n\"Only a few of her PROGENY inherited her rare disease.\" \nPROGENY can also be used in an extended sense, about people or things that are like descendants. \n\"Freud's intellectual PROGENY have dominated psychiatry.\""
            },
            "AMBIENCE": {
              "word": "AMBIENCE",
              "phonetic": "(am'-bE-ÔøΩns)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "environment, milieu \nAMBIENCE is often spelled AMBIANCE. AMBIENCE comes from the French and occasionally keeps its French pronunciation: om-byons'. \nThe latin prefix <em>ambi-</em> means <em>on both sides</em>, <em>around</em>. It is found in the word <em>ambidextrous</em>, which means \"able to use both hands equally well.\" AMBIENCE means \"the surrounding atmosphere,\" the <em>environment</em> or <em>milieu</em>. \n\"Gerald flourished in the challenging intellectual AMBIENCE of the Ivy League school.\" \n\"The decor and the soft lighting create a pleasant, intimate AMBIENCE in the restaurant.\" \n\"The meeting took place in an AMBIENCE of hostility and mutual resentment.\""
            },
            "CATACLYSM": {
              "word": "CATACLYSM",
              "phonetic": "(kat'-ÔøΩ-kliz-ÔøΩm)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a disaster, catastrophe, violent upheaval \nA CATACLYSM is a sudden, violent upheaval. It can be physical, like an earthquake or a flood. \n\"Scientists predicted that a CATACLYSM would devastate the western part of the country.\" \nOr it can be a social or political upheaval, like a revolution. \n\"The CATACLYSM of the French Revolution brought about a change in the social order.\" \n\"He argued that gradual change was preferable to a CATACLYSM that might destroy the good things along with the bad.\" \nOther forms of the word: CATACLYSMIC, adj."
            },
            "DEMISE": {
              "word": "DEMISE",
              "phonetic": "(d;)-mlz')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "death \nDEMISE is a somewhat literary synonym for <em>death</em>. \n\"We were all shocked by her sudden DEMISE; she had never been sick a day in her life.\" \nDEMISE is also used in a figurative sense for the end of anything's existence. \n\"The availability of cheap imports brought about the DEMISE of the shoe industry in New England.\" \n\"The opposition of several key legislators ensured the bill's DEMISE in Congress.\" \nThe most common wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>misfortune</em>, which is close in meaning but certainly not synonymous."
            },
            "HINTERLAND": {
              "word": "HINTERLAND",
              "phonetic": "(hin'-tÔøΩr-land)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "backcountry, remote area, interior region \nHINTERLAND comes from the word <em>land</em> and the German word <em>hinter</em>, which means <em>behind</em>, <em>rear</em>. The HINTERLAND is the land behind a coast that may provide trade goods for a port. In an extended use, HINTERLAND is applied to any sort of remote region, far from a metropolitan area. \n\"When Ellen was tired of the crowded city, she loved to be out in the HINTERLANDS where she wouldn't see a soul for days.\" \n\"It took several months for news of the war to reach the HINTERLANDS.\" \n\"Carl's favorite subject for photography was the lonely, rugged HINTERLAND.\""
            },
            "IMBROGLIO": {
              "word": "IMBROGLIO",
              "phonetic": "(im-brOl'-yO)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a predicament, confused situation, entanglement \nNote the pronunciation. IMBROGLIO is from the Italian, and keeps its Italian pronunciation. An IMBROGLIO is a confused or perplexing state of affairs, particularly one that results in a misunderstanding or a disagreement. \n\"The IMBROGLIO over the diplomat's arrest almost led to a war between the two countries.\" \n\"The billionaire's death caused quite an IMBROGLIO about who would inherit his money.\" \n\"The dispute over who would pay the caterer caused an IMBROGLIO between the two families at the wedding reception.\""
            },
            "MISCREANT": {
              "word": "MISCREANT",
              "phonetic": "(mis'-krE-ÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a villain, scoundrel, evildoer; an infidel, heretic \nMISCREANT originally comes from Latin words meaning \"not believing,\" and was originally used about a person whose religious beliefs were thought to be false, a <em>nonbeliever</em> or <em>heretic</em>. It is still used in this way, but it is used more often with a meaning developed from this original sense: <em>villain</em> or <em>evildoer</em>. \n\"The police chief promised that the MISCREANTS who had vandalized the church would be arrested soon.\" \n\"The man said that Jimmy was a young MISCREANT who should be punished severely.\" \n\"The vicious MISCREANTS lurked in the alley waiting for someone to rob.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "FLACCID",
                  "answers": [
                    "bitter",
                    "peaceful",
                    "flabby",
                    "false",
                    "messy"
                  ],
                  "word": "FLACCID",
                  "correct": "flabby"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DAUNT",
                  "answers": [
                    "hearten",
                    "discourage",
                    "challenge",
                    "insult",
                    "trick"
                  ],
                  "word": "DAUNT",
                  "correct": "discourage"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to MESMERIZE",
                  "answers": [
                    "scandalize",
                    "hypnotize",
                    "bewilder",
                    "enchant",
                    "deceive"
                  ],
                  "word": "MESMERIZE",
                  "correct": "hypnotize"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PEEVISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "hateful",
                    "fearful",
                    "nearsighted",
                    "stingy",
                    "irritable"
                  ],
                  "word": "PEEVISH",
                  "correct": "irritable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRODIGY",
                  "answers": [
                    "waste",
                    "hope",
                    "knowledge",
                    "marvel",
                    "threat"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRODIGY",
                  "correct": "marvel"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TENET",
                  "answers": [
                    "example",
                    "feeling",
                    "belief",
                    "conclusion",
                    "rumor"
                  ],
                  "word": "TENET",
                  "correct": "belief"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DOLOROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "mournful",
                    "soothing",
                    "dull",
                    "cheerful",
                    "glowing"
                  ],
                  "word": "DOLOROUS",
                  "correct": "mournful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FRETFUL",
                  "answers": [
                    "awful",
                    "frightened",
                    "peaceful",
                    "irritable",
                    "proud"
                  ],
                  "word": "FRETFUL",
                  "correct": "irritable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROGENY",
                  "answers": [
                    "relatives",
                    "followers",
                    "talents",
                    "ancestors",
                    "descendants"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROGENY",
                  "correct": "descendants"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMBIENCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "perfume",
                    "environment",
                    "weariness",
                    "horizon",
                    "state of mind"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMBIENCE",
                  "correct": "environment"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CATACLYSM",
                  "answers": [
                    "battle",
                    "jamboree",
                    "cliff",
                    "disaster",
                    "disappointment"
                  ],
                  "word": "CATACLYSM",
                  "correct": "disaster"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEMISE",
                  "answers": [
                    "death",
                    "illness",
                    "birth",
                    "misfortune",
                    "departure"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEMISE",
                  "correct": "death"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HINTERLAND",
                  "answers": [
                    "city",
                    "kingdom",
                    "backcountry",
                    "hilly area",
                    "tropics"
                  ],
                  "word": "HINTERLAND",
                  "correct": "backcountry"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMBROGLIO",
                  "answers": [
                    "celebration",
                    "romance",
                    "defeat",
                    "comedy",
                    "predicament"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMBROGLIO",
                  "correct": "predicament"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MISCREANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "ghost",
                    "beginner",
                    "loser",
                    "evildoer",
                    "moron"
                  ],
                  "word": "MISCREANT",
                  "correct": "evildoer"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a marathon runner have a FLACCID body?",
                  "word": "FLACCID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can the cost of something be DAUNTING?",
                  "word": "DAUNT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a voice MESMERIZE?",
                  "word": "MESMERIZE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would it be difficult to irritate a PEEVISH person?",
                  "word": "PEEVISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a four-hundred-pound pumpkin be called a PRODIGY?",
                  "word": "PRODIGY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a belief in God a TENET of most religions?",
                  "word": "TENET",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can music be DOLOROUS?",
                  "word": "DOLOROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a nonchalant person usually be FRETFUL?",
                  "word": "FRETFUL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are babies PROGENY?",
                  "word": "PROGENY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can the lighting affect the AMBIENCE in a restaurant?",
                  "word": "AMBIENCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Was the Russian Revolution a CATACLYSM?",
                  "word": "CATACLYSM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people feel sad over the DEMISE of a parent?",
                  "word": "DEMISE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are the HINTERLANDS crowded?",
                  "word": "HINTERLAND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an IMBROGLIO likely to lead to an argument?",
                  "word": "IMBROGLIO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a criminal a MISCREANT?",
                  "word": "MISCREANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "They spent a FLACCID day on the beach just swimming and relaxing.",
                  "word": "FLACCID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "John was DAUNTED by the prospect of having to look for a new job.",
                  "word": "DAUNT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher MESMERIZED the material so quickly we couldn't understand it.",
                  "word": "MESMERIZE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The boy complained PEEVISHLY that he never got a chance to play quarterback.",
                  "word": "PEEVISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He lost his PRODIGY when he was quite young, and never entirely regained it.",
                  "word": "PRODIGY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The TENET that all men are created equal is basic in American political thought.",
                  "word": "TENET",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "In a DOLOROUS tone of voice Kathy told us all about her cat's illness.",
                  "word": "DOLOROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The children were so FRETFUL of the movie monster that they had nightmares.",
                  "word": "FRETFUL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "When the rich man died, his numerous PROGENY all claimed part of his estate.",
                  "word": "PROGENY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "John found it impossible to work in the unpleasant AMBIENCE of a noisy and messy office.",
                  "word": "AMBIENCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "These prehistoric CATACLYSMS changed the face of the earth.",
                  "word": "CATACLYSM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The company's DEMISE was attributed to poor planning by management.",
                  "word": "DEMISE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "People in the cities love the politician, but in the HINTERLANDS he is regarded with suspicion.",
                  "word": "HINTERLAND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The IMBROGLIO between the governor and the legislature over the budget finally landed in the courts.",
                  "word": "IMBROGLIO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The principal promptly expelled the MISCREANTS who had attacked the teacher.",
                  "word": "MISCREANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "FLACCID",
                  "answers": [
                    "flimsy",
                    "listless",
                    "hollow"
                  ],
                  "word": "FLACCID",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DAUNT",
                  "answers": [
                    "destroy",
                    "vex",
                    "confound"
                  ],
                  "word": "DAUNT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MESMERIZE",
                  "answers": [
                    "enthrall",
                    "tranquilize",
                    "hypnotize"
                  ],
                  "word": "MESMERIZE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PEEVISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "quarrelsome",
                    "fierce",
                    "petty"
                  ],
                  "word": "PEEVISH",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRODIGY",
                  "answers": [
                    "talent",
                    "fighter",
                    "wonder"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRODIGY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TENET",
                  "answers": [
                    "rumor",
                    "opinion",
                    "principle"
                  ],
                  "word": "TENET",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DOLOROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "sorrowful",
                    "stubborn",
                    "doleful"
                  ],
                  "word": "DOLOROUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FRETFUL",
                  "answers": [
                    "restless",
                    "peevish",
                    "jocose"
                  ],
                  "word": "FRETFUL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROGENY",
                  "answers": [
                    "sons",
                    "cousins",
                    "grandchildren"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROGENY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMBIENCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "milieu",
                    "background",
                    "area"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMBIENCE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CATACLYSM",
                  "answers": [
                    "calamity",
                    "upheaval",
                    "controversy"
                  ],
                  "word": "CATACLYSM",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEMISE",
                  "answers": [
                    "suffering",
                    "extinction",
                    "death"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEMISE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HINTERLAND",
                  "answers": [
                    "city",
                    "interior",
                    "backcountry"
                  ],
                  "word": "HINTERLAND",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMBROGLIO",
                  "answers": [
                    "ambush",
                    "fracas",
                    "altercation"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMBROGLIO",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MISCREANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "nonbeliever",
                    "villain",
                    "inventor"
                  ],
                  "word": "MISCREANT",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "7.8",
          "definitions": {
            "QUAFF": {
              "word": "QUAFF",
              "phonetic": "(kwof)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to drink deeply \nTo QUAFF is to drink deeply and heartily, to drain a cup or glass. \n\"Falstaff QUAFFED the tankard of ale in one long swallow, then called for more.\" \n\"The tired athlete QUAFFED the refreshing drink.\" \n\"I knew you were thirsty, but I didn't expect you to QUAFF the whole pitcher of lemonade.\""
            },
            "CHOLERIC": {
              "word": "CHOLERIC",
              "phonetic": "(kol'-Q-rik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "bad-tempered, irascible \nIn the Middle Ages, anger was thought to be caused by an excess of CHOLER, or yellow bile, in the body. The adjective CHOLERIC (see <em>-ic</em> under Suffixes) is used about people who are easily made angry, who have irritable or touchy dispositions. \n\"As he got older, Mr. Finn became CHOLERIC; he would fly into rages over small matters.\" \n\"Jane's CHOLERIC nature made her difficult to deal with.\" \n\"The CHOLERIC patient became furious with the nurses when they wouldn't cater to his every whim.\" \nOther forms of the word: CHOLER, n."
            },
            "DULCET": {
              "word": "DULCET",
              "phonetic": "(duhl'-sit)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "sweet, melodious \nDULCET comes from an Old French word meaning \"sweet,\" and originally meant \"sweet to the taste\" in English. Over time, however, its meaning changed to \"sweet to the ear,\" <em>melodious</em>. \n\"When the soldier was feverish, only the nurse's DULCET voice could soothe him.\" \n\"The flute, when played well, has a particularly DULCET sound.\""
            },
            "OBSEQUIOUS": {
              "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ob-sE'-kwE-as)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "fawning, servile \nOBSEQUIOUS means \"excessively polite.\" The word usually has a negative connotation and suggests flattery and groveling, although it may only suggest extreme obedience and attentiveness. \n\"The boss didn't like OBSEQUIOUS employees who would constantly open doors for him and compliment his ideas.\" \n\"The service at the restaurant was friendly but not OBSEQUIOUS.\" \n\"The OBSEQUIOUS servants said that nothing would give them more pleasure than to do our bidding.\" \nCrafty is more popular than the correct answer-<em>fawning<em>-on the Pretest, perhaps because OBSEQUIOUS people often seem to be up to something with their insincere flattery; or <em>crafty</em> may be chosen because of confusion with the word <em>devious</em>."
            },
            "REMUNERATE": {
              "word": "REMUNERATE",
              "phonetic": "(ri-myU'-nQ-rAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to pay for, pay to \nREMUNERATE is a somewhat formal synonym for <em>pay</em>. It is especially used about payments for services rendered or losses incurred. \n\"We offered to REMUNERATE them for the time they had spent helping us.\" \n\"If you become my assistant I will REMUNERATE you handsomely.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, REMUNERATE can mean to <em>pay for</em> or to <em>reward</em>. \n\"The boss REMUNERATED our efforts with a large bonus.\" \nREMUNERATION is the act of REMUNERATING, or a payment, a recompense. \"Art was troubled by his inadequate REMUNERATION and demanded more money.\" \nOther forms of the word: REMUNERATION, n."
            },
            "TIMOROUS": {
              "word": "TIMOROUS",
              "phonetic": "(tim'-ÔøΩ-as)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "fearful, timid, apprehensive \nTIMOROUS comes from the Latin word for <em>fear</em>, also the source of the word <em>timid</em>. A person who is TIMOROUS is easily intimidated and is afraid to do things, such as make decisions or be self-assertive. \n\"Paul grew so TIMOROUS once inside the deserted house that he couldn't go forward or leave; he was frozen to the spot with fear.\" \n\"The TIMOROUS clerk couldn't get up the courage to ask his boss for a raise.\" \n\"Susie is so TIMOROUS she is apprehensive about leaving the house.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>quiet</em>. TIMOROUS people are usually quiet, but TIMOROUS means <em>fearful</em>."
            },
            "CHURLISH": {
              "word": "CHURLISH",
              "phonetic": "(cher'-lish)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "rude, boorish, loutish \nA CHURL was originally a man of the lowest class in England. The word then came to refer to a person having the qualities thought to be characteristic of a CHURL: rudeness, surliness, vulgarity. CHURLISH is the adjective from CHURL; see <em>-ish</em> under Suffixes. \n\"The CHURLISH man refused to let the boys cut through his yard.\" \n\"The CHURLISH waitress demanded to know if we hade made up our minds yet.\" \n\"The bus driver CHURLISHLY told the children to shut up or get out and walk.\" \nOther forms of the word: CHURL, n."
            },
            "DILATE": {
              "word": "DILATE",
              "phonetic": "(dl-lAt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to widen, expand \nThe <em>late</em> part of DILATE comes from a Latin word meaning <em>wide</em>, also found in the English word <em>latitude</em>. See <em>di-</em> under Prefixes. To DILATE is to become wider, to expand. The word is generally used about physical objects. \n\"The ophthalmologist put some drops in her eyes to make the pupils DILATE.\" \nThe word is sometimes used about opinions or subject matter, with the meaning \"to speak at length.\" In this sense DILATE is usually followed by <em>on</em> or <em>upon</em>. \"The senator DILATED upon his views on fiscal policy.\" \nOther forms of the word: DILATION, n. DILATATION, n."
            },
            "HIATUS": {
              "word": "HIATUS",
              "phonetic": "(hl-A'-t::is)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a gap, interruption, break \nA HIATUS is a gap or interval, generally of time or continuity. \n\"The celebrated actress returned to the stage after a HIATUS of twelve years.\" \n\"During the brief HIATUS between appointments, the doctor was able to rest for a few minutes.\" \n\"Students used the HIATUS between the end of classes and the beginning of exams to catch up on their reading.\""
            },
            "LASSITUDE": {
              "word": "LASSITUDE",
              "phonetic": "(las'-ÔøΩtUd)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "weariness, lethargy, languor, listlessness \nLASSITUDE is a state of weariness and inactivity, a lack of energy resulting from strain, overwork, a hot climate, or the like. \n\"Angela couldn't seem to overcome her LASSITUDE; all she wanted to do was lie in bed.\" \n\"After the long baseball season the player gave way to a strong feeling of LASSITUDE.\" \n\"The muggy, tropical climate induced an overpowering LASSITUDE that made it difficult to work.\""
            },
            "PETULANT": {
              "word": "PETULANT",
              "phonetic": "(pech'-U-1::int)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "irritable, peevish, ill-tempered \nPETULANT means peevish, \"easily upset or angered,\" like a spoiled child who doesn't get his or her own way. \n\"The PETULANT actress became angry every time the director made a suggestion.\" \n\"Bob complained PETULANTLY that everyone else always got dessert before he did.\" \n\"Rich knew from her PETULANT refusal to greet him that she was angry with him again.\" \nOther forms of the word: PETULANCE, n."
            },
            "REVERIE": {
              "word": "REVERIE",
              "phonetic": "(rev'-::ir-E)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a daydream, fanciful musing \nREVERIE is sometimes spelled REVERY. \nA REVERIE is a daydream, a series of idle thoughts or images. \n\"Sharon was lost in a REVERIE, thinking about things that happened long ago.\" \n\"Jim's REVERIE lasted for an hour before he realized that he bad to go to work.\" \nIt is also the act of daydreaming. \n\"The old man spent his days sitting by the lake in quiet REVERIE.\" \n<em>Prayer</em> is a popular choice as the meaning of REVERIE, perhaps because both involve a kind of quiet thought, perhaps because of confusion with the word <em>revere</em>, which means to <em>worship</em>."
            },
            "SAGACIOUS": {
              "word": "SAGACIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(sÔøΩgA'-shÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "shrewd, astute, judicious, wise \nA SAGACIOUS person possesses good judgment, keen penetration, and farsightedness, usually obtained through wide experience. \n\"The SAGACIOUS lawyer said that these matters took time, but that we should win in the end.\" \n\"Through her SAGACIOUS investments in computer stocks she managed to become quite wealthy.\" \nThe noun related to SAGACIOUS is SAGACITY. \n\"Thanks to the SAGACITY of its president, this company has grown steadily over the years.\" \nOther forms of the word: SAGACITY, n."
            },
            "DIRE": {
              "word": "DIRE",
              "phonetic": "(dlr)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "fearful, calamitous, disastrous; extreme, urgent \nSomething that is DIRE causes great fear, either because it is disastrous now, or threatens disaster in the future. \n\"The general warned of DIRE consequences if the country didn't spend more money on defense.\" \n\"The loss of the star center was a DIRE blow to the basketball team.\" \nOften the word places less emphasis on fear and more on urgency or desperation. \n\"Only in a DIRE emergency would a pupil be allowed to leave school early.\" \n\"He was forced to steal out of DIRE necessity; otherwise he would have starved.\""
            },
            "EBULLIENCE": {
              "word": "EBULLIENCE",
              "phonetic": "(i-bul'-yÔøΩns)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "enthusiasm, exuberance, high spirits \nSee <em>ex-</em> under Prefixes. The <em>bull</em> part of EBULLIENCE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>boil</em>. EBULLIENCE is a \"boiling out\" of enthusiasm or exuberance. It suggests an overflowing of feelings or high spirits. \n\"With his usual EBULLIENCE, the professor talked for an hour about how great and wise Socrates had been.\" \nThe adjective from EBULLIENCE is EBULLIENT. \n\"After the victory, the EBULLIENT coach said that this was the finest team he had ever been associated with.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>brilliance</em>, perhaps because of the similarity in sound, and because both are positive qualities for a person to have. \nOther forms of the word: EBULLIENT, adj."
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to QUAFF",
                  "answers": [
                    "eat",
                    "laugh",
                    "drink",
                    "scratch",
                    "cough"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUAFF",
                  "correct": "drink"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CHOLERIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "bad tempered",
                    "dying",
                    "passive",
                    "energetic",
                    "underfed"
                  ],
                  "word": "CHOLERIC",
                  "correct": "bad tempered"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DULCET",
                  "answers": [
                    "boring",
                    "sweet",
                    "harsh",
                    "bland",
                    "smooth"
                  ],
                  "word": "DULCET",
                  "correct": "sweet"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBSEQUIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "stem",
                    "helpful",
                    "crafty",
                    "fawning",
                    "reverent"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
                  "correct": "fawning"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to REMUNERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "pay",
                    "promote",
                    "fine",
                    "award",
                    "recount"
                  ],
                  "word": "REMUNERATE",
                  "correct": "pay"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TIMOROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "nasty",
                    "quiet",
                    "loving",
                    "tiny",
                    "fearful"
                  ],
                  "word": "TIMOROUS",
                  "correct": "fearful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CHURLISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "helpful",
                    "rude",
                    "silly",
                    "greedy",
                    "ugly"
                  ],
                  "word": "CHURLISH",
                  "correct": "rude"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DILATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "waver",
                    "decline",
                    "expand",
                    "harden",
                    "contract"
                  ],
                  "word": "DILATE",
                  "correct": "expand"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HIATUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "problem",
                    "shelter",
                    "gap",
                    "rumor",
                    "extension"
                  ],
                  "word": "HIATUS",
                  "correct": "gap"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LASSITUDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "poverty",
                    "desire",
                    "happiness",
                    "greed",
                    "weariness"
                  ],
                  "word": "LASSITUDE",
                  "correct": "weariness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PETULANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "quick",
                    "friendly",
                    "popular",
                    "irritable",
                    "cunning"
                  ],
                  "word": "PETULANT",
                  "correct": "irritable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REVERIE",
                  "answers": [
                    "daydream",
                    "prayer",
                    "conversation",
                    "task",
                    "judgment"
                  ],
                  "word": "REVERIE",
                  "correct": "daydream"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SAGACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "absurd",
                    "shrewd",
                    "obscure",
                    "courteous",
                    "renowned"
                  ],
                  "word": "SAGACIOUS",
                  "correct": "shrewd"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIRE",
                  "answers": [
                    "hideous",
                    "uncertain",
                    "complex",
                    "complete",
                    "fearful"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIRE",
                  "correct": "fearful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EBULLIENCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "brilliance",
                    "enthusiasm",
                    "unhappiness",
                    "fatness",
                    "humor"
                  ],
                  "word": "EBULLIENCE",
                  "correct": "enthusiasm"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you QUAFF food?",
                  "word": "QUAFF",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would it be fun to live with a CHOLERIC person?",
                  "word": "CHOLERIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can DULCET sounds be soothing?",
                  "word": "DULCET",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an argumentative person be OBSEQUIOUS?",
                  "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would workers be angry if they received no REMUNERATION?",
                  "word": "REMUNERATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are boxing champions usually TIMOROUS?",
                  "word": "TIMOROUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do CHURLS tend to be pleasant?",
                  "word": "CHURLISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can your stomach DILATE?",
                  "word": "DILATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a HIATUS last for a long time?",
                  "word": "HIATUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a boring job cause LASSITUDE?",
                  "word": "LASSITUDE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it easy to get along with a PETULANT person?",
                  "word": "PETULANT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a REVERIE loud?",
                  "word": "REVERIE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a SAGACIOUS person be likely to go bankrupt?",
                  "word": "SAGACIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an earthquake in a populated area a DIRE event?",
                  "word": "DIRE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would learning about a tragedy cause EBULLIENCE?",
                  "word": "EBULLIENCE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "We didn't mean to be greedy, but the punch was so good we QUAFFED glass after glass of it.",
                  "word": "QUAFF",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The doctor said the infant was CHOLERIC and had to be brought to the hospital immediately.",
                  "word": "CHOLERIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The DULCET sounds of a jackhammer kept him from getting any sleep.",
                  "word": "DULCET",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The OBSEQUIOUS doorman took off his hat and bowed to us as we went in.",
                  "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jennifer REMUNERATED us that the party was Sunday night.",
                  "word": "REMUNERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The TIMOROUS man always let other people get ahead of him in supermarket lines.",
                  "word": "TIMOROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The CHURLISH ballplayer snarled at the boys asking for his autograph.",
                  "word": "CHURLISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The traffic jam DILATED John for his appointment.",
                  "word": "DILATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The president-elect chose his cabinet during the three-month HIATUS between winning the election and taking office.",
                  "word": "HIATUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They gave us extraordinary LASSITUDE, but we were still able to complete the job.",
                  "word": "LASSITUDE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I'm not PETULANT; I just have high standards, and I get angry when people don't meet them.",
                  "word": "PETULANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "In solemn REVERIE he begged God to forgive his sins.",
                  "word": "REVERIE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If it hadn't been for your SAGACIOUS advice we would have made some very foolish mistakes.",
                  "word": "SAGACIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The book's DIRE forecasts of coming wars and famines were very depressing.",
                  "word": "DIRE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Nothing could dampen their EBULLIENCE when the principal let them out of school early.",
                  "word": "EBULLIENCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "QUAFF",
                  "answers": [
                    "drink",
                    "dine",
                    "gulp"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUAFF",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CHOLERIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "pugnacious",
                    "frightened",
                    "peevish"
                  ],
                  "word": "CHOLERIC",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DULCET",
                  "answers": [
                    "harsh",
                    "tuneful",
                    "melodious"
                  ],
                  "word": "DULCET",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBSEQUIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "slavish",
                    "secretive",
                    "subservient"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REMUNERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "recompense",
                    "rectify",
                    "reimburse"
                  ],
                  "word": "REMUNERATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TIMOROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "frightened",
                    "vexing",
                    "daunted"
                  ],
                  "word": "TIMOROUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CHURLISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "brusque",
                    "dour",
                    "suspicious"
                  ],
                  "word": "CHURLISH",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DILATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "expand",
                    "widen",
                    "shorten"
                  ],
                  "word": "DILATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HIATUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "interval",
                    "conclusion",
                    "intermission"
                  ],
                  "word": "HIATUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LASSITUDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "depression",
                    "tiredness",
                    "listlessness"
                  ],
                  "word": "LASSITUDE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PETULANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "irritable",
                    "sad",
                    "peevish"
                  ],
                  "word": "PETULANT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REVERIE",
                  "answers": [
                    "thinking",
                    "planning",
                    "dreaming"
                  ],
                  "word": "REVERIE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SAGACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "holy",
                    "shrewd",
                    "wise"
                  ],
                  "word": "SAGACIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIRE",
                  "answers": [
                    "favorable",
                    "ominous",
                    "painful"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIRE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EBULLIENCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "exuberance",
                    "contentment",
                    "happiness"
                  ],
                  "word": "EBULLIENCE",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "7.9",
          "definitions": {
            "HAPLESS": {
              "word": "HAPLESS",
              "phonetic": "(hap'-lÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "unlucky, unfortunate \nThe <em>hap</em> part of HAPLESS comes from an archaic word related to the word <em>happen</em>. <em>Hap</em> once meant <em>chance</em> or <em>fortune</em>. Someone who is HAPLESS does not have good fortune; he is completely unlucky. \n\"The HAPLESS woman broke her leg on the way home from the hospital.\" \n\"The HAPLESS basketball team never seemed to get a break from the referees during its losing streak.\" \n<em>Useless</em> is the most common wrong answer on the Pretest, perhaps because HAPLESS looks like <em>helpless</em> or <em>hopeless</em>."
            },
            "INCULCATE": {
              "word": "INCULCATE",
              "phonetic": "(in-kÔøΩl'-kAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to instill, implant, teach earnestly \nINCULCATE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>trample in</em>. To INCULCATE something is to teach it or impress it upon someone by persistent repetitions, so that it becomes deeply implanted in his mind. The word is usually used with <em>in</em> or <em>into</em>. \n\"It proved to be impossible to INCULCATE any sense of discipline into those boys.\" \n\"The teacher tried to INCULCATE a love of language in her students.\" \n\"From her earliest years, Deborah had been INCULCATED with a stern code of ethics.\""
            },
            "INFINITESIMAL": {
              "word": "INFINITESIMAL",
              "phonetic": "(in-fin-ÔøΩtes'-ÔøΩmÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "tiny, minute, immeasurably small \nINFINITESIMAL is related to the word <em>infinite</em>. The words, however, are almost completely opposite in meaning. <em>Infinite</em> means <em>endless</em>, \"having no limits.\" INFINITESIMAL means \"extremely minute, immeasurably small.\" \n\"These INFINITESIMAL subatomic particles can be detected only by the most powerful electron microscopes.\" \nThe confusion between <em>infinite</em> and INFINITESIMAL illustrates the difficulty of figuring out a word's meaning by breaking it down into its parts, without seeing it in context. The person who is familiar with the contexts in which INFINITESIMAL is used would not be likely to think it means <em>endless</em>."
            },
            "NOXIOUS": {
              "word": "NOXIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(nok'-shÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "harmful,injurious, destructive, deleterious, detrimental \nNOXIOUS and <em>obnoxious</em> both come from a Latin word meaning <em>harm</em> or <em>damage</em>. <em>Obnoxious</em> now simply means <em>offensive</em>, <em>disagreeable</em>. NOXIOUS is a stronger word, and keeps the original sense of actual harm. Something that is NOXIOUS is harmful to the body or the mind, to health or morals. \n\"The NOXIOUS fumes of the chemical plant sent twenty people to the hospital.\" \n\"Several studies have documented the NOXIOUS effects on children of watching too much television.\" \n\"These NOXIOUS ideas have no place in our educational system.\""
            },
            "PARSIMONIOUS": {
              "word": "PARSIMONIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(pahr-sÔøΩmO'-nE-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "stingy, niggardly \nPARSIMONY is excessive thrift, extreme frugality. PARSIMONIOUS is the adjective from PARSIMONY; see <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. PARSIMONIOUS and <em>stingy</em> are quite close in meaning, but there is a slight difference. <em>Stingy</em> suggests a mean-spirited unwillingness to share what one has. PARSIMONIOUS is not usually quite so negative; it would be used more of a person who carries the virtue of thrift or economy to extremes. \n\"The rich man was so PARSIMONIOUS that he picked through other people's trash looking for clothing he might wear.\" \n\"They accused Jill of being PARSIMONIOUS when she wouldn't buy a ticket to the concert, but she said thirty dollars was far too much to spend.\" \n<em>Generous</em>, an opposite of PARSIMONIOUS, is the most common wrong answer on the Pretest item. \nOther forms of the word: PARSIMONY, n."
            },
            "POTABLE": {
              "word": "POTABLE",
              "phonetic": "(pOt'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "drinkable, fit to drink \nPOTABLE means \"fit to drink,\" <em>drinkable</em>. It is sometimes used as a noun and applied to beverages; they are referred to as POTABLES. \n\"The army scout knew that the water in the algae-covered pond was not POTABLE.\" \n\"My mother makes coffee so thick and bitter it is hardly POTABLE.\""
            },
            "VOCIFEROUS": {
              "word": "VOCIFEROUS",
              "phonetic": "(vO-sif'-ÔøΩr-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "clamorous, boisterous, strident \nThe <em>voe</em> part of VOCIFEROUS comes from the Latin word for <em>voice</em>, also the source of <em>vocal</em> and <em>advocate</em>. VOCIFEROUS people are always ready to use their voices, particularly to demand or object. \n\"The VOCIFEROUS fans at the boxing match let the fighters know they were displeased with the action.\" \n\"One VOCIFEROUS parent objected strongly to everything the principal said.\" \n\"Bowing to the children's VOCIFEROUS entreaties, their parents let them stay up to watch the special TV program.\""
            },
            "ABJECT": {
              "word": "ABJECT",
              "phonetic": "(ab'-jekt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "wretched, humiliating; contemptible, despicable \nABJECT means \"extremely low in position, degree, or worth.\" Sometimes it has the sense of <em>wretched</em>, <em>hopeless</em>. \n\"They lived in ABJECT poverty, without a cent to their name.\" \n\"The ABJECT squalor of the apartment sickened us.\" \nThe word often has a negative or disparaging sense and means <em>contemptible</em>. \n\"The general's ABJECT cowardice was disgraceful.\""
            },
            "BLITHE": {
              "word": "BLITHE",
              "phonetic": "(bllth)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "joyful, glad, cheerful; carefree, casual, heedless \nBLITHE means <em>joyful</em>, <em>merry</em>, <em>gay</em>. It suggests a lighthearted, carefree kind of joy, like that of a child. \n\"Nothing could upset the BLITHE young couple during the first months of their marriage.\" \n\"The BLITHE days of summer vacation were over, and now they had to face school once again.\" \nBLITHE often puts the strongest emphasis on the carefree, heedless quality of this happiness, with the suggestion that this casualness may have bad consequences. \n\"The driver BLITHELY ignored their warning about the slippery roads.\" \n\"Her BLITHE refusal to worry about grades finally caused her to fail three courses.\""
            },
            "CATARACT": {
              "word": "CATARACT",
              "phonetic": "(kat'-ÔøΩakt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a large waterfall, downpour, deluge \nA CATARACT is a large waterfall or steep rapids. \n\"The canoeists came dangerously close to the CATARACT before they managed to reach shore.\" \nCATARACT can also be used in an extended sense about any large downpour. \n\"CATARACTS of rain poured off the roof of our house during the storm.\""
            },
            "OBFUSCATE": {
              "word": "OBFUSCATE",
              "phonetic": "(ob'-fuhs-kAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to darken, make indistinct; to confuse, bewilder, make obscure \nOBFUSCATE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>darken</em>. The word can be used about actual physical darkness. \n\"The fog OBFUSCATED the land.\" \nBut it is generally used in a figurative sense, about intellectual darkness. \n\"If that journalist would write more clearly he would not OBFUSCATE his readers.'' \nTo OBFUSCATE something is to make it obscure, muddled, hard to understand. \n\"The court's contradictory rulings have served only to OBFUSCATE the new law.\" \n\"The inept writer managed to further OBFUSCATE an already unclear subject.\" \nOther forms of the word: OBFUSCATION, n. OBFUSCATORY, adj."
            },
            "OBSTREPEROUS": {
              "word": "OBSTREPEROUS",
              "phonetic": "(ob-strep'-ÔøΩ-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "noisy, tumultuous, unruly, boisterous \nOBSTREPEROUS is used about people who are noisily unruly, who are loud, aggressive, and difficult to control. \n\"The OBSTREPEROUS students were always causing a commotion in the classroom.\" \n\"Whenever people disagree with Bill he becomes OBSTREPEROUS.'' \n\"The judge ordered the OBSTREPEROUS spectators removed from the courtroom.\""
            },
            "OSSIFY": {
              "word": "OSSIFY",
              "phonetic": "(os'-a-fl)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to change into bone, harden \nOSSIFY comes from the Latin word for <em>bone</em>. See <em>-fy</em> under Suffixes. OSSIFY means \"to change or form into bone.\" In an extended sense, the word means \"to mold or become set in a conventional pattern,\" to <em>harden</em> or <em>become rigid</em>. \n\"The elderly man rejected the notion that people's minds tend to OSSIFY as they get older.\" \n\"The passage of time had OSSIFIED both parties in their positions, so that compromise seemed unlikely.\" \n\"The organization's practices were so OSSIFIED that it was unable to adapt to change.\" \nOther forms of the word: OSSIFICATION, n."
            },
            "PORTEND": {
              "word": "PORTEND",
              "phonetic": "(por-tend')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to forebode, foreshadow \nTo PORTEND is to forbode or presage. PORTEND is usually applied to a coming evil or disaster. See PORTENT in Chapter 2. \n\"Geese flying south in October PORTEND an early and hard winter.\" \n\"Madame Zelda said the signs in the tea leaves PORTENDED misfortunes for the lady.\" \n\"The critic's bored sighs PORTEND a bad review.\" \nOther forms of the word: PORTENT, n. PORTENTOUS, adj."
            },
            "PROTRACT": {
              "word": "PROTRACT",
              "phonetic": "(prO-trakt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to prolong, drag out \nTo PROTRACT means \"to lengthen in duration,\" <em>prolong</em>. The word often implies that the prolonging is unnecessary or boring. \n\"They PROTRACTED the conference with an endless series of unnecessary speeches.\" \n\"The discussion between the two businessmen became so PROTRACTED that the other people at the meeting started to fall asleep.\" \n\"Stevens was so bored at work that he wrote a PROTRACTED memo on the virtues of unlined paper: it came to fifteen pages.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "HAPLESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "unhappy",
                    "useless",
                    "unlucky",
                    "vicious",
                    "stupid"
                  ],
                  "word": "HAPLESS",
                  "correct": "unlucky"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to INCULCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "learn",
                    "demand",
                    "suggest",
                    "instill",
                    "lead to"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCULCATE",
                  "correct": "instill"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INFINITESIMAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "endless",
                    "tiny",
                    "essential",
                    "incredible",
                    "light"
                  ],
                  "word": "INFINITESIMAL",
                  "correct": "tiny"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NOXIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "explosive",
                    "dirty",
                    "powerful",
                    "sharp",
                    "harmful"
                  ],
                  "word": "NOXIOUS",
                  "correct": "harmful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARSIMONIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "formal",
                    "generous",
                    "stingy",
                    "sickly",
                    "tricky"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARSIMONIOUS",
                  "correct": "stingy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "POTABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "drinkable",
                    "edible",
                    "poisonous",
                    "valuable",
                    "powerful"
                  ],
                  "word": "POTABLE",
                  "correct": "drinkable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VOCIFEROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "clamorous",
                    "impolite",
                    "vain",
                    "humorous",
                    "threatening"
                  ],
                  "word": "VOCIFEROUS",
                  "correct": "clamorous"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABJECT",
                  "answers": [
                    "real",
                    "impossible",
                    "frightened",
                    "wretched",
                    "drunken"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABJECT",
                  "correct": "wretched"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BLITHE",
                  "answers": [
                    "serious",
                    "weak",
                    "joyful",
                    "silly",
                    "lovely"
                  ],
                  "word": "BLITHE",
                  "correct": "joyful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CATARACT",
                  "answers": [
                    "explosion",
                    "cliff",
                    "canyon",
                    "river",
                    "waterfall"
                  ],
                  "word": "CATARACT",
                  "correct": "waterfall"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to OBFUSCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "obscure",
                    "clarify",
                    "annoy",
                    "defeat",
                    "defile"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBFUSCATE",
                  "correct": "obscure"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBSTREPEROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "obedient",
                    "precocious",
                    "determined",
                    "unruly",
                    "mean"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBSTREPEROUS",
                  "correct": "unruly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to OSSIFY",
                  "answers": [
                    "darken",
                    "rot",
                    "harden",
                    "soften",
                    "waver"
                  ],
                  "word": "OSSIFY",
                  "correct": "harden"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to PORTEND",
                  "answers": [
                    "resemble",
                    "forebode",
                    "cause",
                    "expect",
                    "recall"
                  ],
                  "word": "PORTEND",
                  "correct": "forebode"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to PROTRACT",
                  "answers": [
                    "prolong",
                    "produce",
                    "propose",
                    "plan",
                    "cancel"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROTRACT",
                  "correct": "prolong"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a HAPLESS person have bad luck?",
                  "word": "HAPLESS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you INCULCATE something by repetition?",
                  "word": "INCULCATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are galaxies INFINITESIMAL?",
                  "word": "INFINITESIMAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can chemical fumes be NOXIOUS?",
                  "word": "NOXIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do PARSIMONIOUS people usually give expensive presents?",
                  "word": "PARSIMONIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is sulfuric acid POTABLE?",
                  "word": "POTABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are shy people usually VOCIFEROUS?",
                  "word": "VOCIFEROUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Might a very poor person live in ABJECT poverty?",
                  "word": "ABJECT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a BLITHE person tend to worry a lot?",
                  "word": "BLITHE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could Niagara Falls be called a CATARACT?",
                  "word": "CATARACT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should politicians OBFUSCATE issues?",
                  "word": "OBFUSCATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are OBSTREPEROUS people easily controlled?",
                  "word": "OBSTREPEROUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it easy to change something that has OSSIFIED?",
                  "word": "OSSIFY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do black clouds PORTEND a storm?",
                  "word": "PORTEND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would people want to cut short a PROTRACTED discussion?",
                  "word": "PROTRACT",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Nothing went right for the HAPLESS settlers that first year.",
                  "word": "HAPLESS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The stranger INCULCATED us the way to the fairgrounds.",
                  "word": "INCULCATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The human body needs only INFINITESIMAL amounts of some minerals.",
                  "word": "INFINITESIMAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The government determined that the food additive was NOXIOUS.",
                  "word": "NOXIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Fred PARSIMONIOUSLY agreed to help us on our research project.",
                  "word": "PARSIMONIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The Smiths were in charge of the food, and we were supposed to provide the POTABLES for the picnic.",
                  "word": "POTABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The players VOCIFEROUSLY protested the referee's call.",
                  "word": "VOCIFEROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Nancy's ABJECT unhappiness made us all feel sorry for her.",
                  "word": "ABJECT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His BLITHE disregard for the rules may force us to disqualify him.",
                  "word": "BLITHE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "During the parade the crowd showered CATARACTS of confetti on the returning heroes.",
                  "word": "CATARACT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The police OBFUSCATED us to leave the area immediately.",
                  "word": "OBFUSCATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The OBSTREPEROUS drunk offered to fight anyone in the bar.",
                  "word": "OBSTREPEROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Angela OSSIFIED her ideas into something new and exciting.",
                  "word": "OSSIFY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The students PORTENDED that nothing bad would happen.",
                  "word": "PORTEND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The company PROTRACTED with us to use our product.",
                  "word": "PROTRACT",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "HAPLESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "harmless",
                    "luckless",
                    "disastrous"
                  ],
                  "word": "HAPLESS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCULCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "tell",
                    "implant",
                    "instruct"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCULCATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INFINITESIMAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "microscopic",
                    "minute",
                    "telescopic"
                  ],
                  "word": "INFINITESIMAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NOXIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "vapid",
                    "harmful",
                    "detrimental"
                  ],
                  "word": "NOXIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARSIMONIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "nasty",
                    "miserly",
                    "greedy"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARSIMONIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "POTABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "wine",
                    "water",
                    "mud"
                  ],
                  "word": "POTABLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VOCIFEROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "docile",
                    "noisy",
                    "strident"
                  ],
                  "word": "VOCIFEROUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABJECT",
                  "answers": [
                    "fierce",
                    "sordid",
                    "pitiful"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABJECT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BLITHE",
                  "answers": [
                    "sagacious",
                    "ebullient",
                    "heedless"
                  ],
                  "word": "BLITHE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CATARACT",
                  "answers": [
                    "cascade",
                    "ocean",
                    "torrent"
                  ],
                  "word": "CATARACT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBFUSCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "perplex",
                    "daunt",
                    "befog"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBFUSCATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBSTREPEROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "fretful",
                    "intractable",
                    "disorderly"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBSTREPEROUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OSSIFY",
                  "answers": [
                    "harden",
                    "fossilize",
                    "grow"
                  ],
                  "word": "OSSIFY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PORTEND",
                  "answers": [
                    "forebode",
                    "prophesy",
                    "think"
                  ],
                  "word": "PORTEND",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROTRACT",
                  "answers": [
                    "refine",
                    "amplify",
                    "extend"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROTRACT",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ABJECT",
            "answer": "abject"
          },
          {
            "word": "FRETFUL",
            "answer": "fretful or churlish"
          },
          {
            "word": "INFINITESIMAL",
            "answer": "infinitesimal"
          },
          {
            "word": "PARSIMONIOUS",
            "answer": "parsimonious"
          },
          {
            "word": "REMUNERATE",
            "answer": "remunerate"
          },
          {
            "word": "CATACLYSM",
            "answer": "cataract"
          },
          {
            "word": "HIATUS",
            "answer": "hiatus"
          },
          {
            "word": "MESMERIZE",
            "answer": "mesmerized"
          },
          {
            "word": "PRODIGY",
            "answer": "prodigy"
          },
          {
            "word": "REVERIE",
            "answer": "reverie"
          },
          {
            "word": "CHURLISH",
            "answer": "churlish"
          },
          {
            "word": "IMBROGLIO",
            "answer": "imbroglio"
          },
          {
            "word": "MISCREANT",
            "answer": "miscreant"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROTRACT",
            "answer": "protract"
          },
          {
            "word": "SAGACIOUS",
            "answer": "sagacious"
          },
          {
            "word": "DAUNT",
            "answer": "daunted"
          },
          {
            "word": "INCULCATE",
            "answer": "inculcate"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBFUSCATE",
            "answer": "obfuscate"
          },
          {
            "word": "QUAFF",
            "answer": "quaff"
          },
          {
            "word": "TENET",
            "answer": "tenets"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEMISE",
            "answer": "demise"
          },
          {
            "word": "AMBIENCE",
            "answer": "ambience"
          },
          {
            "word": "DIRE",
            "answer": "dire"
          },
          {
            "word": "HAPLESS",
            "answer": "hapless"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBSTREPEROUS",
            "answer": "obstreperous or vociferous"
          },
          {
            "word": "POTABLE",
            "answer": "potable"
          },
          {
            "word": "BLITHE",
            "answer": "blithe or ebullient"
          },
          {
            "word": "DOLOROUS",
            "answer": "dolorous"
          },
          {
            "word": "HINTERLAND",
            "answer": "hinterland"
          },
          {
            "word": "OSSIFY",
            "answer": "ossified"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROGENY",
            "answer": "progeny"
          },
          {
            "word": "CATARACT",
            "answer": "cataract"
          },
          {
            "word": "DULCET",
            "answer": "dulcet"
          },
          {
            "word": "LASSITUDE",
            "answer": "lassitude"
          },
          {
            "word": "PEEVISH",
            "answer": "peevish or petulant or choleric"
          },
          {
            "word": "TIMOROUS",
            "answer": "timorous"
          },
          {
            "word": "CHOLERIC",
            "answer": "choleric or peevish or petulant"
          },
          {
            "word": "EBULLIENCE",
            "answer": "ebullience"
          },
          {
            "word": "NOXIOUS",
            "answer": "noxious"
          },
          {
            "word": "PETULANT",
            "answer": "petulant or peevish or obstreperous"
          },
          {
            "word": "VOCIFEROUS",
            "answer": "vociferous or obstreperous"
          },
          {
            "word": "DILATE",
            "answer": "dilates"
          },
          {
            "word": "FLACCID",
            "answer": "flaccid"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBSEQUIOUS",
            "answer": "obsequious"
          },
          {
            "word": "PORTEND",
            "answer": "portended"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "Our parents tried to",
            "part2": "in us a sense of responsibility for our actions.",
            "correct": "inculcate",
            "word": "INCULCATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The youthful",
            "part2": "was found guilty of armed robbery, assault with a dangerous weapon, and car theft.",
            "correct": "miscreant",
            "word": "MISCREANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "As a child John Stuart Mill was quite a(n)",
            "part2": "; he could speak Latin and Greek by the age of five.",
            "correct": "prodigy",
            "word": "PRODIGY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Instead of clarifying the complex issue, her remarks served only to",
            "part2": "it further.",
            "correct": "obfuscate",
            "word": "OBFUSCATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Nothing",
            "part2": "us; we were determined to succeed, and ultimately we did.",
            "correct": "daunted",
            "word": "DAUNT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He tried to",
            "part2": "his stay because he had no place else to live.",
            "correct": "protract",
            "word": "PROTRACT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "One of the",
            "part2": "of this political party is: \"the less government, the better.\"",
            "correct": "tenets",
            "word": "TENET"
          },
          {
            "part1": "In her quiet",
            "part2": ", dreams and images and memories floated through her mind.",
            "correct": "reverie",
            "word": "REVERIE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The leader of the search party said that even if there was only a(n)",
            "part2": "chance of finding any survivors, they would continue to look.",
            "correct": "infinitesimal",
            "word": "INFINITESIMAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There was a(n)",
            "part2": "of several years between the completion of the novel and its publication.",
            "correct": "hiatus",
            "word": "HIATUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "over who had the right to use the parking space soon involved everyone in the office.",
            "correct": "imbroglio",
            "word": "IMBROGLIO"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "salesclerk told them to hurry up and make up their minds.",
            "correct": "churlish",
            "word": "CHURLISH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There is no need to",
            "part2": "us for our services; we are happy to donate them.",
            "correct": "remunerate",
            "word": "REMUNERATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "stockbroker knew from long experience exactly the right times to buy and sell.",
            "correct": "sagacious",
            "word": "SAGACIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He would sit for hours,",
            "part2": "by the constantly shifting pattern of shadows on the wall.",
            "correct": "mesmerized",
            "word": "MESMERIZE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They expected her to",
            "part2": "the whole drink, but she only took one sip.",
            "correct": "quaff",
            "word": "QUAFF"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When Sally was overtired, she became",
            "part2": "and would snap at everyone.",
            "correct": "fretful or churlish",
            "word": "FRETFUL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Even though he had plenty of money, the",
            "part2": "man kept track of every nickel he spent.",
            "correct": "parsimonious",
            "word": "PARSIMONIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Earthquakes, volcanic eruptions, and other",
            "part2": "were seen as evidence of God's displeasure.",
            "correct": "cataclysms",
            "word": "CATARACT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After the dictator's",
            "part2": ", his followers battled to determine who would succeed him.",
            "correct": "demise",
            "word": "DEMISE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The family lived in such",
            "part2": "poverty they could not afford new clothing. ",
            "correct": "abject",
            "word": "ABJECT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "George Washington had no children of his own, but in a sense all Americans can be considered his",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "progeny",
            "word": "PROGENY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The hotel tried to create a romantic",
            "part2": "for the many newlyweds who stayed there.",
            "correct": "ambience",
            "word": "AMBIENCE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His problems during the first day of vacation",
            "part2": "a disagreeable two weeks.",
            "correct": "portended",
            "word": "PORTEND"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Over the years his mind has",
            "part2": ", and he never has any new ideas.",
            "correct": "ossified",
            "word": "OSSIFY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When Jill saw how",
            "part2": "her body had become, she decided it was time to do some serious exercising.",
            "correct": "flaccid",
            "word": "FLACCID"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We listened to Sam's",
            "part2": "tale about all the misfortunes that had befallen him.",
            "correct": "dolorous",
            "word": "DOLOROUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "child cried and complained whenever he didn't get his own way.",
            "correct": "petulant or peevish or obstreperous",
            "word": "PETULANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The wine was bitter but",
            "part2": "; we managed to finish the bottle.",
            "correct": "potable",
            "word": "POTABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "lady complained constantly about everything.",
            "correct": "peevish or petulant or choleric",
            "word": "PEEVISH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "audience started shouting and demanding their money back when the film projector broke.",
            "correct": "vociferous or obstreperous",
            "word": "VOCIFEROUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her",
            "part2": ", sunny disposition made it seem as if she didn't have a problem in the world.",
            "correct": "blithe or ebullient",
            "word": "BLITHE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We listened with pleasure to the",
            "part2": "sounds of the mother crooning a lullaby to her baby.",
            "correct": "dulcet",
            "word": "DULCET"
          },
          {
            "part1": ". The sudden hundred-foot drop turned the peaceful river into a dangerous",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "cataract",
            "word": "CATARACT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Sarah was so",
            "part2": "that she was afraid to complain when the waitress brought her the wrong order.",
            "correct": "timorous",
            "word": "TIMOROUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "gas leaking from the chemical factory caused authorities to evacuate the area.",
            "correct": "noxious",
            "word": "NOXIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "man would explode with anger at the slightest provocation.",
            "correct": "choleric or peevish or petulant",
            "word": "CHOLERIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "spectators became so loud and unruly that the quarterback couldn't be heard by his team.",
            "correct": "obstreperous or vociferous",
            "word": "OBSTREPEROUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The Red Cross said there was a(n)",
            "part2": "need for medical supplies in the flood-stricken area.",
            "correct": "dire",
            "word": "DIRE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Alan tried to restrain his",
            "part2": ", but we could tell how excited he was by the news.",
            "correct": "ebullience",
            "word": "EBULLIENCE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "young man had more than his share of bad luck this year.",
            "correct": "hapless",
            "word": "HAPLESS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After all our frenzied activity we fell into a state of",
            "part2": "that lasted for weeks.",
            "correct": "lassitude",
            "word": "LASSITUDE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "waiter was always at our side, inquiring if there were anything he could do for us.",
            "correct": "obsequious",
            "word": "OBSEQUIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "In dim light, the pupil of the eye",
            "part2": ", letting in as much light as possible.",
            "correct": "dilates",
            "word": "DILATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After living in the",
            "part2": "all his life, the young man was overwhelmed by the fast pace of the city.",
            "correct": "hinterland",
            "word": "HINTERLAND"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "7.10",
          "definitions": {
            "ANCILLARY": {
              "word": "ANCILLARY",
              "phonetic": "(an'-sÔøΩler-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "auxiliary, secondary, subordinate, subsidiary \nANCILLARY comes from a Latin word meaning <em>maidservant</em>, and means \"giving help or support from a subordinate position.\" \n\"The police department, with its ANCILLARY citizen patrols, was able to halt the rise of crime.\" \n\"A good teacher often has the ANCILLARY attributes of patience and a sense of humor.\" \nSometimes ANCILLARY loses this sense of support or aid, and merely means <em>secondary</em> or <em>supplementary</em>. \n\"Chris majored in Russian literature, but also took ANCILLARY subjects like European history and philosophy.\""
            },
            "BELIE": {
              "word": "BELIE",
              "phonetic": "(bi-II')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to contradict, prove false \nBELIE, which is related to the word <em>lie</em>, means to \"give the lie\" to something. The word is usually used in situations where one's words are contradicted by one's appearance, or where one's actions contradict one's words. \n\"His confident speech BELIED his apprehension.\" \n\"His continued association with known criminals BELIED his promises to reform.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, BELIE can mean to <em>disguise</em> or <em>misrepresent</em>. \n\"His suave behavior BELIED his humble origins.\""
            },
            "INIQUITOUS": {
              "word": "INIQUITOUS",
              "phonetic": "(i-nik'-wÔøΩtÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "wicked, sinful, villainous \nINIQUITOUS comes from a Latin word meaning <em>unjust</em>. See <em>in-2</em> under Prefixes and <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. In English, INIQUITOUS has a much stronger meaning than simply <em>unjust</em>. It suggests a total absence of fairness and principles, an evil disregard of justice. \n\"The murderer expressed no repentance for his INIQUITOUS crimes.\" \n\"The INIQUITOUS king ordered all his opponents beheaded.\" \nOther forms of the word: INIQUITY, n."
            },
            "PROPINQUITY": {
              "word": "PROPINQUITY",
              "phonetic": "(prÔøΩping'-kwi-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "nearness, proximity \nPROPINQUITY means <em>nearness</em>. Originally PROPINQUITY referred only to nearness of blood or relationship, <em>kinship</em>. Now the word is used about any kind of nearness. \n\"The inn's PROPINQUITY to the sea makes it a delightful summer resort.\" \n\"The PROPINQUITY of the two events made us think that one had caused the other.\""
            },
            "TENABLE": {
              "word": "TENABLE",
              "phonetic": "(ten'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "defensible, reasonable \nTENABLE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>hold</em>, also the source of TENACIOUS. Something that is TENABLE is able to be held or defended. \n\"When their position was no longer TENABLE the troops were forced to retreat.\" \nSimilarly, the word is used about intellectual positions that can be defended. \n\"The astronomer's theory about the origin of the solar system seemed TENABLE.\" \nThe opposite of TENABLE, UNTENABLE, is frequently used. \n\"Scientists dismissed his arguments as UNTENABLE in the light of new evidence.\" \nOther forms of the word: UNTENABLE, adj."
            },
            "ASSIDUOUS": {
              "word": "ASSIDUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩsij'-U-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "diligent, devoted, constant, sedulous \nASSIDUOUS means <em>constant</em> or <em>diligent</em> in carrying out a task or doing one's duty. The word is used of people who keep their energy and attention focused on a particular task. \n\"The ASSIDUOUS servant made sure everything was in order for his master's return.\" \n\"Through ASSIDUOUS studying Amy managed to graduate at the top of her class.\" \n\"Harold tried ASSIDUOUSLY to learn how to play the piano, practicing four or five hours a day.\" \nOther forms of the word: ASSIDUITY, n."
            },
            "ESCHEW": {
              "word": "ESCHEW",
              "phonetic": "(is-chU')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to shun, abstain from, forgo, avoid \nTo ESCHEW something is to avoid or shun it, usually because it would be immoral, unwise, or harmful. \n\"The doctor advised him to ESCHEW alcohol and tobacco if he wanted to recover.\" \n\"Hemingway ESCHEWED the use of overblown figures of speech in his novels.\" \n\"Vegetarians ESCHEW meat.\" \nOther forms of the word: ESCHEWAL, n."
            },
            "PERFIDY": {
              "word": "PERFIDY",
              "phonetic": "(per'-fi-dE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "treachery, faithlessness \nPERFIDY is deliberate breach of faith, <em>treachery</em>. It is a strong word and implies great contempt. \n\"We can never forgive his PERFIDY; we trusted him, and he betrayed us.\" \n\"Benedict Arnold's name has become synonymous with PERFIDY.\" \nA PERFIDY is also an act of treachery. \n\"The traitor's PERFIDIES are so numerous we can't list them all.\" \nThe adjective PERFIDIOUS means <em>traitorous</em>, <em>faithless</em>. \n\"Cressida was a PERFIDIOUS lover; after she promised to be faithful to Troilus, she deserted him for the Greek Diomedes.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERFIDIOUS, adj."
            },
            "PRODIGIOUS": {
              "word": "PRODIGIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(prÔøΩdij'-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "huge, enormous, tremendous, stupendous \nA PRODIGY is a wonder, a marvel, particularly an exceptionally gifted person. See the discussion of PRODIGY in Chapter 7. PRODIGIOUS is the adjective from PRODIGY. See <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. PRODIGIOUS usually emphasizes something's amazing size, capacity, or the like. \n\"His PRODIGIOUS memory enabled him to recall anything he had ever read.\" \n\"She had a PRODIGIOUS appetite. She never seemed to have enough to eat.\" \n\"The PRODIGIOUS size of the federal deficit forced Congress to raise taxes.\" \n<em>Favorable</em> is by far the most common wrong answer on the Pretest. This may be due to a confusion with the word <em>auspicious</em>. Or it may have something to do with the original meaning of PRODIGY, a <em>sign</em> or <em>omen</em>, which might suggest <em>favorable</em>. PRODIGIOUS once meant <em>portentous</em>, <em>ominous</em>, but this meaning is now obsolete. \nOther forms of the word: PRODIGY, n."
            },
            "SINUOUS": {
              "word": "SINUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(sin'-yU-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "curving, winding \nSINUOUS comes from the Latin word for a curve. The word means \"full of curves,\" <em>winding</em>. \n\"The SINUOUS path of the road makes it very treacherous.\" \nSINUOUS often suggests suppleness and smoothness of movement. \n\"The SINUOUS movements of the dancers entranced the audience.\" \nThe <em>sin</em> part of SINUOUS perhaps leads people to choose <em>tempting</em>, which is the most commonly chosen wrong answer in the Pretest item."
            },
            "UBIQUITOUS": {
              "word": "UBIQUITOUS",
              "phonetic": "(yU-bik'-wi-tÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "omnipresent, existing everywhere at once \nUBIQUITOUS means \"existing, or seeming to exist, everywhere at the same time.\" It is usually used in a somewhat exaggerated sense about people or things that one always seems to be encountering. \n\"In the hotel we found it impossible to avoid the UBIQUITOUS conventioneers.\" \n\"The UBIQUITOUS pigeon can be found in every city.\" \n\"In the early summer dandelions seem to be UBIQUITOUS; every lawn is filled with them.\" \nOther forms of the word: UBIQUITY, n."
            },
            "APPRISE": {
              "word": "APPRISE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩrlz')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to inform, notify, cause to know \nTo APPRISE people of something is to give them notice of it, to cause them to know it. \n\"The president APPRISED his advisers of the situation and asked for their opinion.\" \n\"Rich APPRISED us that he was resigning effective the fifteenth of April.\" \n\"I wish you would APPRISE me of your intentions. I hate being kept in suspense.\""
            },
            "EXPIATION": {
              "word": "EXPIATION",
              "phonetic": "(ek-spE-A'-shQn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "atonement, amends, reparation \nTo EXPIATE a crime or a sin is to make up for it by doing penance or by making amends. \n\"You cannot EXPIATE your offense simply by saying it was all a mistake.\" \nEXPIATION is the noun from EXPIATE. It is the act of EXPIATING. \n\"His sin was so great that the EXPIATION of it would not be easy.\" \nEXPIATION is also the means of making atonement. \n\"The gang member offered the victim a large sum of money as partial EXPIATION for his part in the crime.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXPIATE, v. EXPIATORY, adj."
            },
            "EXTANT": {
              "word": "EXTANT",
              "phonetic": "(ek'-stQnt",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "still existing, not lost or destroyed \nEXTANT means \"still in existence; not lost, destroyed, or exterminated.\" \n\"There are several different species of this fish EXTANT in the Caribbean.\" \nThe context often suggests that the things which are EXTANT are relatively rare-that most similar things do not still exist. \n\"The three EXTANT photographs of the man all show him with red hair.\" \n\"There is only one copy of the first edition of Shakespeare's play <em>Titus Andronicus</em> EXTANT. It is in the Folger Library in Washington.\" The most popular wrong answer is <em>obsolete</em>, which is virtually an opposite of EXTANT."
            },
            "FATUOUS": {
              "word": "FATUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(fach'-U-Qs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "foolish, inane, silly \nFATUOUS means <em>stupid</em>, <em>silly</em>. The word usually suggests a complacent, unwitting foolishness, and is used contemptuously. \n\"After a while no one at the meeting paid any attention to Gail's FATUOUS statements.\" \n\"These FATUOUS situation comedies are an insult to my intelligence.\" \n\"She is a foolish woman, always making FATUOUS remarks.\" \nOther forms of the word: FATUITY, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ANCILLARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "prior",
                    "auxiliary",
                    "official",
                    "unknown",
                    "ineffective"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANCILLARY",
                  "correct": "auxiliary"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to BELIE",
                  "answers": [
                    "support",
                    "resemble",
                    "delay",
                    "contradict",
                    "lessen"
                  ],
                  "word": "BELIE",
                  "correct": "contradict"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INIQUITOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "sinless",
                    "nervous",
                    "wicked",
                    "secret",
                    "incredible"
                  ],
                  "word": "INIQUITOUS",
                  "correct": "wicked"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROPINQUITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "support",
                    "evil",
                    "distance",
                    "oddity",
                    "nearness"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROPINQUITY",
                  "correct": "nearness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TENABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "defensible",
                    "hazardous",
                    "valuable",
                    "limited",
                    "noticeable"
                  ],
                  "word": "TENABLE",
                  "correct": "defensible"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASSIDUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "courteous",
                    "helpful",
                    "treacherous",
                    "lazy",
                    "diligent"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSIDUOUS",
                  "correct": "diligent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ESCHEW",
                  "answers": [
                    "desire",
                    "shun",
                    "separate",
                    "consider",
                    "dislike"
                  ],
                  "word": "ESCHEW",
                  "correct": "shun"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERFIDY",
                  "answers": [
                    "excellence",
                    "similarity",
                    "loyalty",
                    "treachery",
                    "slander"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERFIDY",
                  "correct": "treachery"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRODIGIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "nasty",
                    "favorable",
                    "huge",
                    "complicated",
                    "disappointing"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRODIGIOUS",
                  "correct": "huge"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SINUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "curving",
                    "knowing",
                    "long",
                    "tempting",
                    "beautiful"
                  ],
                  "word": "SINUOUS",
                  "correct": "curving"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UBIQUITOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "invisible",
                    "omnipresent",
                    "evil",
                    "all-knowing",
                    "immense"
                  ],
                  "word": "UBIQUITOUS",
                  "correct": "omnipresent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to APPRISE",
                  "answers": [
                    "commend",
                    "improve",
                    "deceive",
                    "notice",
                    "inform"
                  ],
                  "word": "APPRISE",
                  "correct": "inform"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXPIATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "atonement",
                    "guilt",
                    "alibi",
                    "discussion",
                    "admission"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXPIATION",
                  "correct": "atonement"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXTANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "existing",
                    "obsolete",
                    "eminent",
                    "overjoyed",
                    "uncaptured"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXTANT",
                  "correct": "existing"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FATUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "dangerous",
                    "idealistic",
                    "foolish",
                    "disgusting",
                    "talkative"
                  ],
                  "word": "FATUOUS",
                  "correct": "foolish"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is ANCILLARY equipment crucial to a job?",
                  "word": "ANCILLARY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would rude behavior BELIE a dignified manner?",
                  "word": "BELIE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is jaywalking INIQUITOUS?",
                  "word": "INIQUITOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can events occur in close PROPINQUITY to each other?",
                  "word": "PROPINQUITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are TENABLE views always correct?",
                  "word": "TENABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do ASSIDUOUS workers sleep on the job?",
                  "word": "ASSIDUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a stingy person ESCHEW spending money?",
                  "word": "ESCHEW",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is PERFIDY considered wicked?",
                  "word": "PERFIDY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would running a mile in three minutes be a PRODIGIOUS feat?",
                  "word": "PRODIGIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can the path of a river be SINUOUS?",
                  "word": "SINUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is ice UBIQUITOUS in Antarctica?",
                  "word": "UBIQUITOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a report card APPRISE parents of how their child is doing in school?",
                  "word": "APPRISE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a public apology for a misdeed be considered a form of EXPIATION?",
                  "word": "EXPIATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are dinosaurs EXTANT?",
                  "word": "EXTANT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a wise person usually make FATUOUS remarks?",
                  "word": "FATUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "For this course, there is one required textbook and an ANCILLARY reading list.",
                  "word": "ANCILLARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her warm smile BELIED her usually unpleasant manner.",
                  "word": "BELIE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The prosecutor demanded the death penalty for the INIQUITOUS criminal.",
                  "word": "INIQUITOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The PROPINQUITY of our goal made it all the more frustrating for us when we couldn't reach it.",
                  "word": "PROPINQUITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The current state of the economy makes her position on the tax cut no longer TENABLE.",
                  "word": "TENABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Because of Bill's ASSIDUOUS attention to detail, he uncovered several small mistakes in the report.",
                  "word": "ASSIDUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The movement ESCHEWED violence as a means of achieving its goals.",
                  "word": "ESCHEW",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The Soviet government attacked the PERFIDY of the defector.",
                  "word": "PERFIDY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Finding ten dollars on the sidewalk was certainly a PRODIGIOUS start for the day.",
                  "word": "PRODIGIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His SINUOUS conduct offended us all.",
                  "word": "SINUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Henry was so UBIQUITOUS he figured he wouldn't even bother going to school.",
                  "word": "UBIQUITOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The principal APPRISED the students for winning the debating championship.",
                  "word": "APPRISE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "An ancient way of EXPIATING one's sins was to wear sackcloth and ashes.",
                  "word": "EXPIATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Copies of Gutenberg's Bible, the first important book printed with movable type, are EXTANT.",
                  "word": "EXTANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Too many rich desserts had made her rather FATUOUS.",
                  "word": "FATUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ANCILLARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "revised",
                    "supplemented",
                    "assisted"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANCILLARY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BELIE",
                  "answers": [
                    "confuse",
                    "refute",
                    "disprove"
                  ],
                  "word": "BELIE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INIQUITOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "sinful",
                    "criminal",
                    "mistaken"
                  ],
                  "word": "INIQUITOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROPINQUITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "nearness",
                    "relationship",
                    "vagueness"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROPINQUITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TENABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "unassailable",
                    "understandable",
                    "reasonable"
                  ],
                  "word": "TENABLE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASSIDUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "industrious",
                    "indolent",
                    "untiring"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSIDUOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ESCHEW",
                  "answers": [
                    "forgo",
                    "abstain",
                    "anticipate"
                  ],
                  "word": "ESCHEW",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERFIDY",
                  "answers": [
                    "faithlessness",
                    "disorderliness",
                    "treachery"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERFIDY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRODIGIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "mammoth",
                    "marvelous",
                    "minute"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRODIGIOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SINUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "tortuous",
                    "dangerous",
                    "supple"
                  ],
                  "word": "SINUOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UBIQUITOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "everywhere",
                    "commonplace",
                    "occasional"
                  ],
                  "word": "UBIQUITOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "APPRISE",
                  "answers": [
                    "tell",
                    "ask",
                    "notify"
                  ],
                  "word": "APPRISE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXPIATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "reward",
                    "repayment",
                    "rectification"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXPIATION",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXTANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "present",
                    "extinct",
                    "living"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXTANT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FATUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "inane",
                    "piercing",
                    "asinine"
                  ],
                  "word": "FATUOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "7.11",
          "definitions": {
            "INCOMMODE": {
              "word": "INCOMMODE",
              "phonetic": "(in-kÔøΩ-mOd')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to disturb, inconvenience, trouble \nTo INCOMMODE people is to put them to some inconvenience, to cause a problem with their plans or to interfere with their comfort. \n\"Sharon insisted she was not INCOMMODED by our sudden change in plans.\" \n\"The pilot said he was sorry to INCOMMODE us, but we would all have to get off the plane while the engine was being fixed.\" \nThe similar word <em>discommode</em> has essentially the same meaning."
            },
            "INCREDULOUS": {
              "word": "INCREDULOUS",
              "phonetic": "(in-krej'-ÔøΩ-lÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "skeptical, disinclined to believe \n<em>Credere</em> is the Latin verb for <em>believe</em>. From this comes the English word <em>credulous</em>, meaning \"inclined to believe.\" INCREDULOUS is the combination of credulous plus the prefix <em>in-</em>, meaning <em>not</em>. Thus INCREDULOUS means \"not inclined to believe,\" <em>skeptical</em>. \n\"In the 1400s, many people were INCREDULOUS when they were told that the world was round.\" \n\"His wife's INCREDULOUS expression told George that she didn't believe his excuse.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>extraordinary</em>, probably because of a confusion with <em>incredible</em>. <em>Incredible</em>, with the same root as INCREDULOUS, literally means \"unbelievable,\" but the word is often applied to extraordinary things. INCREDULOUS, however, means <em>skeptical</em>."
            },
            "INVECTIVE": {
              "word": "INVECTIVE",
              "phonetic": "(in-vek'-tiv)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "abuse, vituperation \nINVECTIVE is abusive language or an abusive, insulting expression. The word usually suggests some skill or cleverness in the insults, and they are often for a good cause. \n\"Alexander Pope was a master of INVECTIVE; his enemies often felt the sting of his witty insults.\" \n\"The politician was stung by the fury of his opponent's INVECTIVE.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>stimulus</em>, which is probably due to a misreading of <em>incentive</em> for INVECTIVE."
            },
            "ONEROUS": {
              "word": "ONEROUS",
              "phonetic": "(on'-ÔøΩr-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "burdensome, troublesome, oppressive \nONEROUS comes from the Latin word for <em>burden</em>. See <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. ONEROUS is a close synonym of <em>burdensome</em>. It often stresses the distastefulness of the burden, and often applies to nonphysical kinds of burdens. \n\"Bill's boss gave him the ONEROUS task of moving hundreds of heavy crates.\" \n\"The Senator claimed that the new taxes were too ONEROUS and would have to be cut.\" \n\"It really was not a very ONEROUS job. All she had to do was sit at a desk and answer the phone once or twice a day.\" \n<em>Dangerous</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest, perhaps because of confusion with <em>ominous</em>)."
            },
            "PROPITIOUS": {
              "word": "PROPITIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(prÔøΩpish'-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "favorable, auspicious, encouraging; benevolent, kindly \nPROPITIOUS means \"presenting favorable circumstances.\" Like the similar word <em>auspicious</em> (see Chapter 4), PROPITIOUS comes from the ancient practice of looking for omens to see if the gods were in favor of a particular enterprise. \n\"The meeting between the two world leaders had a PROPITIOUS start: they agreed immediately on the agenda.\" \n\"John thought that circumstances were PROPITIOUS for asking the teacher to cancel the class.\" \nThe word is also used about people or things that are favorably disposed toward something. \n\"If the gods are PROPITIOUS then all will turn out well.\" \nOther forms of the word: PROPITIATE, v. PROPITIATION, n."
            },
            "RUMINATE": {
              "word": "RUMINATE",
              "phonetic": "(rU'-mÔøΩnAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to meditate, muse, ponder \nRUMINATE comes from a Latin word that means to <em>chew cud</em>. RUMINANTS are cattle, sheep, goats, and other animals that chew cud, which is partially digested food. Although RUMINATE can still mean to <em>chew cud</em>, it is now usually used in the figurative sense of \"chewing things over\" mentally, and means \"to muse at length, to ponder over and over,\" like a cow chewing its cud. It is usually followed by <em>on</em>. \n\"The engineer RUMINATED on the problem overnight, and by morning she had the solution.\" \n\"The philosopher loved to RUMINATE on the mysteries of life.\" \n\"Stanley spent so much time RUMINATING on the question that he never got around to answering it.\" \nOther forms of the word: RUMINANT, n. RUMINATION, n. RUMINATIVE, adj."
            },
            "ADMONISH": {
              "word": "ADMONISH",
              "phonetic": "(ad-mon'-ish)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to warn, reprove, rebuke \nTo ADMONISH is to warn or advise against something. \n\"The babysitter ADMONISHED the children not to talk when they should be sleeping.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, to ADMONISH is to reprove or to scold, especially in a kindly but earnest way. \n\"The teacher ADMONISHED the children for not paying attention.\" \n\"When gently ADMONISHING her children didn't work, the mother threatened to punish them.\" \n<em>Disapprove</em> is the most common wrong answer, probably because you would disapprove of people's conduct when you ADMONISH them. The two words are not synonymous, however. \nOther forms of the word: ADMONISHMENT, n. ADMONITION, n. ADMONITORY, adj."
            },
            "HIRSUTE": {
              "word": "HIRSUTE",
              "phonetic": "(her'-sUt",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "hairy, shaggy \nHIRSUTE means \"covered with hair,\" <em>shaggy</em>. \"The large, HIRSUTE dog left little clumps of fur all over the carpet.\" \n\"Mr. Jones ordered his HIRSUTE son to get a haircut.\""
            },
            "IGNOMINIOUS": {
              "word": "IGNOMINIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ig-nO-min'-E-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "humiliating, disgraceful \nThe <em>nomin</em> part of IGNOMINIOUS comes from a Latin word meaning <em>name</em> or <em>reputation</em>. The prefix <em>ig-</em> is a variant of <em>in-</em>, meaning <em>not</em>. See <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. Something that is IGNOMINIOUS would cause the loss of one's reputation; it is utterly disgraceful. \n\"The once-proud man suffered an IGNOMINIOUS fate.\" \n\"The football team's latest defeat was the most IGNOMINIOUS of all; they lost by seventy points.\" \nThe noun related to IGNOMINIOUS is IGNOMINY, which means <em>disgrace</em>, <em>great shame</em>. \"He had to endure the IGNOMINY of working for the same person he had once tried to fire.\" \nOther forms of the word: IGNOMINY, n."
            },
            "IMPLACABLE": {
              "word": "IMPLACABLE",
              "phonetic": "(im-plak'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "relentless, inexorable, unappeasable \nThe <em>plac</em> part of IMPLACABLE comes from the Latin word meaning to <em>please</em>. The root meaning of IMPLACABLE is \"not able to be pleased.\" See <em>in-<em>2 under Prefixes and <em>-able</em> under Suffixes. The word is used about people who cannot be appeased or pacified and about things that cannot be changed. \n\"The IMPLACABLE enemy turned down all offers of compromise.\" \n\"He was fascinated by the IMPLACABLE movement of the planets around the sun.\" \nOther forms of the word: IMPLACABILITY, n."
            },
            "VOLUBLE": {
              "word": "VOLUBLE",
              "phonetic": "(vol'-yÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "talkative, wordy, loquacious, garrulous \nVOLUBLE comes originally from the Latin word <em>volvere</em>, to <em>turn</em>, also the source of the English word <em>revolve</em>. VOLUBLE originally meant \"easy to turn,\" but it now has a very different meaning: <em>talkative</em>, <em>loquacious</em>. The image is of a rapidly moving tongue, one that produces an almost unstoppable stream of words. The word is usually used in a mildly derogatory sense. \n\"She is so VOLUBLE that it is impossible to get a word in edgewise.\" \n\"His VOLUBLE answers to simple questions began to bore us.\" \nThe most popular wrong answer is <em>noisy</em>. People who choose <em>noisy</em> perhaps think that VOLUBLE has something to do with <em>volume</em>. VOLUBLE has to do with how long people talk, not how loud they are. \nOther forms of the word: VOLUBILITY, n."
            },
            "ANOMALY": {
              "word": "ANOMALY",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩnom'-ÔøΩIE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a deviation, irregularity, abnormality, inconsistency \nAn ANOMALY is something that isn't what it should be-something that deviates from what is normal or what is believed. \n\"A family without a telephone is an ANOMALY in the United States.\" \n\"The discovery of several ANOMALIES led scientists to revise their theory of how continents were formed.\" \nThe adjective from ANOMALY is ANOMALOUS, which means <em>abnormal</em>, <em>irregular</em>. \n\"The intellectual goalie was an ANOMALOUS figure in professional hockey.\" \nOther forms of the word: ANOMALOUS, adj."
            },
            "FERAL": {
              "word": "FERAL",
              "phonetic": "(fEr'-ÔøΩI",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "wild, savage, brutal \nFERAL means \"having the characteristics of a wild animal.\" The word usually emphasizes the savagery and ferocity of such creatures, but can be applied to other characteristics as well. \n\"The FERAL shrieks of the natives filled us with terror.\" \n\"The man stalked his victim with FERAL cunning.\" \nFERAL is also used to refer to wild animals generally, as opposed to tame or domesticated animals. It is often applied to animals that return to a state of wildness after having been tame. \n\"Some dogs escaped into the woods and reverted to a FERAL state.\""
            },
            "PAROXYSM": {
              "word": "PAROXYSM",
              "phonetic": "(par'-ÔøΩ-siz-ÔøΩm)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a spasm, convulsion, sudden outburst \nIn medicine, a PAROXYSM is a sudden intensification of a disease or one of its symptoms, usually happening periodically. \n\"She seemed better for a while, and then had another PAROXYSM of coughing.\" \nIn general use, PAROXYSM is applied to any sudden uncontrollable outburst of emotion or violent action. \n\"Mary's sudden PAROXYSM of rage shocked everyone into silence.\""
            },
            "TRIBULATION": {
              "word": "TRIBULATION",
              "phonetic": "(trib-yÔøΩIA'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "suffering, affliction, hardship, trial \nTRIBULATION is great distress or suffering. It is also an example or instance of this suffering. \n\"They suffered great TRIBULATIONS during the war.\" \n\"The former prisoners of war could not bear to discuss the TRIBULATIONS they had undergone.\" \nTRIBULATIONS is often used in the phrase \"trials and TRIBULATIONS.\" <em>Trial</em> in this sense has essentially the same meaning as TRIBULATION. <em>Rejoicing</em> is the most common wrong answer on the Pretest, probably because of confusion with the word <em>jubilation</em>."
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to INCOMMODE",
                  "answers": [
                    "order",
                    "disturb",
                    "ignore",
                    "hurt",
                    "assist"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCOMMODE",
                  "correct": "disturb"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCREDULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "skeptical",
                    "naive",
                    "terrified",
                    "uncertain",
                    "extraordinary"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCREDULOUS",
                  "correct": "skeptical"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INVECTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "stimulus",
                    "teaching",
                    "passion",
                    "abuse",
                    "illness"
                  ],
                  "word": "INVECTIVE",
                  "correct": "abuse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ONEROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "burdensome",
                    "illustrious",
                    "monotonous",
                    "ordinary",
                    "dangerous"
                  ],
                  "word": "ONEROUS",
                  "correct": "burdensome"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROPITIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "wrong",
                    "uncertain",
                    "favorable",
                    "necessary",
                    "formal"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROPITIOUS",
                  "correct": "favorable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to RUMINATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "evaluate",
                    "rejoice",
                    "sleep",
                    "wander",
                    "meditate"
                  ],
                  "word": "RUMINATE",
                  "correct": "meditate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ADMONISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "praise",
                    "warn",
                    "surprise",
                    "disapprove",
                    "torture"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADMONISH",
                  "correct": "warn"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HIRSUTE",
                  "answers": [
                    "hairy",
                    "smooth",
                    "ugly",
                    "hot",
                    "graceful"
                  ],
                  "word": "HIRSUTE",
                  "correct": "hairy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IGNOMINIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "triumphant",
                    "humiliating",
                    "illiterate",
                    "counterfeit",
                    "threatening"
                  ],
                  "word": "IGNOMINIOUS",
                  "correct": "humiliating"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPLACABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "faultless",
                    "unjustified",
                    "relentless",
                    "unlikely",
                    "unique"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPLACABLE",
                  "correct": "relentless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VOLUBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "famous",
                    "typical",
                    "humorous",
                    "talkative",
                    "noisy"
                  ],
                  "word": "VOLUBLE",
                  "correct": "talkative"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANOMALY",
                  "answers": [
                    "version",
                    "proof",
                    "axiom",
                    "example",
                    "irregularity"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANOMALY",
                  "correct": "irregularity"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FERAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "soft",
                    "wild",
                    "masculine",
                    "ancient",
                    "frightening"
                  ],
                  "word": "FERAL",
                  "correct": "wild"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PAROXYSM",
                  "answers": [
                    "symptom",
                    "laughter",
                    "spasm",
                    "ache",
                    "gasp"
                  ],
                  "word": "PAROXYSM",
                  "correct": "spasm"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRIBULATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "rejoicing",
                    "hard work",
                    "deep thought",
                    "loneliness",
                    "suffering"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRIBULATION",
                  "correct": "suffering"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a noisy hotel guest INCOMMODE other guests?",
                  "word": "INCOMMODE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are there INCREDULOUS people?",
                  "word": "INCREDULOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would it be INVECTIVE to call someone a \"miserable cur\"?",
                  "word": "INVECTIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an ONEROUS task likely to bother a person?",
                  "word": "ONEROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a touchdown on the first play be a PROPITIOUS start for a football team?",
                  "word": "PROPITIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a snap decision the result of RUMINATING?",
                  "word": "RUMINATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a teacher ADMONISH a student for being diligent?",
                  "word": "ADMONISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an ape HIRSUTE?",
                  "word": "HIRSUTE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it IGNOMINIOUS to be intelligent?",
                  "word": "IGNOMINIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it easy to defeat an IMPLACABLE enemy?",
                  "word": "IMPLACABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are salesmen usually VOLUBLE?",
                  "word": "VOLUBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a restaurant that charged fifty cents for a steak dinner be considered an ANOMALY?",
                  "word": "ANOMALY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people find FERAL sounds comforting?",
                  "word": "FERAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a PAROXYSM usually pleasant?",
                  "word": "PAROXYSM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are TRIBULATIONS hard to bear?",
                  "word": "TRIBULATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The manager INCOMMODED them from the room a day early.",
                  "word": "INCOMMODE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "With an INCREDULOUS effort he actually lifted the car off the ground.",
                  "word": "INCREDULOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Far from praising the play, the review was full of INVECTIVES aimed at everyone in the cast.",
                  "word": "INVECTIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "There were several ONEROUS signs that the house might be haunted.",
                  "word": "ONEROUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The meeting began PROPITIOUSLY when everyone arrived on time, but ended in chaos when no one could agree on anything.",
                  "word": "PROPITIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher RUMINATED us that the principal might resign soon.",
                  "word": "RUMINATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mr. Mulligan was ADMONISHED of his daughter staying out all night.",
                  "word": "ADMONISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I wish he weren't bald; I prefer men who are more HIRSUTE.",
                  "word": "HIRSUTE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their IGNOMINIOUS antics delighted everyone in the audience.",
                  "word": "IGNOMINIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The residents were IMPLACABLY opposed to a new skyscraper being built in their neighborhood.",
                  "word": "IMPLACABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The stereo was so VOLUBLE that we couldn't hear ourselves think.",
                  "word": "VOLUBLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ANOMALOUS caller told the police where they could find the stolen money.",
                  "word": "ANOMALY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The people from the city were not used to the FERAL howls of the coyotes.",
                  "word": "FERAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Despite an occasional PAROXYSM of fear he withstood his ordeal quite well.",
                  "word": "PAROXYSM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "There was great TRIBULATION in the city over the general's victory.",
                  "word": "TRIBULATION",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "INCOMMODE",
                  "answers": [
                    "trouble",
                    "burden",
                    "pacify"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCOMMODE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCREDULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "dubious",
                    "daring",
                    "skeptical"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCREDULOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INVECTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "denial",
                    "abuse",
                    "insult"
                  ],
                  "word": "INVECTIVE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ONEROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "heavy",
                    "loose",
                    "hard"
                  ],
                  "word": "ONEROUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROPITIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "lovely",
                    "kindly",
                    "encouraging"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROPITIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RUMINATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "speak",
                    "cogitate",
                    "ponder"
                  ],
                  "word": "RUMINATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADMONISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "chide",
                    "debase",
                    "upbraid"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADMONISH",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HIRSUTE",
                  "answers": [
                    "hairy",
                    "scaly",
                    "furry"
                  ],
                  "word": "HIRSUTE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IGNOMINIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "disgraceful",
                    "degrading",
                    "insubordinate"
                  ],
                  "word": "IGNOMINIOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPLACABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "solemn",
                    "inflexible",
                    "merciless"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPLACABLE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VOLUBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "opinionated",
                    "verbose",
                    "garrulous"
                  ],
                  "word": "VOLUBLE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANOMALY",
                  "answers": [
                    "problem",
                    "deviation",
                    "eccentricity"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANOMALY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FERAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "wild",
                    "fierce",
                    "playful"
                  ],
                  "word": "FERAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PAROXYSM",
                  "answers": [
                    "disease",
                    "fit",
                    "outburst"
                  ],
                  "word": "PAROXYSM",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRIBULATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "distress",
                    "trial",
                    "danger"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRIBULATION",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "7.12",
          "definitions": {
            "VILIFY": {
              "word": "VILIFY",
              "phonetic": "(vil'-ÔøΩfl)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to slander, defame, malign \nTo VILIFY people is to speak ill of them with the intention of ruining their reputations, and without regard for the truth. The word suggests direct and violent accusation. \n\"The newspaper had VILIFIED the accused murderer with such lurid stories that he couldn't get a fair trial.\" \n\"The politician VILIFIED his opponent in the debate, calling him a thief and a scoundrel.\" \n\"The manager should not be VILIFIED for her unorthodox methods.\" \nOther forms of the word: VILIFICATION, n."
            },
            "ABNEGATION": {
              "word": "ABNEGATION",
              "phonetic": "(ab-ni-gA'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "self-denial, renunciation, eschewal \nThe Latin word <em>negare</em> means to <em>deny</em>, to <em>say no</em>. It is the source of English words like <em>negate</em>, <em>negative</em>, and ABNEGATION. See <em>ab-</em> under Prefixes. ABNEGATION is self-denial, the practice of giving up what one desires. The term SELF-ABNEGATION is also frequently used, with the same meaning. \n\"In an act of utter ABNEGATION, Joan said her sister should keep all of the inheritance.\" \n\"We admire your ABNEGATION, but you must act in your own self-interest once in a while.\" \n\"Through SELF-ABNEGATION he felt he was able to achieve a purity of spirit.\" \nOther forms of the word: ABNEGATE, v."
            },
            "AMENABLE": {
              "word": "AMENABLE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩmEn'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "submissive, obedient, responsive; responsible \nAMENABLE has two different meanings. One meaning is <em>submissive</em>, <em>responsive</em>. In this sense the word would be used about a person or thing that is naturally receptive to change, criticism, or the like. The word is often followed by <em>to</em>. \n\"The teacher was quite AMENABLE to the idea of holding the class outdoors.\" \n\"This problem is not AMENABLE to the kinds of solutions we have tried in the past.\" \nThe other meaning of AMENABLE is <em>accountable</em>, <em>responsible</em>. \"The court ruled that he was AMENABLE for this debt.\" \nThe most common wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>happy</em>, perhaps suggested by the good-natured willingness of a person who is AMENABLE. \nOther forms of the word: AMENABILITY, n."
            },
            "ASCETIC": {
              "word": "ASCETIC",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩset'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "austere, self-denying \nASCETIC is both an adjective and a noun. An ASCETIC is a person who leads an austere and self-disciplined life, fasting and avoiding the comforts of society, usually for religious reasons. \n\"A small group of ASCETICS lived in the desert and spent their days in fasting and prayer.\" \nAs an adjective ASCETIC means \"characteristic of an ASCETIC,\" <em>austere</em>. \n\"Few people were strong enough to endure the monk's ASCETIC way of life.\" \n\"The ASCETIC man denied himself all pleasures, saying he was atoning for his sins.\" \n<em>Beautiful</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest. This is probably due to a confusion of ASCETIC with <em>aesthetic</em>, which means \"pertaining to the sense of beauty,\" <em>artistic</em>. \nOther forms of the word: ASCETICISM, n."
            },
            "BELLICOSE": {
              "word": "BELLICOSE",
              "phonetic": "(bel'-i-kOs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "belligerent, warlike, combative \nBELLICOSE, like the similar word <em>belligerent</em>, comes from the Latin <em>bellum</em>, meaning <em>war</em>. BELLICOSE means \"having a warlike manner or attitude.\" It is often used in a somewhat weaker sense about people who are always ready to start an argument or pick a fight. \n\"The BELLICOSE tribe was always at war.\" \"The BELLICOSE drunk threatened to punch me in the nose.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>comical</em>, perhaps because of confusion with <em>jocose</em>, which means <em>merry</em>, <em>humorous</em>. \nOther forms of the word: BELLICOSITY, n."
            },
            "BENIGN": {
              "word": "BENIGN",
              "phonetic": "(bi-nln')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "kindly, gracious; favorable \nBENIGN comes from the Latin word <em>bene</em>, meaning <em>well</em>, also the source of the English words <em>benevolent</em> and <em>beneficial</em>. BENIGN has two related meanings. The first is \"having a kind or gentle temperament.\" \n\"The BENIGN man simply smiled and put down his book when the children interrupted his reading.\" \n\"You certainly could not say that Adolf Hitler, the leader of Nazi Germany, was a BENIGN ruler.\" \nThe other meaning is <em>favorable</em>, <em>beneficial</em>. \n\"The older boy's good example had a BENIGN influence on the younger children.\" \nIn medicine, a BENIGN tumor is one that doesn't threaten one's health or life. In this sense, the opposite of BENIGN is <em>malignant</em>. By far the most popular wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>silent</em>, which may be one characteristic of a BENIGN person, but hardly the major one. \nOther forms of the word: BENIGNITY (b::i-nig'-nHE), n."
            },
            "CREDULOUS": {
              "word": "CREDULOUS",
              "phonetic": "(krej'-ÔøΩlÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "gullible, overly trusting \nThe words CREDULOUS, <em>credible</em>, <em>credence</em>, and <em>credit</em> all come from a Latin word meaning to <em>believe</em>. Someone who is CREDULOUS is too easily given to believing something. Such a person might be easily fooled by a tall tale or a lie. \n\"The CREDULOUS fellow actually believed the two women when they told him about their trip in the flying saucer.\" \n\"You are too CREDULOUS. Just because one of your friends says something, that doesn't mean it has to be true.\" \nCREDULOUS is difficult mainly because of confusion with its opposite, <em>incredulous</em> (see Chapter 11). People who are <em>incredulous</em> of something do not believe in it; they are skeptical or suspicious. <em>Incredulous</em> is more commonly used than CREDULOUS, and that may be why so many people pick <em>suspicious</em> as the meaning of CREDULOUS. \nOther forms of the word: CREDULITY, n."
            },
            "PARADIGM": {
              "word": "PARADIGM",
              "phonetic": "(par'-ÔøΩdlm",
              "pos": " n.",
              "deftext": "a model, example, pattern \nThe prefix <em>para-</em> means \"alongside,\" as in the word <em>parallel</em>. The <em>digm</em> part of PARADIGM comes from a Greek word meaning to <em>show</em> or <em>display</em>. A PARADIGM is a model or pattern of something else. The word tends to have an academic or scientific flavor. \n\"In the classic conditioned-response PARADIGM, the dog that hears a bell ring whenever he receives food will eventually salivate when he hears the bell, even without receiving food.\" \n\"They were considered the PARADIGMS of artistic perfection.\" \n\"Shakespeare's Macbeth is a PARADIGM of the man destroyed by his ambition.\" \nThe most popular wrong answers are <em>story</em> and <em>lesson</em>, perhaps suggested by the word <em>parable</em>. \nOther forms of the word: PARADIGMATIC (par-::i-dig- mat'-ikl, adj."
            },
            "SEQUESTER": {
              "word": "SEQUESTER",
              "phonetic": "(si-kwes'-tÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to isolate, segregate, seclude \nSEQUESTER means to <em>set apart</em>, to <em>isolate</em>. Often the sense of the word is \"to withdraw into seclusion or solitude.\" \n\"His ranch is SEQUESTERED in the California mountains, far from the city.\" \n\"The judge SEQUESTERED the jury, putting them in a hotel at night.\" \n\"The strange man SEQUESTERED himself in his room and refused to have anything more to do with the world.\" \nIn legal usage, SEQUESTER means \"to seize property by public authority until legal claims are satisfied,\" to <em>confiscate</em>. \n\"The estate of the deceased multimillionaire was SEQUESTERED while various parties contested his will.\" \nOther forms of the word: SEQUESTRATION, n."
            },
            "STODGY": {
              "word": "STODGY",
              "phonetic": "(stoj'-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "dull, pompous, stuffy \nSTODGY comes from the word <em>stodge</em>, which is any thick food, like oatmeal. STODGY can mean <em>thick</em> or <em>heavy</em>, like <em>stodge</em>, but it is usually used in an extended sense to mean <em>dull</em>, <em>stuffy</em>, \"lacking in humor or lightness.\" \n\"The STODGY teacher disapproved of students talking and laughing in the corridor.\" \n\"Susan thought the reception was terribly STODGY-just a bunch of serious people standing around, talking quietly.\" \n\"Classical music isn't always STODGY; some of it is quite exciting.\" \nThe difficulty people have with this word is thinking that it means <em>old</em>. An old person, of course, can be the very opposite of STODGY."
            },
            "SUFFUSE": {
              "word": "SUFFUSE",
              "phonetic": "(sÔøΩfyUz')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to overspread, spread through \nThe <em>-fuse</em> part of SUFFUSE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>pour</em>. This root is also found in <em>infuse</em>, <em>diffuse</em>, and <em>transfuse</em>. To SUFFUSE is to overspread, especially with a liquid or a color. \n\"The sunset SUFFUSED the western sky with purple and gold.\" \n\"Her eyes were SUFFUSED with tears as she remembered her late husband.\" \n\"Chekhov's plays are SUFFUSED with an air of wistful melancholy.\" \nOther forms of the word: SUFFUSIVE, adj. SUFFUSION, n."
            },
            "CELERITY": {
              "word": "CELERITY",
              "phonetic": "(sÔøΩler'-ÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "swiftness, quickness, rapidity \nCELERITY comes from the Latin word for <em>speed</em>, also the source of <em>accelerate</em>; it is a rather literary synonym for <em>swiftness</em>, <em>quickness</em>. \n\"The CELERITY of his response showed that he had mastered the subject.\" \n\"Art finished his homework with astonishing CELERITY so that he could watch his favorite TV program.\" \n\"The experienced surgeon performed the operation with ease and CELERITY.\" \n<em>Smoothness</em> is the most common wrong answer, perhaps suggested by the sound of CELERITY, and a confusion of quick movements with smooth ones."
            },
            "ABLUTION": {
              "word": "ABLUTION",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩblU'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a cleansing or washing of the body \nAn ABLUTION is a washing of the body, particularly as part of a religious rite. It is usually used in the plural. \n\"The novices had to perform their ABLUTIONS before they were allowed to wear the sacred vestments of the priesthood.\" \nABLUTION is only occasionally used about washing of the body in general. \n\"After Bill had finished his morning ABLUTIONS he felt much better.\""
            },
            "ABRADE": {
              "word": "ABRADE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩbrAd')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to wear away, erode, scrape, chafe \nABRADE is related to the word ABRASIVE. To ABRADE is to rub or wear away, usually as the result of friction. \n\"The skin on her knees was ABRADED when she slid along the concrete.\" \n\"The sandpaper ABRADED the surface of the dish.\" \nABRADE is also sometimes used figuratively, meaning to <em>wear down</em> or <em>irritate</em>. \n\"Our nerves were ABRADED by the constant noise of the jackhammer outside our window.\" \nOther forms of the word: ABRASION, n. ABRASIVE, adj."
            },
            "ABSTRUSE": {
              "word": "ABSTRUSE",
              "phonetic": "(ab-strUs')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "hard to understand, obscure, mysterious \nABSTRUSE means \"difficult to understand,\" usually because of extreme complexity, or because of the remoteness of the material from everyday experience. The word occasionally has a slightly negative sense, suggesting that this complexity may be unnecessary or excessive. \n\"Modern physics is a very ABSTRUSE subject. You have to be an expert to understand much of it.\" \n\"No one in the audience could make sense of the play's ABSTRUSE symbolism.\" \n\"The senator's arguments were so ABSTRUSE that no one else on the committee could follow them.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to VILIFY",
                  "answers": [
                    "slander",
                    "appease",
                    "despise",
                    "terrify",
                    "cheat"
                  ],
                  "word": "VILIFY",
                  "correct": "slander"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABNEGATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "improvement",
                    "cancellation",
                    "self-denial",
                    "indulgence",
                    "purity"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABNEGATION",
                  "correct": "self-denial"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMENABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "happy",
                    "submissive",
                    "irresponsible",
                    "holy",
                    "fragile"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMENABLE",
                  "correct": "submissive"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASCETIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "holy",
                    "self-indulgent",
                    "beautiful",
                    "austere",
                    "powerful"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASCETIC",
                  "correct": "austere"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BELLICOSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "warlike",
                    "peaceful",
                    "comical",
                    "overweight",
                    "evil"
                  ],
                  "word": "BELLICOSE",
                  "correct": "warlike"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BENIGN",
                  "answers": [
                    "kindly",
                    "lovely",
                    "silent",
                    "malicious",
                    "unforgiving"
                  ],
                  "word": "BENIGN",
                  "correct": "kindly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CREDULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "stupid",
                    "unknown",
                    "extravagant",
                    "suspicious",
                    "gullible"
                  ],
                  "word": "CREDULOUS",
                  "correct": "gullible"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARADIGM",
                  "answers": [
                    "story",
                    "model",
                    "lesson",
                    "copy",
                    "result"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARADIGM",
                  "correct": "model"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to SEQUESTER",
                  "answers": [
                    "isolate",
                    "assemble",
                    "harass",
                    "protect",
                    "follow"
                  ],
                  "word": "SEQUESTER",
                  "correct": "isolate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STODGY",
                  "answers": [
                    "lively",
                    "old",
                    "cruel",
                    "dull",
                    "clever"
                  ],
                  "word": "STODGY",
                  "correct": "dull"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to SUFFUSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "disappear",
                    "undergo",
                    "overspread",
                    "affect",
                    "darken"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUFFUSE",
                  "correct": "overspread"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CELERITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "rashness",
                    "swiftness",
                    "sluggishness",
                    "isolation",
                    "smoothness"
                  ],
                  "word": "CELERITY",
                  "correct": "swiftness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABLUTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "staining",
                    "forgiveness",
                    "cleansing",
                    "prayer",
                    "blessing"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABLUTION",
                  "correct": "cleansing"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ABRADE",
                  "answers": [
                    "insult",
                    "uproot",
                    "break apart",
                    "twist",
                    "wear away"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABRADE",
                  "correct": "wear away"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABSTRUSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "mysterious",
                    "obvious",
                    "dull",
                    "forgotten",
                    "religious"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABSTRUSE",
                  "correct": "mysterious"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a gentleman VILIFY a friend?",
                  "word": "VILIFY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a person who fasts practice ABNEGATION?",
                  "word": "ABNEGATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are stubborn people AMENABLE to change?",
                  "word": "AMENABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an ASCETIC likely to be overweight?",
                  "word": "ASCETIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a BELLICOSE person be likely to have a large circle of friends?",
                  "word": "BELLICOSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a BENIGN tumor dangerous?",
                  "word": "BENIGN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are skeptics CREDULOUS?",
                  "word": "CREDULOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a person be a PARADIGM?",
                  "word": "PARADIGM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a hermit want to SEQUESTER himself?",
                  "word": "SEQUESTER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are most children STODGY?",
                  "word": "STODGY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a room be SUFFUSED with light?",
                  "word": "SUFFUSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should a typist possess CELERITY?",
                  "word": "CELERITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a bath be a form of ABLUTION?",
                  "word": "ABLUTION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can sandpaper ABRADE metal?",
                  "word": "ABRADE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a poem be ABSTRUSE?",
                  "word": "ABSTRUSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "He claimed the magazine was VILIFYING him, but the editor said it was legitimate criticism.",
                  "word": "VILIFY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The woman's entire life was one of SELF-ABNEGATION; she always helped others before thinking of herself.",
                  "word": "ABNEGATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jake's boss was not AMENABLE to any of the suggestions he made.",
                  "word": "AMENABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their ASCETIC practices included eating only one meal a day.",
                  "word": "ASCETIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The BELLICOSE comedian had us rolling in the aisles with laughter.",
                  "word": "BELLICOSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His vacation had a BENIGN effect: he came back rested, refreshed, and eager to work.",
                  "word": "BENIGN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It is a CREDULOUS story; we are inclined to believe it.",
                  "word": "CREDULOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The minister gave his sermon on the PARADIGM of the loaves and the fishes.",
                  "word": "PARADIGM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She longed to live in a SEQUESTERED village deep in some hidden valley.",
                  "word": "SEQUESTER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "No one could accuse Mr. Wilkes of being STODGY; he was the life of every party.",
                  "word": "STODGY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They SUFFUSED us about their true reason for coming here.",
                  "word": "SUFFUSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The CELERITY of the surface made the dish difficult to grip.",
                  "word": "CELERITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They performed their ABLUTIONS with water from a nearby stream.",
                  "word": "ABLUTION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She ABRADED us constantly for our poor performance in school.",
                  "word": "ABRADE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was ABSTRUSE of him to treat me that way; he should be ashamed of himself.",
                  "word": "ABSTRUSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "VILIFY",
                  "answers": [
                    "defame",
                    "malign",
                    "belie"
                  ],
                  "word": "VILIFY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABNEGATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "sacrifice",
                    "prayer",
                    "denial"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABNEGATION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMENABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "docile",
                    "pleasant",
                    "responsible"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMENABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASCETIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "disciplined",
                    "austere",
                    "serene"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASCETIC",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BELLICOSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "noisy",
                    "argumentative",
                    "aggressive"
                  ],
                  "word": "BELLICOSE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BENIGN",
                  "answers": [
                    "humane",
                    "cordial",
                    "tireless"
                  ],
                  "word": "BENIGN",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CREDULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "trusting",
                    "trustworthy",
                    "gullible"
                  ],
                  "word": "CREDULOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARADIGM",
                  "answers": [
                    "example",
                    "character",
                    "standard"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARADIGM",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SEQUESTER",
                  "answers": [
                    "seclude",
                    "destroy",
                    "confiscate"
                  ],
                  "word": "SEQUESTER",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STODGY",
                  "answers": [
                    "boring",
                    "prudish",
                    "learned"
                  ],
                  "word": "STODGY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUFFUSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "saturate",
                    "imbue",
                    "darken"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUFFUSE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CELERITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "softness",
                    "fleetness",
                    "briskness"
                  ],
                  "word": "CELERITY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABLUTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "washing",
                    "cleansing",
                    "beautifying"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABLUTION",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABRADE",
                  "answers": [
                    "scrape",
                    "puncture",
                    "irritate"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABRADE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABSTRUSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "obscure",
                    "complicated",
                    "ancient"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABSTRUSE",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ABRADE",
            "answer": "abraded"
          },
          {
            "word": "ASSIDUOUS",
            "answer": "assiduous"
          },
          {
            "word": "IGNOMINIOUS",
            "answer": "ignominious"
          },
          {
            "word": "PARADIGM",
            "answer": "paradigm"
          },
          {
            "word": "STODGY",
            "answer": "stodgy"
          },
          {
            "word": "ABSTRUSE",
            "answer": "abstruse"
          },
          {
            "word": "CREDULOUS",
            "answer": "credulous"
          },
          {
            "word": "IMPLACABLE",
            "answer": "implacable"
          },
          {
            "word": "PRODIGIOUS",
            "answer": "prodigious"
          },
          {
            "word": "SUFFUSE",
            "answer": "suffused"
          },
          {
            "word": "AMENABLE",
            "answer": "amenable"
          },
          {
            "word": "ESCHEW",
            "answer": "eschew"
          },
          {
            "word": "INCOMMODE",
            "answer": "incommode"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROPINQUITY",
            "answer": "propinquity"
          },
          {
            "word": "TRIBULATION",
            "answer": "tribulations"
          },
          {
            "word": "APPRISE",
            "answer": "apprise"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXPIATION",
            "answer": "expiation"
          },
          {
            "word": "INCREDULOUS",
            "answer": "incredulous"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROPITIOUS",
            "answer": "propinquity"
          },
          {
            "word": "UBIQUITOUS",
            "answer": "ubiquitous"
          },
          {
            "word": "ASCETIC",
            "answer": "ascetic"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXTANT",
            "answer": "extant"
          },
          {
            "word": "ABLUTION",
            "answer": "ablution"
          },
          {
            "word": "BELIE",
            "answer": "belie"
          },
          {
            "word": "FERAL",
            "answer": "feral"
          },
          {
            "word": "PAROXYSM",
            "answer": "paroxysm"
          },
          {
            "word": "SINUOUS",
            "answer": "sinuous"
          },
          {
            "word": "ABNEGATION",
            "answer": "abnegation"
          },
          {
            "word": "BELLICOSE",
            "answer": "bellicose"
          },
          {
            "word": "HIRSUTE",
            "answer": "hirsute"
          },
          {
            "word": "PERFIDY",
            "answer": "perfidy"
          },
          {
            "word": "TENABLE",
            "answer": "tenable"
          },
          {
            "word": "ADMONISH",
            "answer": "admonished"
          },
          {
            "word": "BENIGN",
            "answer": "benign"
          },
          {
            "word": "INIQUITOUS",
            "answer": "iniquitous"
          },
          {
            "word": "RUMINATE",
            "answer": "ruminate"
          },
          {
            "word": "VILIFY",
            "answer": "vilified"
          },
          {
            "word": "ANCILLARY",
            "answer": "ancillary"
          },
          {
            "word": "CELERITY",
            "answer": "celerity"
          },
          {
            "word": "INVECTIVE",
            "answer": "invective"
          },
          {
            "word": "SEQUESTER",
            "answer": "sequestered"
          },
          {
            "word": "VOLUBLE",
            "answer": "voluble"
          },
          {
            "word": "ANOMALY",
            "answer": "anomaly"
          },
          {
            "word": "FATUOUS",
            "answer": "fatuous"
          },
          {
            "word": "ONEROUS",
            "answer": "onerous"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "mechanic worked hard to make sure the engine was absolutely perfect.",
            "correct": "assiduous",
            "word": "ASSIDUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "All the circumstances were",
            "part2": "for a victory: everyone was healthy, we were on our home field and we had an excellent game plan.",
            "correct": "propitious",
            "word": "PROPITIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "young man chose to live on bread and water in order to purify his spirit.",
            "correct": "ascetic",
            "word": "ASCETIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "You are too",
            "part2": "; why do you believe everything you are told?",
            "correct": "credulous",
            "word": "CREDULOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Only the most brilliant students could follow the professor's",
            "part2": "lecture.",
            "correct": "abstruse",
            "word": "ABSTRUSE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "As he slid down the side of the hill, his palms were",
            "part2": "by the rough surface of the rock.",
            "correct": "abraded",
            "word": "ABRADE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Gandhi's movement was a(n)",
            "part2": "of the successful, nonviolent approach to political change.",
            "correct": "paradigm",
            "word": "PARADIGM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The townspeople demanded that Hester Prynne wear a scarlet A on her chest as",
            "part2": "for her adultery.",
            "correct": "expiation",
            "word": "EXPIATION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The general's",
            "part2": "defeat in the important battle destroyed his reputation.",
            "correct": "ignominious",
            "word": "IGNOMINIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The Andersons seemed rather",
            "part2": "to Barbara; they didn't approve of young people laughing or playing in the house.",
            "correct": "stodgy",
            "word": "STODGY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jason proved to be extremely",
            "part2": "to our advice; in fact, he said it was quite helpful.",
            "correct": "amenable",
            "word": "AMENABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The writer's output was",
            "part2": ": he wrote over a hundred novels in his lifetime.",
            "correct": "prodigious",
            "word": "PRODIGIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We left the \"Do Not Disturb\" sign on the door so that the maid wouldn't",
            "part2": "us.",
            "correct": "incommode",
            "word": "INCOMMODE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Since absolute silence was required, we were asked to",
            "part2": "talking during the performances.",
            "correct": "eschew",
            "word": "ESCHEW"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Despite all her",
            "part2": "she still managed to keep smiling.",
            "correct": "tribulations",
            "word": "TRIBULATION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Juan wrote us a letter to",
            "part2": "us of conditions in his country.",
            "correct": "apprise",
            "word": "APPRISE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Nothing would satisfy the",
            "part2": "enemy but our complete and utter defeat.",
            "correct": "implacable",
            "word": "IMPLACABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The evening sky was",
            "part2": "with an eerie red glow.",
            "correct": "suffused",
            "word": "SUFFUSE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "You couldn't go anywhere in Rome that summer without running into the",
            "part2": "tourists - cameras and guidebooks in hand.",
            "correct": "ubiquitous",
            "word": "UBIQUITOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "students refused to believe their teacher could actually make a mistake.",
            "correct": "incredulous",
            "word": "INCREDULOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "of his apartment to where he worked meant that he could be on the job in less than five minutes.",
            "correct": "propinquity",
            "word": "PROPITIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There is only one copy of the book",
            "part2": "; all the rest were destroyed by fire.",
            "correct": "extant",
            "word": "EXTANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The speech was totally",
            "part2": "; there wasn't an ounce of sense in it.",
            "correct": "fatuous",
            "word": "FATUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The task of retyping the book proved to be too",
            "part2": "for just one person, so two people were assigned to it.",
            "correct": "onerous",
            "word": "ONEROUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His views on medicine are simply not",
            "part2": "in light of what we know about how the body works.",
            "correct": "tenable",
            "word": "TENABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We were impressed by her act of",
            "part2": "; she refused to accept any financial rewards for her medical discovery.",
            "correct": "abnegation",
            "word": "ABNEGATION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The animal's",
            "part2": "instincts told it when it was in danger.",
            "correct": "feral",
            "word": "FERAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After a year without a shave or haircut, Jim had an extremely",
            "part2": "appearance.",
            "correct": "hirsute",
            "word": "HIRSUTE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We have enough money for the required equipment, but not for the",
            "part2": "materials that would make the job so much easier.",
            "correct": "ancillary",
            "word": "ANCILLARY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "uncle would always have a kind word and a gift for his nephews and nieces.",
            "correct": "benign",
            "word": "BENIGN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She works with such great",
            "part2": "that she will finish the job by the end of the day.",
            "correct": "celerity",
            "word": "CELERITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "actress spent half an hour answering the interviewer's first question.",
            "correct": "voluble",
            "word": "VOLUBLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The newspaper",
            "part2": "the mayor, saying that he was the scum of the earth.",
            "correct": "vilified",
            "word": "VILIFY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The committee was",
            "part2": "in the conference room all day while they tried to decide whom to hire.",
            "correct": "sequestered",
            "word": "SEQUESTER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The newspaper called the dictator's decision",
            "part2": ", a disgraceful violation of human rights.",
            "correct": "iniquitous",
            "word": "INIQUITOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The audience went into a sudden",
            "part2": "of laughter when the comedian told the joke.",
            "correct": "paroxysm",
            "word": "PAROXYSM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The man",
            "part2": "Jimmy for disturbing his nap.",
            "correct": "admonished",
            "word": "ADMONISH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His insistence on wearing a business suit and tie made him a(n)",
            "part2": "among the casually dressed students.",
            "correct": "anomaly",
            "word": "ANOMALY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Late at night he liked to",
            "part2": "on what his life would have been like if he had been born in another century.",
            "correct": "ruminate",
            "word": "RUMINATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "man said that if anyone disagreed with him, he'd be happy to prove his point with his fists.",
            "correct": "bellicose",
            "word": "BELLICOSE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We were astonished by his",
            "part2": "in selling the military secrets to the enemy.",
            "correct": "perfidy",
            "word": "PERFIDY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Your trembling hands",
            "part2": "your brave words; you are really quite frightened.",
            "correct": "belie",
            "word": "BELIE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "path of the stream led us in and out of many interesting places.",
            "correct": "sinuous",
            "word": "SINUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The priestess performed a ceremonial",
            "part2": "by washing her face and hands in the sacred water.",
            "correct": "ablution",
            "word": "ABLUTION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The writer's speech was filled with",
            "part2": "; we were shocked at the bitterness of his insults.",
            "correct": "invective",
            "word": "INVECTIVE"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    }
  ]
}